<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-08-26T20:08:44+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">OpenSourceFeed</title><subtitle>Gallery of various GNU/Linux, BSD and other open source distributions and different open source desktop environments with updates &amp; stories on each.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Bodhi Linux 5.0.0 released based on Ubuntu 18.04</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-bodhi-linux-5.0.0-released-with-ubuntu-18.04-base/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bodhi Linux 5.0.0 released based on Ubuntu 18.04" /><published>2018-08-22T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-08-22T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-bodhi-linux-5.0.0-released-with-ubuntu-18.04-base</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-bodhi-linux-5.0.0-released-with-ubuntu-18.04-base/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Jeff Hoogland&lt;/em&gt; of Bodhi Linux project has announced the immediate availability of Bodhi Linux 5.0.0, the fifth major release of Ubuntu-based GNU/Linux distribution serving simple and fast desktop experience. It has been more than 7 years since the inception of Bodhi Linux 1.x, the first stable release from the project. Over the years, the project has evolved a lot in terms of user experience and stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/bodhilinux5.0.0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of Bodhi Linux 5.0.0 clean desktop&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A preview of Bodhi Linux 5.0.0 clean desktop&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bodhi Linux 5.0.0 is based on Ubuntu 18.04 LTS. It will be supported until 2023. While the recent releases of Bodhi Linux were based on Ubuntu 16.04 LTS and will continue to provide support till 2021. Other than the core change, there is nothing remarkable in Bodhi Linux 5.0.0. However, the core change implies, updated packages, more stability, and better hardware compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the main-stream distributions, Bodhi Linux does not provide direct upgrade path between the major releases. It encourages to do a fresh installation in order to avoid system breakage and other stability issues. However, the regression testers and the distribution enthusiasts who are already running a 5.0.0 prerelease, can perform a normal system update operation to get changes from the latest ISO. This will require manual configuration to get the latest look &amp;amp; feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Today I am very pleased to share the hard work of the Bodhi Team which has resulted in our fifth major release. It has been quite the journey since our first stable release a little over seven years ago and I am happy with the progress this projected has made in that time.
For those looking for a lengthy changelog between the 4.5.0 release and 5.0.0, you will not find one. We have been happy with what the Moksha desktop has provided for some time now. This new major release simply serves to bring a modern look and updated Ubuntu core (18.04) to the lightning-fast desktop you have come to expect from Bodhi Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodhilinux.com/2018/08/22/bodhi-linux-5-0-0-released/&quot;&gt;Bodhi Linux 5.0.0 release announcement&lt;/a&gt; in projects website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;download-bodhi-linux-500&quot;&gt;Download Bodhi Linux 5.0.0&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bodhi Linux 5.0.0 installation images can be grabbed by following below links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standard Release &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; –&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/5.0.0/bodhi-5.0.0-64.iso/download&quot;&gt;ISO Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Legacy Release&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; –&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/5.0.0/bodhi-5.0.0-legacy.iso/download&quot;&gt;ISO Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AppPack Release&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;–&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/5.0.0/bodhi-5.0.0-appack-64.iso/download&quot;&gt;ISO Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Mr Jeff Hoogland of Bodhi Linux project has announced the immediate availability of Bodhi Linux 5.0.0, the fifth major release of Ubuntu-based GNU/Linux distribution serving simple and fast desktop experience. It has been more than 7 years since the inception of Bodhi Linux 1.x, the first stable release from the project. Over the years, the project has evolved a lot in terms of user experience and stability.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/bodhilinux5.0.0.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">deepin 15.7 brings improved performance, reduced power usage and more</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-deepin-15.7-brings-power-consumption-and-performance-improvements/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="deepin 15.7 brings improved performance, reduced power usage and more" /><published>2018-08-20T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-08-20T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-deepin-15.7-brings-power-consumption-and-performance-improvements</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-deepin-15.7-brings-power-consumption-and-performance-improvements/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; deepin project has announced the release of deepin 15.7. This release brings various performance improvements, power optimization, and other critical bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/deepin157.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Category listing in deepin menu mini-mode&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-deepin-version-number-convention&quot;&gt;The deepin version number convention&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning from deepin 15.7, the project is changing the version number convention. The version number will be of the form X.Y.Z, in which X indicates the major version number. Currently, the major version number is 15, it indicates current version is developed and maintained from 2015. Y - indicates the subversion number, and it will come in a rough period of 3 months. Deepin releases with even subversion number will bring feature additions. While the odd releases will focus on bug fixes and stability improvements. The Z component in version number indicates the minor version number. It will be used if there is any minor update in the current release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-new-in-debian-157&quot;&gt;What is new in Debian 15.7?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;deepin 15.7 is a release that focuses mainly on bug fixes and performance improvements. It synchronizes the latest packages from the upstream project, Debian. If you are updating from an existing installation, there will be more than 1G of package updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main highlights of deepin 15.7 include,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Reduced ISO size. The deepin ISO size used to increase drastically, in proportion to the number of features and artworks added. With the 15.7 release, the team has reduced the ISO size to 2.5GB from the previous 3.1 GB. This is done by removing unnecessary components and packages from the system.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The overall power consumption is reduced by adding the power saving mode in deepin 15.7. It allows the system to automatically enter on power saving mode while running on battery. Preliminary tests show standby time extended by 20%.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The memory consumption on startup is reduced to 830MB. In the previous release, it was around 1.1 GB.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Other usability &amp;amp; configuration changes like power saving configuration in control panel, a time-costing prompt from bigger updates, category listing in application menu min-mode ..etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deepin.org/en/2018/08/20/deepin-15-7-enjoy-the-better-performance/&quot;&gt;more details on deepin 15.7&lt;/a&gt;, read official release announcement in projects blog.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The deepin project has announced the release of deepin 15.7. This release brings various performance improvements, power optimization, and other critical bug fixes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/deepin157.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Zorin OS 12.4 released with better hardware support</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-zorin-os-12.4-released-with-better-hardware-support/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zorin OS 12.4 released with better hardware support" /><published>2018-08-13T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-08-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-zorin-os-12.4-released-with-better-hardware-support</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-zorin-os-12.4-released-with-better-hardware-support/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Zorin Group has announced the availability of Zorin OS 12.4, the final snapshot in Zorin 12.x series. This release brings various updated packages from the upstream project, ie, Ubuntu 16.04.5. It provides better hardware support with Linux Kernel 4.15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a minor release, Zorin OS brings critical package updates, crucial bug fixes, and other performance enhancements. The existing users of Zorin OS 12.x can perform a regular system update operation to get all benefits from Zorin OS 12.4. With the updated ISO new users can ensure that they have to download only the minimum number of packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/zorinos122.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of Zorin OS 12.2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Zorin OS 12.4 introduces an updated hardware enablement stack. The newly-included Linux kernel 4.15, as well as an updated X server graphics stack, add compatibility for newer computers and hardware in Zorin OS. In addition, new patches for system vulnerabilities are included in this release, so you can have the peace of mind knowing that you’re using the most secure version of Zorin OS ever.&lt;br /&gt;
After installing Zorin OS 12.4, you will have the latest versions of the pre-installed packages. That means fewer software updates will need to be downloaded after installing Zorin OS onto your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&quot;https://zoringroup.com/blog/2018/08/13/zorin-os-12-4-released-more-secure-and-compatible-than-ever-before/&quot;&gt;more information on Zorin OS 12.4&lt;/a&gt;, read the official release announcement published on Zorin Group blog.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Zorin Group has announced the availability of Zorin OS 12.4, the final snapshot in Zorin 12.x series. This release brings various updated packages from the upstream project, ie, Ubuntu 16.04.5. It provides better hardware support with Linux Kernel 4.15.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/zorinos122.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">LibreOffice 6.1 shows the power of large and diverse community contributors</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/01-libreoffice-6.1-proclaims-the-power-of-large-and-diverse-community-contributors/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LibreOffice 6.1 shows the power of large and diverse community contributors" /><published>2018-08-10T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-08-10T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/01-libreoffice-6.1-proclaims-the-power-of-large-and-diverse-community-contributors</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/01-libreoffice-6.1-proclaims-the-power-of-large-and-diverse-community-contributors/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Document Foundation has announced the release of LibreOffice 6.1. It is a major release with contributions from hundreds of community contributors around the world.  TDF showcases this release as an example of, what an open source can do with the collective power of contributors from diverse backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/libreoffice-community.png&quot; alt=&quot;The LibreOffice community&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LibreOffice 6.1 brings a significant number of improvements, both in UX and in the overall performance. The community contributors have helped to implement most of these improvements. 72% of the community contributors are people working at various open source organizations. While the remaining are individual contributors. In addition to these contributions, LibreOffice is also benefited by a global community with localization, documentation editing, quality assurance, user interface design and other activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main highlights in LibreOffice 6.1 include,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Colibre, a new icon theme for Windows based on Microsoft’s icon design guidelines, which makes the office suite visually appealing for users coming from the Microsoft environment;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A reworked image handling feature, which is significantly faster and smoother thanks to a new graphics manager and an improved image lifecycle, with some advantages, also when loading documents in Microsoft proprietary formats;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The reorganization of Draw menus with the addition of a new Page menu, for better UX consistency across the different modules;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A major improvement for Base, only available in experimental mode: the old HSQLDB database engine has been deprecated, though still available, and the new Firebird database engine is now the default option (users are encouraged to migrate files using the migration assistant from HSQLDB to Firebird, or by exporting them to an external HSQLDB server);&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Significant improvements in all modules of LibreOffice Online, with changes to the user interface to make it more appealing and consistent with the desktop version,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;An improved EPUB export filter, in terms of the link, table, image, font embedding and footnote support, with more options for customizing metadata;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Online Help pages have been enriched with text and example files to guide the users through features, and are now easier to localize.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.documentfoundation.org/blog/2018/08/08/libreoffice-6-1/&quot;&gt;more information on LibreOffice 6.1&lt;/a&gt;, see the release announcement published on Document Foundation blog.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Document Foundation has announced the release of LibreOffice 6.1. It is a major release with contributions from hundreds of community contributors around the world. TDF showcases this release as an example of, what an open source can do with the collective power of contributors from diverse backgrounds.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/libreoffice-community.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Netrunner Rolling 2018.08 released with seamless Gtk Integration</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/01-Netrunner-rolling-2018.07-released-with-seamless-gtk-integration/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Netrunner Rolling 2018.08 released with seamless Gtk Integration" /><published>2018-08-06T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-08-06T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/01-Netrunner-rolling-2018.07-released-with-seamless-gtk-integration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/01-Netrunner-rolling-2018.07-released-with-seamless-gtk-integration/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Netrunner team has announced the availability of Netrunner 2018.08, the latest stable release of Arch-based rolling GNU/Linux distribution. This release includes multiple improvements including the Plasma 5.13.3 and other components. It also provides a nice integration with Gtk based applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/netrunner-rolling-2018.08.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of Netrunner Rolling 2018.08&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A preview of Netrunner Rolling 2018.08&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the Netrunner Core edition, Netrunner Rolling is a GNU/Linux distribution based on Arch and Manjaro flavors. It provides a decent Plasma experience with continuous updates from the upstream projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main highlights in Netrunner Rolling 2018.08 release can be summarized as follows,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Updated applications including KDE Plasma 5.13.3, KDE Frameworks 5.48, KDE Applications 18.04, Qt 5.11.1, Linux Kernel 4.17, Firefox Quantum 61.0, Thunderbird 52.5 and more.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Gtk Apps now makes use of Kwin borders to provide a better integration with the rest of the ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Krita 4.1.1 which has got plenty of features compared to the previous release.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Using the new sidebar Layout, all the revamped UI-related KCM modules into one section called “Plasma Tweaks” for easy configuring Plasma Desktop.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;This release also comes with some new Plasma Theme that has some transparency built in to allow for experimenting with the new Blur options.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the original &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netrunner.com/netrunner-rolling-2018-08-released/&quot;&gt;release announcement of Netrunner Rolling 2018.08&lt;/a&gt; and download links, proceed to Netrunner Website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Netrunner team has announced the availability of Netrunner 2018.08, the latest stable release of Arch-based rolling GNU/Linux distribution. This release includes multiple improvements including the Plasma 5.13.3 and other components. It also provides a nice integration with Gtk based applications.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/netrunner-rolling-2018.08.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Korora team is back on Korora 28 development after the vecation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/01-korora-team-is-back-on-korora-28-development-after-vacation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Korora team is back on Korora 28 development after the vecation" /><published>2018-08-03T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-08-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/01-korora-team-is-back-on-korora-28-development-after-vacation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/01-korora-team-is-back-on-korora-28-development-after-vacation/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Closing&lt;/strong&gt; the uncertainties on the future of Korora project, Korora team has started working on Korora 28. Earlier, the team had planned to go on an indefinite vacation because of the poor community support for taking the Korora project forward. This put the future of Korora project in a dilemma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/korora-banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;Korora Linux banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Korora team announced their vacation, some of the community members came forward to prepare the ISO for the upcoming release. Mr. &lt;em&gt;JMiahMan&lt;/em&gt;, a community contributor prepared a Korora 28 Xfce image with the usual add-ons. This inspired the team to come back and to start working on Korora 28. As a beginning, the team is performing the QA activities on Korora 28 Xfce. The team is also seeking community contribution for testing this image. Once the issues on Xfce edition is sorted out, Korora team will prepare images with other ecosystems also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As most people will know the Korora team has been having a break for the last few months. One of our community members wasn’t happy about this and stepped up to produce a Korora 28 release. We welcome the support and ask that the rest of the community help out by testing the ISO and providing feedback.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A past contributor JMiahMan has produced an Xfce ISO based on Fedora 28 and including the usual Korora additions. There are more details on this Engage item. You might find this blog post interesting too.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There are plans to produce ISOs of the other desktops once Xfce is sorted. So even if you don’t use Xfce it would be helpful if you could test this system on a live system or in a VM. Remember these are community produced, beta releases and not designed for day to day use (yet!) so we don’t recommend installing them on a production system. Feedback can be provided on the Engage item mentioned above or IRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further details, you can read the official &lt;a href=&quot;https://kororaproject.org/about/news/the-community-is-working-on-korora-28&quot;&gt;Korora 28 development announcement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Closing the uncertainties on the future of Korora project, Korora team has started working on Korora 28. Earlier, the team had planned to go on an indefinite vacation because of the poor community support for taking the Korora project forward. This put the future of Korora project in a dilemma.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/korora-banner.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lubuntu is taking a new direction with LXQt</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-lubuntu-is-changing-its-direction-with-lxqt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lubuntu is taking a new direction with LXQt" /><published>2018-08-02T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-08-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-lubuntu-is-changing-its-direction-with-lxqt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-lubuntu-is-changing-its-direction-with-lxqt/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With&lt;/strong&gt; the migration to &lt;a href=&quot;/desktop/lxqt&quot;&gt;LXQt&lt;/a&gt; ecosystem, Lubuntu team is planning to revise their initial design goals and to take a new direction. The initial design goal of Lubuntu was to provide a lightweight operating system that can revive older hardware. In the past, this distribution was a success in accomplishing its mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/lubuntu-1710.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of Lubuntu with LXDE ecosystem&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of &lt;em&gt;older machine&lt;/em&gt; changes over the time. The rough goal of Lubuntu was to work smoothly on a 10 years old hardware. If we think of a 10 years old hardware now, it will be having a modern processor with a minimum of 2GB RAM and 64-bit compatibility. Today, most of the Ubuntu derivatives can run smoothly run on a system with 2GB of the RAM. So, the design goal of Lubuntu is almost obsolete now.  This idea brought a lot of internal debates within the Lubuntu community and the team finally decided to go with a more modern design approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the direction change, Lubuntu can still work on older hardware. But, the main goal of the distribution will be providing a more modern user experience to the users. Other decisions made by the Lubuntu team includes,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Lubuntu will leverage modern, Qt-based technologies and programs to give users a functional yet modular experience.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;In collaboration with others, Lubuntu will continue to be a transparent and open distribution which makes it a priority to keep the community informed about the development when possible.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Lubuntu will create and maintain complete documentation which will be included by default in the operating system and can guide anyone from beginner to expert on how to use Lubuntu to its full potential and contribute to the further development of it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Lubuntu will keep a light experience by default but enable users to utilize more heavy and featureful components as desired.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Lubuntu will have the ability to be used in any language across the world, and enable contributors to easily translate all components of the operating system.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lubuntu.me/taking-a-new-direction/&quot;&gt;official statement on changing the design goals of Lubuntu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">With the migration to LXQt ecosystem, Lubuntu team is planning to revise their initial design goals and to take a new direction. The initial design goal of Lubuntu was to provide a lightweight operating system that can revive older hardware. In the past, this distribution was a success in accomplishing its mission.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/lubuntu-1710.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dell XPS 13 Developer Edition becomes first OEM hardware with Ubuntu 18.04 LTS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/01-dell-xps-13-developer-edition-becomes-first-major-oem-hardware-with-ubuntu-18.04/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dell XPS 13 Developer Edition becomes first OEM hardware with Ubuntu 18.04 LTS" /><published>2018-07-30T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-07-30T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/01-dell-xps-13-developer-edition-becomes-first-major-oem-hardware-with-ubuntu-18.04</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/01-dell-xps-13-developer-edition-becomes-first-major-oem-hardware-with-ubuntu-18.04/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Dell XPS 13 Developer Edition laptops are now available in the US with pre-installed Ubuntu 18.04 LTS. This is the first major OEM’s hardware that ships Ubuntu 18.04 since it’s inception on April 2018. Canonical and Dell have worked to together to provide a seamless experience with Ubuntu on Dell XP 13 laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presently, Dell XPS 13 Developer Edition is only available in the US only. It will be available in Europe by August 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/xps13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dell XPS 13 Developer Edition with Ubuntu 18.04 LTS&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dell XPS 13 Developer Edition launched in the US provides multiple configuration options including SSD extendable up to 1 TB, 16 GB RAM, the latest 8th generation Quad Core processors. With the power of supporting a wide range of applications, it can be used in either enterprise environments or at home or by developers. It also features the world’s first InfinityEdge 13.3” near borderless display housed in a sleek silver magnesium body, which is the smallest in its class. It provides options to choose between Full HD or Ultra HD resolutions with the option of touch on later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu 18.04 LTS released on April 2018 brings a range of features. It includes the GNOME shell instead of Ubuntu home-made Unity shell. It also provides better support for applications like Skype, Spotify, and Slack with the full snap integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When Project Sputnik debuted over five years ago we launched with one config of our XPS 13 developer edition on Ubuntu 12.04. Fast forward to today and thanks to the interest and support of the community, we are able to announce that our seventh generation XPS 13 developer edition now comes with Ubuntu 18.04 LTS. 18.04 represents Project Sputnik’s fourth preloaded LTS. We’re already looking forward to Sputnik’s fifth LTS in 2020,” says Barton George, Project Sputnik and Linux Lead at Dell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We are delighted to have worked in close partnership with Dell for the launch of their latest XPS 13 Developer Edition pre-installed with our newest LTS release. Dell’s superior hardware combined with Ubuntu 18.04 LTS provides an excellent, reliable experience straight out of the box. Building on our longstanding relationship with Dell over the last six years, we look forward to seeing 18.04 LTS roll out on further models in the coming months,” comments Will Cooke, Desktop Engineering Director, Canonical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ubuntu.com/2018/07/27/dell-xps13-developer-edition-ships-with-ubuntu-18-04-lts-pre-installed&quot;&gt;feature article on Dell XPS Developer Edition with Ubuntu 18.04 LTS&lt;/a&gt; on Ubuntu blog.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Dell XPS 13 Developer Edition laptops are now available in the US with pre-installed Ubuntu 18.04 LTS. This is the first major OEM’s hardware that ships Ubuntu 18.04 since it’s inception on April 2018. Canonical and Dell have worked to together to provide a seamless experience with Ubuntu on Dell XP 13 laptop.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/xps13.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">ArchLabs Linux 2018.07 released with a brand new dark theme</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-archlabs-linux-2018.07-released-with-brand-new-dark-theme/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ArchLabs Linux 2018.07 released with a brand new dark theme" /><published>2018-07-30T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-07-30T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-archlabs-linux-2018.07-released-with-brand-new-dark-theme</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-archlabs-linux-2018.07-released-with-brand-new-dark-theme/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; ArchLabs team has announced the release of ArchLabs 2018.07. It is the latest stable release of Arch-based GNU/Linux distribution inspired by the design principles of &lt;em&gt;Bunsenlabs&lt;/em&gt;. The main focus of this release on stability improvement, performance and usability improvements and other optimizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/ArchLabs_2018-02-07-18_1920x1080.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of ArchLabs 2018.07&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A preview of ArchLabs Linux 2018.07&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the visible change with ArchLabs is the introduction of a brand new dark theme which works well the default light icon theme shipped with ArchLabs. Last week, ArchLabs team had shared some updates on with a discussion thread on ArchLabs forums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other main highlights in ArchLabs Linux 2018.07 includes,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The ArchLabs installer finally has it’s own name, presenting, AL-Installer.  Originally forked from ABIF, it has been completely re-written for use with ArchLabs and only vaguely resembles the original product.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A lot of changes have been made to keep your install simple.  Sorting of mirrors has been added as well as a page to create your user.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A brand new default theme, ArchLabs-dARK.  This works nicely with the current icon theme, ArchLabs-Light.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;New default wallpaper.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Aurman has replaced Yaourt as our AUR helper.  This helper works nicely with Pacman.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Neofetch has been replaced quite some time ago with our lightweight homemade info script, AL-Info.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;With the help from Oddproton and Karl Schneider, we have our very own dynamic wallpaper script (à la MacOS Mojave/Gnome) called Dynpaper.  With custom walls created by the ever talented Karl.  Dynpaper isn’t installed or enabled by default.  If you’d like to get this up and running on your system, check out our thread at the forum.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Polybar has been updated to the latest version and has undergone a tidy up.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Vim and Ranger’s configs have been added and updated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the original &lt;a href=&quot;https://archlabslinux.com/2018/07/29/archlabs-linux-2018-07/&quot;&gt;ArchLabs 2018.07 release announcement&lt;/a&gt; in projects website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The ArchLabs team has announced the release of ArchLabs 2018.07. It is the latest stable release of Arch-based GNU/Linux distribution inspired by the design principles of Bunsenlabs. The main focus of this release on stability improvement, performance and usability improvements and other optimizations.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/ArchLabs_2018-02-07-18_1920x1080.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Neptune 5.4 released with a fresh look and feel</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/neptune-5.4-released-with-better-dark-theme-and-icon-theme/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Neptune 5.4 released with a fresh look and feel" /><published>2018-07-24T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-07-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/neptune-5.4-released-with-better-dark-theme-and-icon-theme</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/neptune-5.4-released-with-better-dark-theme-and-icon-theme/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Leszek&lt;/em&gt; of the Neptune project has announced the release of Neptune 5.4. It is the latest updated snapshot in Neptune 5.x series. It brings a set of updated packages and applications and avoids the need for the bulk package update after installing the operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to package updates and critical bug fixes, Neptune 5.4 brings a fresh look and feel with an improved dark theme.  This dark theme also includes a modified version of &lt;em&gt;Faenza&lt;/em&gt; icon theme. Neptune 5.4 also brings Linux Kernel 5.16.x. It ensures better hardware support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/preview/neptune5.0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A file picture of Neptune 5.0&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A file picture of Neptune 5.0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other highlights from Neptune 5.4 include,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;the update of KDE Frameworks to version 5.48  and KDE Applications to version 18.04.3. As the new KF5 version is not compatible with Qt 5.7 anymore we had to backport its patches to version 5.45.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;VLC has been updated to 3.0.3 to provide more speed and lots of bugfixes.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thunderbird 52.9 fixes issues with encrypted HTML e-mails. The Excalibur menu is now available in version 2.7 which provides some bugfixes in regards to multiple activities and moving favorites around.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;KWin the default window manager for Plasma got an update to version 5.12.5.  This offers some nice speed improvements as well as some updated effects and better hardware support.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;LibreOffice is now available in version 6.0.6. We fixed an issue with MTP causing issues to share files with Android devices.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Enlightenment 22 is now available in Version 0.22.3 together with Terminology 1.2.1.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find further information in &lt;a href=&quot;https://neptuneos.com/en/news-reader/neptune-5-4-159.html&quot;&gt;Neptune 5.4 release announcement&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://neptuneos.com/en/changelog.html&quot;&gt;Neptune 5.4 changelogs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Mr. Leszek of the Neptune project has announced the release of Neptune 5.4. It is the latest updated snapshot in Neptune 5.x series. It brings a set of updated packages and applications and avoids the need for the bulk package update after installing the operating system.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/preview/neptune5.0.jpg" /></entry></feed>