<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-03-30T08:40:09+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">OpenSourceFeed</title><subtitle>Database of various GNU/Linux, BSD and other open source distributions and different open source desktop environments with updates &amp; stories on each.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Slax 9.4 Final released with single click installation launchers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Slax-9.4-released-with-extra-applications/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Slax 9.4 Final released with single click installation launchers" /><published>2018-03-27T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Slax-9.4-released-with-extra-applications</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Slax-9.4-released-with-extra-applications/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Slax team has announced the release of Slax 9.4 &lt;em&gt;Final&lt;/em&gt;, the latest stable release of GNU/Linux distribution that follows a minimalistic and fully modular approach. This release includes package updates from base distribution, numerous bug fixes and single click installation launchers for various applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-slax&quot;&gt;What is Slax?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slax is a live GNU/Linux distribution based on Debian &lt;em&gt;stable&lt;/em&gt; branch that can be directly booted from any storage media. Despite being a small sized distribution, Slax provides a full-fledged &lt;em&gt;Fluxbox&lt;/em&gt; desktop with essential applications like command line emulator and web browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/slax94.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Preview of application launcher in Slax 9.4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-new-in-slax-94&quot;&gt;What is new in Slax 9.4?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the key highlights of Slax 9.4 release is the inclusion of shortcuts for various popular applications like VLC, VoteCoin ..etc. These applications are not included in Slax by default. But, when you try to open these applications for the first time, it will be downloaded and installed automatically. If this approach really works, then the team will try to include more application launchers in upcoming releases. You can also get in touch with Slax team to include your favorite applications in this manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slax 9.4 also includes package updates from current Debian &lt;em&gt;stable&lt;/em&gt; branch, along with numerous bug fixes. The file manager is improved to understand various file types. So, it is now easier for users to open files like images and documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slax.org/next.php&quot;&gt;Slax 9.4 road map&lt;/a&gt;, following are other changes in this release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;add rfkill so users can switch on/off their wifi devices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;make xlunch in Slax search for icons in /usr/share/pixmaps too, else many apps won’t show up in the list&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if there are more rows with icons in xLunch, next row is displayed at the bottom of the screen, should be on top&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;include libdrm-intel1, libgl1-mesa-dri, libglu1-mesa packages in Slax for direct rendering. Adds 8 MB :(&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;alright, add /usr/share/games to PATH&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;enable hotkeys in alsa config (enabling volumeUp/Dn/mute buttons)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if the filesystem is not known, do not add partition to fstab, else it fails miserably&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;add xarchiver&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;remove unneeded packages grub* vim* debconf-i18n installation-report&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;consider cbatticon as a battery monitor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setup file associations in the file manager, as per this suggestion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;add shortcuts to apps which will auto-install and then run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;download-slax-94&quot;&gt;Download Slax 9.4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;download-slax-94-64-bit-iso-260-mb&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ftp.sh.cvut.cz/slax/Slax-9.x/slax-64bit-9.4.0.iso&quot;&gt;Download Slax 9.4 64 BIT ISO&lt;/a&gt; (260 MB)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;download-slax-94-32-bit-iso-265-mb&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ftp.sh.cvut.cz/slax/Slax-9.x/slax-32bit-9.4.0.iso&quot;&gt;Download Slax 9.4 32 BIT ISO&lt;/a&gt; (265 MB)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;download-slax-94-ipxe-image-09-mb&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ftp.sh.cvut.cz/slax/Slax-9.x/slax-ipxe.iso&quot;&gt;Download Slax 9.4 IPXE Image&lt;/a&gt; (0.9 MB)&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Slax team has announced the release of Slax 9.4 Final, the latest stable release of GNU/Linux distribution that follows a minimalistic and fully modular approach. This release includes package updates from base distribution, numerous bug fixes and single click installation launchers for various applications.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/slax94.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">KDE Neon 5.12 is a cool release with a lot of potential and hope</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/KDE-neon-5.12-is-a-cool-distribution-with-a-lot-of-potential-and-hope/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KDE Neon 5.12 is a cool release with a lot of potential and hope" /><published>2018-03-21T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-21T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/KDE-neon-5.12-is-a-cool-distribution-with-a-lot-of-potential-and-hope</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/KDE-neon-5.12-is-a-cool-distribution-with-a-lot-of-potential-and-hope/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KDE Neon&lt;/strong&gt; is a distribution developed to showcase the real potential of Plasma Desktop. It is built on top of solid Ubuntu base and brings latest and greatest applications from KDE world. It helps users to experience latest features from Plasma desktop environment and other related applications without worrying about the stability of the underlying operating system. Also, the Plasma developers can show the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; Plasma to the end users by avoiding &lt;em&gt;unnecessary&lt;/em&gt; customization shipped by various distribution developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/kde-neon-5.10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A file picture of KDE Neon 5.10 User Edition&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A preview of KDE Neon 5.10 User Edition. You can find Neon 5.12 screenshots on original post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dedoimedo.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;dedoimedo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; portal has published a review on KDE Neon 5.12, a release featuring Plasma 5.12 LTS. There are numerous distributions featuring KDE Plasma Desktop. However, the review suggests KDE Neon is an ideal choice for people who fancy about Plasma Desktop and likes to experience the latest updates from Plasma World.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this review, various aspects of the distributions are being examined. The over all visual appearance is consistent, elegant and looks like a well-planned distribution. The defaults font configuration is not good enough and users are expected to enable anti-aliasing to have a better look. Despite being a lean distribution, Neon provides VLC in default installation it supports most of the multimedia files. The windows and android phones can be easily connected to the system, however, there is an issue with iPhones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The default installation of Neon ships only a few applications like Firefox, Okular, VLC, GwenView..etc. The &lt;em&gt;Discover&lt;/em&gt; package manager is not mature it. It misses a lot of expected features and better to stick with &lt;em&gt;apt&lt;/em&gt; if you are okey with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KDE Neon has an impressive resource usage graph. On idle state, it takes around 400 MB of RAM and 1-2% of CPU. This is the impact of the optimizations and improvements on Plasma 5.x release. This resource is even less than some so-called lightweight distributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the reviewer puts a remark that KDE Neon 5.12 is better than many other distributions featuring Plasma Desktop. However, it lacks hardware support to the decision to stick with a stable and long-term supported Ubuntu base. It does a fair balancing between stability and latest Plasma releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    It can do better, and we have the most splendid Kubuntu 17.04 as the golden benchmark from now on until the end of times, we few, we happy few, we band of geeks, for he who tests with me together, shall be my code brother, may his git ne'er be so vile, and the persons of all genders now in bed shall feel themselves accursed, and hold their VR sets cheap ... I think you get the idea. I got carried away. Let's summarize. KDE neon 5.12, fresh, cool, sleek, needs more apps, better package management, better overall peripheral support. But there's a lot of potential and hope, and I think we will see cool things in Plasma this year. 7.5/10. Worth checking.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read complete &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dedoimedo.com/computers/kde-neon-5-12.html&quot;&gt;KDE Neon 5.12 review in dedoimedo portal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">KDE Neon is a distribution developed to showcase the real potential of Plasma Desktop. It is built on top of solid Ubuntu base and brings latest and greatest applications from KDE world. It helps users to experience latest features from Plasma desktop environment and other related applications without worrying about the stability of the underlying operating system. Also, the Plasma developers can show the real Plasma to the end users by avoiding unnecessary customization shipped by various distribution developers.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/kde-neon-5.10.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">NetBSD 7.1.2 released with critical security and stability patches</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/NetBSD-7.1.2-released-with-security-fixes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NetBSD 7.1.2 released with critical security and stability patches" /><published>2018-03-19T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-19T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/NetBSD-7.1.2-released-with-security-fixes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/NetBSD-7.1.2-released-with-security-fixes/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; NetBSD foundation has announced the release of NetBSD 7.1.2, the second security update in NetBSD 7.1.x series. This release brings various security fixes and other stability related patches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/netbsd.png&quot; alt=&quot;NetBSD banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-netbsd&quot;&gt;What is NetBSD?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NetBSD is UNIX like operating system developed by the collaborative effort of a large group of people. It also includes a variety of other free software like 4.4BSD Lite2 developed at UC Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NetBSD implements several standard APIs and network protocols which makes it interoperable with other systems. One of the founding principles of NetBSD is to be highly portable. Towards this goal, the project has been ported to a wide range of platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find &lt;a href=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/distribution/netbsd&quot;&gt;more details on NetBSD&lt;/a&gt; in our gallery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-changed-between-netbsd-711-and-712&quot;&gt;What changed between NetBSD 7.1.1 and 7.1.2?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NetBSD 7.1.2 is a bug fix cum stability improvement update in 7.1.x series. Citing from &lt;a href=&quot;https://netbsd.org/releases/formal-7/NetBSD-7.1.2.html&quot;&gt;NetBSD 7.1.2 release announcement&lt;/a&gt; published on project’s website, following are some of the issues fixed in this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fixed Remote DoS in IPsec (IPv6) and remote memory corruption in IPv6&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Disable compat_svr4 and compat_svr4_32 by default on all ports.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Disable compat_ibcs2 everywhere but on Vax.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Remove svr4/svr4_32/ibcs2/freebsd from the module autoload list.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Disable LSRR (loose source and record route) and SSRR (strict source and record route) by default.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;amd64: Make the direct map non-executable.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;BIND: update bind.keys.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;bozohttpd(8): Fix issue where bozohttpd would fail to exec scripts via the -C mechanism.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;drm2: Fix issues preventing the use of more than one graphics device.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fix detection of duplicate symbols in kernel modules.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ipfilter: Fix a kernel panic when altering the ipf state table size at runtime.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;IPsec:
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Fix a couple use-after-free issues.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Fix IPv6-IPsec-AH tunnels.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Fix inverted logic that could crash the kernel.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Fix out-of-bounds read.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Strengthen sanity checks (AH/ESP).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;IPv6:
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Kick nested IPv6 fragments.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Fix a couple use-after-free issues.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Fix memory leak in nd6_na_input().&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ksh: Create HISTFILE with mode 0600, not 777.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;MPLS: Fix several memory corruptions and inconsistencies.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;pf: Fix signedness bug.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;sparc:
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Fix time goes backward problems.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Fix problem using the ps command in ddb.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;tlp(4): Fix timeout using the Legacy Network Adapter in Microsoft Windows Server Hyper-V VMs.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ypserv(8): Avoid returning stale request data to the client.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Xen: Prevent unrestricted userland access to I/O ports.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;download-netbsd-712&quot;&gt;Download NetBSD 7.1.2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a popular project, NetBSD 7.1.2 is hosted in several locations. You can find these servers in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netbsd.org/mirrors/&quot;&gt;NetBSD mirror listing page&lt;/a&gt;. Alternatively, you can choose a bit torrent file from &lt;a href=&quot;https://netbsd.org/mirrors/torrents/&quot;&gt;NetBSD torrent listing page&lt;/a&gt;. When downloading, please make sure that you are downloading an image compatible with your system.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The NetBSD foundation has announced the release of NetBSD 7.1.2, the second security update in NetBSD 7.1.x series. This release brings various security fixes and other stability related patches.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/netbsd.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Zorin OS 12.3 comes with improved user experience and better windows application support</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Zorin-OS-12.3-release-includes-better-windows-application-support-and-visual-improvements/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zorin OS 12.3 comes with improved user experience and better windows application support" /><published>2018-03-16T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-16T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Zorin-OS-12.3-release-includes-better-windows-application-support-and-visual-improvements</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Zorin-OS-12.3-release-includes-better-windows-application-support-and-visual-improvements/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Following&lt;/strong&gt; the release of Ubuntu 16.04.4, the Zorin Group has announced the immediate availability of Zorin OS 12.3, latest stable snapshot in projects 12.x LTS (Long Term Support) series. This release brings various package updates and bug fixes from the base distribution. It also includes several refinements to Zorin Desktop components to provide a better user experience. The windows application support is also improved with Wine 3.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/zorin123folders.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A demo of individual folder styling in Zorin OS 12.3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-new-in-zorin-os-123-release&quot;&gt;What is new in Zorin OS 12.3 release?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a snapshot update in Zorin 12.x series, Zorin OS 12.3 brings most of the updated from base release, ie, Ubuntu 16.04.4 LTS. Providing a more recent version of packages will help to ensure users have to spend less amount of time and bandwidth on updating their system after the first installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zorin OS 12.3 includes Wine 3.0, latest stable version of windows compatibility layer for POSIX like systems. This will help the system to run windows application in a faster and reliable way. Another main highlight of Wine 3.0 is the improvement in the gaming experience. By introducing Direct3D 10 &amp;amp; 11 support, Wine 3.0 enables access to a wider range of gaming libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been multiple improvements to the Zorin Desktop based on user feedback. This will provide users a better and smooth desktop experience. Some of the notable changes in Zorin Desktop includes the ability to give custom colors and emblems to each individual folders, new printer job indicator which will appear automatically when a job is initiated, ability to pin and launch applications on panel, a quick preview of applications residing on the panel ..etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zorin OS 12.3 Linux Kernel 4.13 which will provide better compatibility with modern hardware components. This Kernel also fixes various vulnerabilities like meltdown and spectre which were a hot discussion topic on open source communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-long-zorin-os-123-will-be-supported&quot;&gt;How long Zorin OS 12.3 will be supported?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zorin OS 12.x is based on Ubuntu 16.04.x LTS series. Hence, it will provide minor software updates and security patches till 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-can-i-get-zorin-os-123&quot;&gt;Where can I get Zorin OS 12.3?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are already using Zorin OS 12.x, there is no need to download a new installation unless you are planning for a fresh installation. You can run a regular system update operation to enjoy updates from Zorin OS 12.3 snapshot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zorin OS installation images can be downloaded from following links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://10gbps-io.dl.sourceforge.net/project/zorin-os/12/Zorin-OS-12.3-Core-64.iso&quot;&gt;Download Zorin OS 12.3 Core 64 bit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://10gbps-io.dl.sourceforge.net/project/zorin-os/12/Zorin-OS-12.3-Core-32.iso&quot;&gt;Download Zorin OS 12.3 Core 32 bit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you are looking to download the ultimate edition, or lite edition, proceed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://zorinos.com/download/&quot;&gt;Zorin OS download page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further information, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://zoringroup.com/blog/2018/03/15/zorin-os-12-3-released-a-stronger-more-versatile-system/&quot;&gt;Zorin OS 12.3 release announcement&lt;/a&gt; published in projects blog.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Following the release of Ubuntu 16.04.4, the Zorin Group has announced the immediate availability of Zorin OS 12.3, latest stable snapshot in projects 12.x LTS (Long Term Support) series. This release brings various package updates and bug fixes from the base distribution. It also includes several refinements to Zorin Desktop components to provide a better user experience. The windows application support is also improved with Wine 3.0.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/zorin123folders.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">MX-17.1 is available now, includes LibreOffice 6, updated MX Apps and more</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mx-linux-17.1-released-featuring-libreoffice-6-and-mx-apps-improvements/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MX-17.1 is available now, includes LibreOffice 6, updated MX Apps and more" /><published>2018-03-15T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-15T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mx-linux-17.1-released-featuring-libreoffice-6-and-mx-apps-improvements</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mx-linux-17.1-released-featuring-libreoffice-6-and-mx-apps-improvements/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Dolphin Oracle&lt;/em&gt; on behalf of MX team has announced the release of MX-17.1, the latest stable snapshot of Debian based GNU/Linux distribution striving to provide a robust desktop experience with highly customized Xfce Desktop environment. This release includes various updated packages from the base distribution, along with some bleeding edge applications and improved MX applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/mx-17.1_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of MX-17.1 Desktop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-mx-linux-or-mx&quot;&gt;What is MX Linux or MX?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MX Linux is a Debian &lt;em&gt;stable&lt;/em&gt; based operating system providing solid desktop experience. This project is inspired by the ideas established by antiX and MEPIS operating systems. It provides a stable, reliable and consistent computing ecosystem without consuming much of system resources. You can find &lt;a href=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/distribution/mx&quot;&gt;more about MX Linux&lt;/a&gt; in our gallery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-new-in-mx-171&quot;&gt;What is new in MX-17.1?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MX-17.1 is an updated snapshot in MX-17.x series. It includes all changes occurred in the base distribution, ie, Debian &lt;em&gt;stretch&lt;/em&gt; since it’s initial release. Additionally, MX-17.1 includes some bleeding edge applications and some updated applications developed by the MX project itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main highlights of MX-17.1 release can be summarized as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Includes Linux Kernel 4.15.0 in both 64 bit and 32-bit flavors. The 64-bit flavor includes patches for meltdown and spectre issues. While 4.15.0 is the default Kernel, users can easily switch between the latest liquorix kernel or Debian Stable Kernel (4.9) using MX package installer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Includes latest updates from Debian 9.4, antiX and MX repositories.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Various updated packages like
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Browser: Firefox 58.0.2 (59 hitting repo soon via update)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Video Player: VLC 2.2.8-2 (3.0 in test repo)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Music Manager/Player: Clementine 1.3.1&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Email client: Thunderbird 52.6&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Office suite: LibreOffice 6.0.1&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Backup: LuckyBackup 0.4.9-1&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Security: Passwords and Keys 3.20.0-3.1&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Terminal: Xfce4 Terminal 0.8.3-1&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The MX-Updater tools now includes an &lt;em&gt;auto update&lt;/em&gt; feature which enables background update operation without user intervention.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Includes MX-Live-USB-Maker which is a functional front end to antiX live usb maker utility and &lt;em&gt;dd&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MX-Tweaks includes a &lt;em&gt;Config Options&lt;/em&gt; tab to reset lightdm customizations and thunar actions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-can-i-download-mx-171-images&quot;&gt;Where can I download MX-17.1 images?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MX-17.1 images can be downloaded from following links&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/mx-linux/files/Final/MX-17.1/&quot;&gt;Download MX-17.1 images from sourceforge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://linuxtracker.org/download.php?id=c677c0156c605eb0633ae1587360eb7d6653f1bd&amp;amp;f=MX-17.1_386.iso.torrent&amp;amp;key=0&quot;&gt;MX-17.1 TORRENT 32 BIT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://linuxtracker.org/download.php?id=b3891c6a6036f85444e6fa26b823f28657e7cd76&amp;amp;f=MX-17.1_x64.iso.torrent&amp;amp;key=0&quot;&gt;MX-17.1 TORRENT 64 BIT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;REFERENCES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mxlinux.org/mx-171-released&quot;&gt;MX-17.1 release announcement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Mr Dolphin Oracle on behalf of MX team has announced the release of MX-17.1, the latest stable snapshot of Debian based GNU/Linux distribution striving to provide a robust desktop experience with highly customized Xfce Desktop environment. This release includes various updated packages from the base distribution, along with some bleeding edge applications and improved MX applications.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/mx-17.1_0.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tails 3.6 released with Video Acceleration API driver, UI improvements and other updates</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tails-3.6-released-with-video-acceleration-driver-api-and-other-updates/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tails 3.6 released with Video Acceleration API driver, UI improvements and other updates" /><published>2018-03-14T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-14T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tails-3.6-released-with-video-acceleration-driver-api-and-other-updates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tails-3.6-released-with-video-acceleration-driver-api-and-other-updates/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Tails team has announced the release of Tails 3.6, the latest stable snapshot of &lt;em&gt;the amnesic live incognito system&lt;/em&gt;. This release brings various user experience improvements, the driver for video acceleration, along with various updated tools and packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since each Tails release fixes various security loop holes and vulnerabilities, it is highly recommended to use the latest version of Tails always. Tails 3.6 is not an exception from this generalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/tails 720x340.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tails Linux banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-new-in-tails-36&quot;&gt;What is new in Tails 3.6?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tails 3.6 brings various user experience improvements as part of GNOME Desktop. These improvements can be summarized as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a dedicated lock button included in the system menu. Users can click this button to lock their screen instantly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If an administrative password is set while starting Tails, the system can be unlocked using administrative password. Alternatively, users can configure a password when locking screen for the first time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There has been multiple under the hood improvements for additional software persistence feature. This includes installation of additional software in background after starting the session instead of blocking the loading of desktop. Also, the software will be installed even when user is offline.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Includes pdf-redact-tools, a command line tool to clean metadata and redact PDF files by converting them to PNG images.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An error message indicating the name of the graphics card is now displayed when Tails fails to start GNOME.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Tails documentation launcher on the desktop now opens the documentation on our website if you are online.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install drivers for the Video Acceleration API to improve the display of videos on many graphics cards.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multiple package updates like Electrum 3.0.6, Linux Kernel 4.15.0, Tor 0.3.2.10, Thunderbird 52.6.0, ..etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;AppArmor&lt;/em&gt; profile for Thunderbird in Debian has been updated to protect of Thunderbird vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some of the internal scripts written in shell script has been replaced with python scripts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multiple bug fixes like removal of debug and error messages while booting, unavailability of ISO selection for non-English languages in Tails Installer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fix OpenPGP Applet being unresponsive when decrypting a lot of text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-can-i-get-tails-36&quot;&gt;Where can I get Tails 3.6?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two popular ways to get Tails operating system. The most used option is an &lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/install/index.en.html&quot;&gt;online installation wizard&lt;/a&gt; which let you download an image matches your requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, the Tails 3.6 image can be downloaded using following links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mirrors.dotsrc.org/tails/stable/tails-amd64-3.6/tails-amd64-3.6.iso&quot;&gt;Download Tails 3.6 ISO Image (1.2 GB)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/torrents/files/tails-amd64-3.6.torrent&quot;&gt;Download Tails 3.6 TORRENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read more about Tails 3.6 from following sources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/news/version_3.6/index.en.html&quot;&gt;Tails 3.6 release announcement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://git-tails.immerda.ch/tails/plain/debian/changelog&quot;&gt;Tails 3.6 changelogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Tails team has announced the release of Tails 3.6, the latest stable snapshot of the amnesic live incognito system. This release brings various user experience improvements, the driver for video acceleration, along with various updated tools and packages.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/tails%20720x340.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Neptune 5 ‘Refresh’ released; See what is new</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/neptune-os-5.0-refresh-released-with-updated-debian-base/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Neptune 5 'Refresh' released; See what is new" /><published>2018-03-13T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/neptune-os-5.0-refresh-released-with-updated-debian-base</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/neptune-os-5.0-refresh-released-with-updated-debian-base/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr&lt;/strong&gt; Leszek, on behalf of Neptune OS project, has announced the release of Neptune 5 ‘Refresh’, the latest release of Debian stable based, GNU/Linux distribution striving to provide a robust desktop experience with Plasma Desktop. This release has been rebased to Debian &lt;em&gt;Stretch&lt;/em&gt; current stable release. It includes several updated packages and implementation of several strategical decisions taken by the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/neptune5.0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of Neptune 5 'Refresh'&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-new-in-neptune-5-refresh-release&quot;&gt;What is new in Neptune 5 ‘Refresh’ release?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the Debian base change, Neptune 5 comes with several strategical changes regarding the OS release approach itself. Let’s have a quick summary of main highlights in Neptune 5 release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neptune 5 has been rebased to Debian 9.x &lt;em&gt;Stretch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beginning from this release, Neptune would not be providing the latest version of Plasma Desktop, Linux Kernel or other applications. The project will just reuse the components from upstream project. If users are curious to explore the bleeding edge applications, then cross distribution supported app formats like Flatpak, snaps, and AppImage can be used.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The main purpose of Neptune OS is to provide a robust desktop experience. Towards this goal, Neptune 5.0 includes Plasma Desktop 5.12 LTS, KDE Applications 17.12 and KDE Frameworks 5.43.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linux Kernel 3.14 from Debian stretch backports repository is included to provide better hardware support.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neptune 5.0 drops the support for proprietary packages and &lt;em&gt;zevenoshardwaremanager&lt;/em&gt;, the tool enables easy installation of proprietary drivers has been removed. Now, users should find their own way if proprietary drivers are required.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neptune 5.0 brings a refreshed user experience with a reiterated set of artworks. It provides a consistent experience across Gtk+2, Gtk+3, Qt4 and Qt5 applications.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are multiple themes available in the default installation of the Neptune and can be easily switched between these themes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updated packages like LibreOffice 6, Chromium 64, Thunderbird 52.6, Amarok 2.9, VLC 2.2 ..etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information and queries, see official &lt;a href=&quot;https://neptuneos.com/en/news-reader/neptune-5-release.html&quot;&gt;Neptune 5.0 ‘Refresh’ release announcement&lt;/a&gt; published on project’s website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Mr Leszek, on behalf of Neptune OS project, has announced the release of Neptune 5 ‘Refresh’, the latest release of Debian stable based, GNU/Linux distribution striving to provide a robust desktop experience with Plasma Desktop. This release has been rebased to Debian Stretch current stable release. It includes several updated packages and implementation of several strategical decisions taken by the team.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/neptune5.0.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Netrunner 18.03 Idolon released with a set of redesigned artworks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/netrunner-1803-idolon-released-with-a-set-of-redesigned-artworks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Netrunner 18.03 Idolon released with a set of redesigned artworks" /><published>2018-03-12T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-12T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/netrunner-1803-idolon-released-with-a-set-of-redesigned-artworks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/netrunner-1803-idolon-released-with-a-set-of-redesigned-artworks/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Netrunner team has announced the release of Netrunner 18.03 &lt;em&gt;Idolon&lt;/em&gt;, the latest stable snapshot of Debian testing based GNU/Linux distribution featuring latest plasma desktop environment. This release includes various updates from upstream distribution, along with a set of redesigned visual effects, theme and wallpapers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/netrunner%2018.03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of Netrunner 18.03&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-highlights-of-netrunner-1803-snapshot&quot;&gt;What are highlights of Netrunner 18.03 snapshot?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to various package updates and bug fixes from Debian testing branch, following are important highlights of Netrunner 18.03 snapshot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beginning from 18.03 snapshot, Netrunner will be including more packages from upstream directly. This will help the project to maintain better compatibility with base distribution while continuously updating the testing repository.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Just like in rolling edition, Netrunner 18.03 also includes &lt;em&gt;Yarock&lt;/em&gt;, a Qt-based music player which supports a wide range of online streaming networks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discover&lt;/em&gt;, the plasma software center is back in Netrunner desktop edition. Also, there is firefox with plasma integration and suse image writer. &lt;em&gt;MintUpdate&lt;/em&gt; is still available in this release to enable update in a classical way.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Netrunner 18.03 features settings window with sidebar layout. All UI related customization options can be found under &lt;em&gt;Plasma Tweaks&lt;/em&gt; tab.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Various updated packages like
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;KDE Plasma 5.12.2&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;KDE Frameworks 5.42&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;KDE Applications 17.08.3&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Qt 5.9.2&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Linux Kernel 4.14&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Firefox Quantum 58.0.1&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Thunderbird 52.6.0&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;LibreOffice 6.0.2&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-can-i-download-netrunner-1803&quot;&gt;Where can I download Netrunner 18.03?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netrunner 18.03 is only available for 64-bit architectures. The installation image has a size of 2.4 GiB and can be downloaded using following links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/netrunneros/files/netrunner-1803/netrunner-1803-64bit.iso&quot;&gt;Netrunner 18.03 ISO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/netrunneros/files/netrunner-1803/netrunner-1803-64bit.iso.torrent&quot;&gt;Netrunner 18.03 Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Netrunner team has announced the release of Netrunner 18.03 Idolon, the latest stable snapshot of Debian testing based GNU/Linux distribution featuring latest plasma desktop environment. This release includes various updates from upstream distribution, along with a set of redesigned visual effects, theme and wallpapers.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/netrunner%2018.03.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SolydXK 201801 released with Meltodown vulnerability fix, SolydXK System Settings ..etc</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/solydxk-201811-released-with-meltodown-vulnerability-fix-solydxk-system-settings-etc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SolydXK 201801 released with Meltodown vulnerability fix, SolydXK System Settings ..etc" /><published>2018-01-17T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-17T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/solydxk-201811-released-with-meltodown-vulnerability-fix-solydxk-system-settings-etc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/solydxk-201811-released-with-meltodown-vulnerability-fix-solydxk-system-settings-etc/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; SolydXK team has announced availability of SolydXK 201801, an updated snapshot for Debian based GNU/Linux distribution. This snapshot includes various updates from base distribution, latest Linux Kernel with &lt;em&gt;Meltdown&lt;/em&gt; vulnerability patch, and a centralized Control Center called &lt;em&gt;SolydXK System Settings&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/solydxk-home-banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;SolydXK banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After installation, SolydXK provides a Welcome App from which users can choose additional packages to install. This LetoDMS (Document Management System) has been removed from Welcome Application as it is not working well with SolydXK. It is also removed from project repositories. The SolydXK team suggests to use SeedDMS instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though, SolydXK is basically a Dutch operating system, it provides international community as well. The project maintainer has decided to maintain an official German image to accomodate German users. Community editions like 32 bit image and Enthusiast’s editions (based on Debian Buster) will be made available in near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other highlights from SolydXK 201801 release includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Device Driver Manager (DDM) has been integrated.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Debian Plymouth Manager has been integrated.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Add new partitions to Fstab.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Safely remove old kernel packages.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, see original release announcement published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://solydxk.com/new-solydxk-isos-released/&quot;&gt;SolydXK website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The SolydXK team has announced availability of SolydXK 201801, an updated snapshot for Debian based GNU/Linux distribution. This snapshot includes various updates from base distribution, latest Linux Kernel with Meltdown vulnerability patch, and a centralized Control Center called SolydXK System Settings.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/solydxk-home-banner.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lubuntu 17.10.1 released with fix for BIOS issue on lenovo laptops</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lubuntu-17101-released-with-fix-for-bios-issue-on-lenovo-laptops/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lubuntu 17.10.1 released with fix for BIOS issue on lenovo laptops" /><published>2018-01-12T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-12T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lubuntu-17101-released-with-fix-for-bios-issue-on-lenovo-laptops</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lubuntu-17101-released-with-fix-for-bios-issue-on-lenovo-laptops/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bringing&lt;/strong&gt; an end to the long standing uncertainty, Lubuntu team has published an updated Lubuntu 17.10 ISO which fixes BIOS issue reported in various Lenovo laptops. This issue was a hot discussion topic in Linux communities for past few days and it has raised a serious question on the credibility of Ubuntu and it’s derivatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/lubuntu17101.png&quot; alt=&quot;Lubuntu 17.10.1 banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An update for Kernel in (L)Ubuntu 17.10 with Intel SPI drivers enabled was causing the issue with Lenovo BIOS. It affects the persistence of BIOS changes, USB boot and modifiability of EFI entries. You can learn more about this issue in &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/linux/+bug/1734147&quot;&gt;launchpad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Lubuntu 17.10.1 has been released to fix a major problem affecting many Lenovo laptops that causes the computer to have BIOS problems after installing. .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Please note that the Meltdown and Spectre vulnerabilities have not been fixed in this ISO, so we advise that if you install this ISO, update directly after.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This release is no different in terms of features from the 17.10 release and is comparable to an LTS point release in that all updates since the 17.10 release have been rolled into this ISO.
The original &lt;a href=&quot;http://lubuntu.me/lubuntu-artful-atque-vale-released/&quot;&gt;release announcement of Lubuntu 17.10.1&lt;/a&gt; is available on project’s website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Bringing an end to the long standing uncertainty, Lubuntu team has published an updated Lubuntu 17.10 ISO which fixes BIOS issue reported in various Lenovo laptops. This issue was a hot discussion topic in Linux communities for past few days and it has raised a serious question on the credibility of Ubuntu and it’s derivatives.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/lubuntu17101.png" /></entry></feed>