<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-05-08T21:14:32+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">OpenSourceFeed</title><subtitle>Database of free &amp; open-source distributions and desktop environments
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Ubuntu 16.04.2 LTS will be postponed till February 9, due to boot issues</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/01-ubuntu-16042-will-delayed-till-february-9-due-to-boot-issues/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ubuntu 16.04.2 LTS will be postponed till February 9, due to boot issues" /><published>2017-02-02T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-02-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/01-ubuntu-16042-will-delayed-till-february-9-due-to-boot-issues</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/01-ubuntu-16042-will-delayed-till-february-9-due-to-boot-issues/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Leann Ogasawara&lt;/em&gt; of Ubuntu engineering team has requested the release team to postpone Ubuntu 16.04.2 LTS release till February 9. This was owing to some serious booting issues found in arm64 systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is expected that, the resolution for currently detected issue will require pulling kernel leve changes and flash kernel. Eventhough this can be completed within the scheduled time, there won’t be enough time available for testing which will raise a concern over stability of the release. Considering the seriousness of issue, &lt;em&gt;Mr Adam Cornard&lt;/em&gt; from Ubuntu release engineering team has agreed to postpone the release till February 9th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/ubuntu16042-banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ubuntu 16.04.2 banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You find these mail threads in Ubuntu &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.ubuntu.com/archives/ubuntu-release/2017-January/004015.html&quot;&gt;release mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
Hi Adam (and the Release Team),
&lt;br /&gt;
We would like to formally request an extension for 16.04.2's release.  We
have just identified a serious boot regression on arm64.  The resolution
looks to require landing changes to the kernel, flash-kernel, and possibly
d-i.  While we can likely physically get those changes into the archive in
time for the release, there would be next to no time to test this nor
provide appropriate regression testing on other platforms. We would be much
more comfortable giving that some proper testing before releasing and
therefore would like to request an additional extension for the point
release date.  Thoughts?  We will honor whatever guidance we receive from
you.
&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks,
Leann
&lt;br /&gt;
----
&lt;br /&gt;
I'm a big fan of caution when it comes to the bits that make people's
computers either boot or completely fail to, as it's pretty hard to fix
boot errors after shipping them.  So, yes, a delay for a week while all
this is landed and tested seems entirely reasonable to me.  Will push
the release to Feb 9 instead.
&lt;br /&gt;
... Adam
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><summary type="html">Mr Leann Ogasawara of Ubuntu engineering team has requested the release team to postpone Ubuntu 16.04.2 LTS release till February 9. This was owing to some serious booting issues found in arm64 systems.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/ubuntu16042-banner.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">LibreOffice 5.3 released with a tons of new features</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-libreoffice-53-released-see-what-is-new/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LibreOffice 5.3 released with a tons of new features" /><published>2017-02-02T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-02-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-libreoffice-53-released-see-what-is-new</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-libreoffice-53-released-see-what-is-new/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Document Foundation&lt;/strong&gt; has announced release of LibreOffice 5.3, latest stable release of popular
free and open source office suite. This release introduces a lot of new proffessional quality features which makes it more competing with other proprietary office suites. It will be immediately available for windows, GNU/Linux and macOS platforms and also for cloud platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LibreOffice 5.3 is a major milestone in the history projects. It introduces new features like online collaborative editing, which will increase the competency of project, also this release provides a lot of incremental improvements to make it more reliable, smooth and user friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/LibreOffice Impress - Notebookbar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;LibreOffice 5.3 with Notebookbar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major highlights in LibreOffice 5.3 can be summarized as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduces LibreOffice Online, a cloud based office suite that offers basic collaborative editing features on a web browsers. It is basically a server service and should be expected and configured by adding a cloud storage and SSL certificate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An experimental ribbon UI (MUFFIN - My User Friendly &amp;amp; Flexible INterface)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyboard shortcuts can now be displayed in context menus, and are enabled by default on Windows and Linux.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To help you work better with filled shapes, the Area dialog has been simplified and includes a new Patterns section, for better compatibility with other office software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additionally, if you want to fill a shape with a custom bitmap image, you can now import a new image directly from the sidebar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's now possible to insert PDFs into your documents as images, with the first page being shown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Furthermore, you can sign existing PDF files, and verify those signatures as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colour palette management has been simplified, and new palettes have been added for professional graphic and layout workflows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New items have been added to the Help menu, including quick links to user guides and community support forums.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Safe Mode is now available, to help you find and fix problems with your user profile or extensions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text layout has been unified for consistency across operating systems, while file format compatibility has been improved as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, LibreOffice 5.3 is the first full source code release of LibreOffice online, a browser-based version of the suite that you can run on your private cloud infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Writer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In LibreOffice 5.3, Writer has some great new features to make your documents shine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table styles are now supported, letting you apply formatting to a table which is preserved when you make edits to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new Page deck in the sidebar lets you quickly customise page settings without having to go through a separate dialog box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For faster navigation, a new Go to Page box lets you jump to another page in the document with just a few keypresses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the drawing tools, arrows that were previously only available in Draw and Impress can now be used in Writer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lastly, the toolbar includes a new Small Capitals button, and this formatting can also be applied via macros.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Calc&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LibreOffice 5.3 has many improvements in Calc, to help you work smarter with spreadsheets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new set of default cell styles are now available, with greater variety and better names than in previous releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In fresh installations, &quot;Enable wildcards in formulas&quot; is now the default option, rather than regular expressions, to improve compatibility with other spreadsheet software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you're creating pivot tables, a new median function is now available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The merge cells feature now lets you empty the contents of cells that are hidden after the merge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, when you're inserting a function, a new text entry box lets you narrow down the functions you're looking for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Impress &amp;amp; Draw&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In LibreOffice 5.3, Impress has been updated to make your presentations really stand out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you launch the software, a template selector now appears to get you off to a quick start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two new attractive templates have been included by default, whileothers have been improved as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you're inserting images from a photo album, it's now possible to link these images so that they're not saved in the document itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lastly, in slide master mode, slide properties are now available in the sidebar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details, see release announcement published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.documentfoundation.org/blog/2017/02/01/the-document-foundation-announces-feature-rich-libreoffice-5-3/&quot;&gt;document foundation blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">The Document Foundation has announced release of LibreOffice 5.3, latest stable release of popular
free and open source office suite. This release introduces a lot of new proffessional quality features which makes it more competing with other proprietary office suites. It will be immediately available for windows, GNU/Linux and macOS platforms and also for cloud platforms.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/LibreOffice%20Impress%20-%20Notebookbar.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">KDE neon offers a near perfect desktop on a stable base</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-kde-neon-offers-perfect-desktop-on-stable-base/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KDE neon offers a near perfect desktop on a stable base" /><published>2017-02-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-02-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-kde-neon-offers-perfect-desktop-on-stable-base</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-kde-neon-offers-perfect-desktop-on-stable-base/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KDE neon&lt;/strong&gt; is an amazing GNU/Linux distribution developed by the KDE community. It integrates most up-to-date
KDE Plasma desktop and other KDE community developed applications on stable base of Ubuntu LTS (Long Term
Supported) releases. While the core remains the same (LTS release of Ubuntu), the KDE components get
contineous updates to provide most modern KDE technologies to the end users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/neon_a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Preview of KDE neon Desktop&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Courtesy : Linux.com portal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Linux.com&lt;/em&gt; portal has published a review on KDE neon project which observes that, the project a 
success for providing an almost perfect desktop environment to the end users. The review begins by 
stating that, the user interest has dramatically moved away from KDE project over the years. Plasma 3
was able to attract a lot of users owing to it’s simplcity and traditional user experience. However, Plasma 4
made the system more heavy and was not that responsive. Plasma 5 was able to overcome limitations of 
Plasma 4 by making system more responsive and resource efficient. Still it was lagging behind due to
sticking with a traditional desktop metaphor and the desktop was buggy on most of the platforms. The
KDE neon project was started to show-off how well, KDE Plasma desktop can be integrated with a GNU/Linux
distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the review, KDE neon provides a smooth Plasma experience to the end users. The project is
integrating a nice flat theme, and it is very stable and fast comparing to KDE Plasma 4. The widget management
has also becomes much easier. However, there are some rough edges like, lack of commonly used applications
like office suites and somewhat outdated packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
To recover a bit of that lost ground, the KDE developers opted to fork Ubuntu into KDE Neon. The launch of Neon didn’t quite go as planned (and the initial release wasn’t exactly stable). Since then, however, the project has managed to pull off something quite intriguing. KDE Neon takes the stability of Ubuntu 16.04 and applies a cutting-edge release of the KDE desktop to create an absolutely beautiful experience, that could easily appease those looking for the best of both worlds.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read complete review in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linux.com/learn/kde-neon-offers-near-perfect-desktop-solid-platform&quot;&gt;linux.com&lt;/a&gt; portal.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">KDE neon is an amazing GNU/Linux distribution developed by the KDE community. It integrates most up-to-date
KDE Plasma desktop and other KDE community developed applications on stable base of Ubuntu LTS (Long Term
Supported) releases. While the core remains the same (LTS release of Ubuntu), the KDE components get
contineous updates to provide most modern KDE technologies to the end users.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/neon_a.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bodhi Linux 4.1.0 released with Linux 4.8 and Arc inspired moksha theme</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/01-bodhi-linux-410-released-with-linux-kernel-48/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bodhi Linux 4.1.0 released with Linux 4.8 and Arc inspired moksha theme" /><published>2017-01-29T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-01-29T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/01-bodhi-linux-410-released-with-linux-kernel-48</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/01-bodhi-linux-410-released-with-linux-kernel-48/">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;/distribution/bodhi&quot;&gt;Bodhi Linux&lt;/a&gt; team has announced release of Bodhi Linux 4.1.0, latest maintenance cum bug fix release in Bodhi Linux 4 branch. This release comes with several updated packages and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who are not familiar with Bodhi Linux, it is an Ubuntu LTS based GNU/Linux distribution featuring Enlightenment inspired &lt;a href=&quot;/desktop/moksha&quot;&gt;Moksha desktop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/bodhi410.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bodhi Linux 4.1.0 Preview&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Bodhi Linux 4.1.0 Preview&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newly announced Bodhi Linux 4.1.0 features updated packages like EFL 1.18.4, and updated version of Enlightenment Foundation Libraries, Linux Kernel 4.8 which comes with improved support for different graphics cards, and a new Moksha desktop theme inspired by Arc Dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The existing users of Bodhi Linux 4.x, can avail all the bug fixes by a simple system update. But they need to take manual actions for changing linux kernel and to use updated dark theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
This release serves to package up the fixes for a few bugs that slipped through the cracks in the 4.0.0 release, as well as provided updated package sets for the install ISO images. Most notably these ISO images come with EFL 1.18.4, Linux Kernel 4.8, and a new Moksha Theme based on the “Arc Dark” theme. Existing Bodhi 4.0.0 users already have the bug fixes incorporated into these ISO images, but they will need to manually install the newer kernel and theme if they wish to utilize them.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also find original &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bodhilinux.com/2017/01/27/bodhi-linux-4-1-0-released/&quot;&gt;release announcement&lt;/a&gt; and a few screenshtos in Bodhi Linux blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download Bodhi Linux 4.1.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;64bit &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.1.0/bodhi-4.1.0-64.iso/download&quot;&gt;ISO Download&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;– &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.1.0/bodhi-4.1.0-64.iso.torrent/download&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;32bit &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.1.0/bodhi-4.1.0-32.iso/download&quot;&gt;ISO Download&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.1.0/bodhi-4.1.0-32.iso.torrent/download&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Legacy &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;– &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.1.0/bodhi-4.1.0-legacy.iso/download&quot;&gt;ISO Download&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.0.0/bodhi-4.0.0-legacy.iso.torrent/download&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;64bit AppPack – &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.1.0/bodhi-4.1.0-apppack-64.iso/download&quot;&gt;ISO Download&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.1.0/bodhi-4.1.0-apppack-64.iso.torrent/download&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;32bit AppPack – &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.1.0/bodhi-4.1.0-apppack-32.iso/download&quot;&gt;ISO Download&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.1.0/bodhi-4.1.0-apppack-32.iso.torrent/download&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><summary type="html">The Bodhi Linux team has announced release of Bodhi Linux 4.1.0, latest maintenance cum bug fix release in Bodhi Linux 4 branch. This release comes with several updated packages and bug fixes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/bodhi410.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Linux Mint 18.1 Serena Xfce &amp;amp; KDE editions released</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-linuxmint-181-serena-xfce-and-kde-editions-released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linux Mint 18.1 Serena Xfce &amp; KDE editions released" /><published>2017-01-29T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-01-29T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-linuxmint-181-serena-xfce-and-kde-editions-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-linuxmint-181-serena-xfce-and-kde-editions-released/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/distribution/linuxmint&quot;&gt;Linux Mint&lt;/a&gt; community has announced release of Linux Mint 18.1 Serena Xfce and KDE editions. These releases includes packages updates and usability improvements to provide a better user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux Mint 18.1 a long term supported (LTS) release based on Ubuntu 16.04 LTS and it will continue to get critical security updates till 2021. Thereafter, the release will be discarded and users are expected to upgrade their system to a newer release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/linuxmint-xfce-181.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Linux Mint 18.1 Xfce Preview&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Linux Mint 18.1 Xfce Desktop&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major highlights in both KDE &amp;amp; Xfce flavors can be summarized as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KDE Plasma 5.8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whisker application menu in Xfce flavor is upgraded to version 1.6.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new cross desktop compatible collection of common applications, X-Apps developed by Linux Mint project which includes text editor, media player, document viewer..etc. All these apps are inspired by old gnome school applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved update manager which include option to sort package updates based on origin and displays kernel versions in a more clear way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better language support which includes translated text for more packages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;World Wide availability &lt;/i&gt;of packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated MDM - Mint Display Manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Banshee music player is replaced with Rhythmbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved artwork&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux Kernel 4.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details, see separate release announcements for &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.linuxmint.com/?p=3222&quot;&gt;Xfce&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxmint.com/rel_serena_kde_whatsnew.php&quot;&gt;KDE&lt;/a&gt; flavors of Linux Mint 18.1.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">The Linux Mint community has announced release of Linux Mint 18.1 Serena Xfce and KDE editions. These releases includes packages updates and usability improvements to provide a better user experience.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/linuxmint-xfce-181.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">WINE 2.0 stable released with MS Office 2013 support</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/wine-2.0-stable-released-with-ms-office-2013-support/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WINE 2.0 stable released with MS Office 2013 support " /><published>2017-01-27T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-01-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/wine-2.0-stable-released-with-ms-office-2013-support</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/wine-2.0-stable-released-with-ms-office-2013-support/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally&lt;/strong&gt; the WINE (recursive acronym for Wine Is Not Emulator) developers has announced availability of Wine 2.0 stable release. This release includes numerous changes on underlying components and comes with better application support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wine is basically a compatibly layer for running windows binary executables on different POSIX compliant platforms like GNU/Linux, BSD and macOS. WINE is not a mere emulator, instead it maps windows system calls into native system calls on real time and hence provide better performance than an emulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/wine banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;WINE banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main highlight of WINE 2.0 is support for MS Office 2013, new office suite published by Microsoft Corporation and 64 bit application support in macOS operating system. It took almost one complete year to finish development of WINE 2.0 and it includes around 6,600 individual revisions after previous release. These revisoins provides support for a lot of new games and applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WINE 2.0 is first stable release in revised annual release plan for the project. When a release is published strict annual basis, there can be space for some incomplete changes and WINE 2.0 is not and exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    This release represents over a year of development effort and around 6,600 individual changes. The main highlights are the support for Microsoft Office 2013, and the 64-bit support on macOS.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    It also contains a lot of improvements across the board, as well as support for many new applications and games. See the release notes below for a summary of the major changes.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    This is the first release made on the new time-based, annual release schedule. This implies that some features that are being worked on but couldn't be finished in time have been deferred to the next development cycle. This includes in particular the Direct3D command stream, the full HID support, the Android graphics driver, and message-mode pipes.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a complete list of changes, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winehq.org/announce/2.0&quot;&gt;release announcement&lt;/a&gt; in WINE project website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Finally the WINE (recursive acronym for Wine Is Not Emulator) developers has announced availability of Wine 2.0 stable release. This release includes numerous changes on underlying components and comes with better application support.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/wine%20banner.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tails 2.10 released with OnionShare and other updated packages</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tails-210-released-with-onion-share-and-updated-packages/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tails 2.10 released with OnionShare and other updated packages" /><published>2017-01-27T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-01-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tails-210-released-with-onion-share-and-updated-packages</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tails-210-released-with-onion-share-and-updated-packages/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Tails developers has announced release of Tails 2.10, latest maintenance release of Debian based  &lt;em&gt;amnesic incognito live system&lt;/em&gt; that offers provision for anonymous and secure browsing. This release fixes many issues reported in previous releases and comes with several updated packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A notable highlight of Tails 2.10 is inclusion of OnionShare an anonymous file sharing tool, and  tor circuit view is enabled in tor browser which will show the nodes through which connection is made to the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/tails image.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tails banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other notable updates/changes in this release includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrade Tor to 0.2.9.9.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrade Tor Browser to 6.5.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrade Linux to 4.8. This should improve the support for newer hardware (graphics, Wi-Fi, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrade Icedove to 45.6.0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replace AdBlock Plus with uBlock Origin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure the APT package manage to use Debian's Onion services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install the AMDGPU display driver. This should improve the support for newer AMD graphics adapters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renamed the Boot Loader Menu entries from &quot;Live&quot; to &quot;Tails&quot;, and replaced the confusing &quot;failsafe&quot; wording with &quot;Troubleshooting Mode&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add support for exFAT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove Nyx (previously called arm).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rewrite Tor control port filter entirely. Now Tails can safely support OnionShare, the circuit view of Tor Browser, and similar. This also enabled Whonix to replace their own similar piece of software with this one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made OnionCircuits compatible with the Orca screen reader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also find out &lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/news/version_2.10/index.en.html&quot;&gt;release announcement&lt;/a&gt; in tails website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">The Tails developers has announced release of Tails 2.10, latest maintenance release of Debian based  amnesic incognito live system that offers provision for anonymous and secure browsing. This release fixes many issues reported in previous releases and comes with several updated packages.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/tails%20image.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">elementary OS Loki ships first set of updates in 2017</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/elementary-loki-ships-first-set-of-updates-in-2017/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="elementary OS Loki ships first set of updates in 2017" /><published>2017-01-27T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-01-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/elementary-loki-ships-first-set-of-updates-in-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/elementary-loki-ships-first-set-of-updates-in-2017/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/distribution/elementary&quot;&gt;elementary&lt;/a&gt; team has announced shipping of first set of updates in 2017 for most celebrated release of project, elementary OS 0.4 Loki. These updates includes fixes for bugs detected in after the base release and also includes some new features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/elementary.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;elementary OS Preview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main highlights of elementary Loki update can be summarized as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Photos : &lt;/b&gt;The biggest change with Photos, the image viewer application in elementary, is a revamped meta bar which lists image details in a more human readable way. It includes image resolution, camera details, and image location details in a more friendly manner. Other changes are inclusion of new keyboard shortcuts and support for GIF format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Files : &lt;/b&gt;In updated Files application, file search can be initiated just by start typing. Earlier an explicit Ctrl + F shortcut was required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Parental Control : &lt;/b&gt;There were some issues which was preventing Parental Controlling system from working. Those issues has been addressed and you can expect parental control system to work as expected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Network Indicator : &lt;/b&gt;Icons used in network indicator has been updated to indicated correct status of connection in a more understandable way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Application Menu : &lt;/b&gt;CJK input related issue associated with application menu is fixed. This issue was pending for a long time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other updated packages like Captive Network Assistant, Calculator, Terminal, Improved look &amp;amp; feel, bluetooth indicator and many more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a detailed change list and screenshtos, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/elementaryos/loki-updates-for-the-new-year-ff6b6ba65531#.x25pgg30c&quot;&gt;original announcement&lt;/a&gt; made by elementary team on projects blog.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">The elementary team has announced shipping of first set of updates in 2017 for most celebrated release of project, elementary OS 0.4 Loki. These updates includes fixes for bugs detected in after the base release and also includes some new features.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/elementary.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">LMDE 2 Betsy is getting an updated image after two years</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/04-lmde-2-betsy-is-getting-an-updated-image/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LMDE 2 Betsy is getting an updated image after two years" /><published>2017-01-27T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-01-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/04-lmde-2-betsy-is-getting-an-updated-image</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/04-lmde-2-betsy-is-getting-an-updated-image/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; LMDE (acronym for Linux Mint Debian Edition) team has announced plan to release an updated image for LMDE 2 Betsey which was released in 2015. Towards this plan, the project has published an updated beta image which can be used for testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/lmde-cinnamon_2017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;LMDE Cinnamon Preview (2017)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who are not familiar with LMDE, it is a &lt;a href=&quot;/distribution/debian&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; based, semi-rolling GNU/Linux distribution developed by &lt;a href=&quot;/distribution/linuxmint&quot;&gt;Linux Mint&lt;/a&gt; team. It features Cinnamon &amp;amp; MATE Desktops as official Linux Mint releases, but the difference is in its rolling behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a rolling distribution, LMDE 2 has got several major and minor updates over past two years. This includes updates MATE &amp;amp; Cinnamon desktops and updated linux kernels. All these updates will be available in new installation media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For original announcement and discussions on updated image of LMDE 2, see &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.linuxmint.com/?p=3212&quot;&gt;projects blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
Download Linux Mint Debian Edition 2 beta (2017)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
Cinnamon - &lt;a href=&quot;http://torrents.linuxmint.com/torrents/lmde-2-201701-cinnamon-64bit-beta.iso.torrent&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TORRENT&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://mirrors.evowise.com/linuxmint/testing/lmde-2-201701-cinnamon-64bit-beta.iso&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ISO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
MATE - &lt;a href=&quot;http://torrents.linuxmint.com/torrents/lmde-2-201701-mate-64bit-beta.iso.torrent&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TORRENT&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://mirrors.evowise.com/linuxmint/testing/lmde-2-201701-mate-64bit-beta.iso&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ISO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><summary type="html">The LMDE (acronym for Linux Mint Debian Edition) team has announced plan to release an updated image for LMDE 2 Betsey which was released in 2015. Towards this plan, the project has published an updated beta image which can be used for testing.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/lmde-cinnamon_2017.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">OpenSourceFeed : Weekly News Feed 79</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/newsfeed/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenSourceFeed : Weekly News Feed 79" /><published>2017-01-22T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-01-22T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/newsfeed</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/newsfeed/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welcome&lt;/strong&gt; to the 79th Weekly News Feed of OpenSourceFeed portal. This week, we have migrated to a different
platform to provide news in a more organized way. In this platform we have individual pages for each
popular distributions and desktop environments and you can find news related to each of them in their
respective pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/news feed.png&quot; alt=&quot;News Feed Banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; class=&quot;entry&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/running-arch-linux-on-lenovo-yoga-900/&quot;&gt;&lt;span xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/feed.xml&quot;&gt;Running Arch Linux on a Lenovo Yoga 900&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;lastUpdated&quot;&gt;01/20/2017 05:30 AM&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/running-arch-linux-on-lenovo-yoga-900/&quot; class=&quot;feedEntryContent&quot;&gt;Over the years GNU/Linux operating system has grown to support a wide range of hardware devices. Also, there are some companies like system 76 who mainly focus on building GNU/Linux powered laptops. Most of the big players like HP, Dell, Lenovo has introduced few special laptops to attract GNU/Linux enthusiasts.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; class=&quot;entry&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/elementary-os-looks-cool-but-package-management-is-a-pain/&quot;&gt;&lt;span xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/running-arch-linux-on-lenovo-yoga-900/&quot;&gt;elementary OS looks cool but package management is a pain : Review&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;lastUpdated&quot;&gt;01/20/2017 05:30 AM&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/elementary-os-looks-cool-but-package-management-is-a-pain/&quot; class=&quot;feedEntryContent&quot;&gt;elementary OS has received a lot of visibility within a relatively small span of time and introducing elementary OS will be redundant for an average GNU/Linux user. If someone does not have heard about elementary, it is an Ubuntu LTS based GNU/Linux distribution shipping a simple, elegant &amp;amp; responsive user interface which is called as Pantheon. Pantheon features some cool components like Slingshot application menu, switchboard configuration app, a cool dock ..etc.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; class=&quot;entry&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/linuxmint-18-1-kde-beta-released/&quot;&gt;&lt;span xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/elementary-os-looks-cool-but-package-management-is-a-pain/&quot;&gt;Linux Mint 18.1 KDE beta released&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;lastUpdated&quot;&gt;01/16/2017 05:30 AM&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/linuxmint-18-1-kde-beta-released/&quot; class=&quot;feedEntryContent&quot;&gt;The Linux Mint team has announced availability of Linux Mint 18.1 KDE beta, development 
release for upcoming Linux Mint distribution featuring KDE Plasma as default desktop environment.
Linux Mint 18.x series is based on Ubuntu 16.04 LTS and hence will be supported till 2021.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; class=&quot;entry&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/debian-9-stretch-installer-rc1-released/&quot;&gt;&lt;span xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/linuxmint-18-1-kde-beta-released/&quot;&gt;Debian 9 Stretch installer rc1 released&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;lastUpdated&quot;&gt;01/16/2017 05:30 AM&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/debian-9-stretch-installer-rc1-released/&quot; class=&quot;feedEntryContent&quot;&gt;The Debian Installer team has announced availability of first release candidate for 
Debian 9 Stretch Installer rc1. This release is coming after several alpha releases and 
can expect improved stability and robustness.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; class=&quot;entry&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/debian-8-7-released-with-security-fixes/&quot;&gt;&lt;span xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/debian-9-stretch-installer-rc1-released/&quot;&gt;Debian 8.7 released with critical security fixes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;lastUpdated&quot;&gt;01/15/2017 05:30 AM&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/debian-8-7-released-with-security-fixes/&quot; class=&quot;feedEntryContent&quot;&gt;Debian - The Universal Operating System developers has announced release of Debian 8.7, 7th updated snapshot in Debian 8.x Jessy branch. This release includes some security fixes and resolutions for other critical issues reported in previous snapshots.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; class=&quot;entry&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/manjaro-170-alpha2-released-with-kde-and-xfce-flavors/&quot;&gt;&lt;span xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/debian-8-7-released-with-security-fixes/&quot;&gt;Manjaro 17.0 Gellivara Alpha 2 released in KDE &amp;amp; Xfce flavors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;lastUpdated&quot;&gt;01/11/2017 05:30 AM&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/manjaro-170-alpha2-released-with-kde-and-xfce-flavors/&quot; class=&quot;feedEntryContent&quot;&gt;Mr Philm - member of Manjaro development team has announced availability of Manjaro 17.0 Alpha 2 
for testing. As any other official releases of Manjaro, this release also includes KDE &amp;amp; Xfce flavors.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; class=&quot;entry&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/mx-linux-16-keeps-a-good-balance-between-performance-and-elegance-review/&quot;&gt;&lt;span xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/manjaro-170-alpha2-released-with-kde-and-xfce-flavors/&quot;&gt;MX Linux 16 keeps a good balance between performance and elegance : Review&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;lastUpdated&quot;&gt;01/09/2017 05:30 AM&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/mx-linux-16-keeps-a-good-balance-between-performance-and-elegance-review/&quot; class=&quot;feedEntryContent&quot;&gt;MX Linux is a Debian stable based GNU/Linux distribution grown as a cooperative venture between the antiX and retired MEPIS communities. It makes use of best tools and technologies from both distributions. In terms of resource usage, it is expected to be a midweight(somewhere between lightweight and heavy distributions) which combines a beautiful and efficient Xfce desktop with 
Debian to provide a highly stable, solid operating system.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; class=&quot;entry&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/deepin-technology-gets-a-new-community-website/&quot;&gt;&lt;span xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/mx-linux-16-keeps-a-good-balance-between-performance-and-elegance-review/&quot;&gt;Deepin Technology gets a new community website&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;lastUpdated&quot;&gt;01/09/2017 05:30 AM&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/deepin-technology-gets-a-new-community-website/&quot; class=&quot;feedEntryContent&quot;&gt;The Deepin Technology team has announced launch of new community website for the deepin technology - a Chinese firm doing innovative development on free &amp;amp; open source technologies.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; class=&quot;entry&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/ultimate-50-gamers-edition-released/&quot;&gt;&lt;span xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/deepin-technology-gets-a-new-community-website/&quot;&gt;Ultimate 5.0 Gamers Edition released&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;lastUpdated&quot;&gt;01/08/2017 05:30 AM&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/ultimate-50-gamers-edition-released/&quot; class=&quot;feedEntryContent&quot;&gt;Mr Theehman, core developer of Ultimate OS has announced release of Ultimate 5.0 Gamers edition, latest stable release of Ubuntu based GNU/Linux distribution specifically developed for gamers. This release ships numerous games of reasonable quality.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; class=&quot;entry&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/Maui-Linux-2.1-is-a-suprisingly-good-plasma-distribution-Review/&quot;&gt;&lt;span xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/ultimate-50-gamers-edition-released/&quot;&gt;Maui Linux 2.1 is a suprisingly good plasma distribution : Review&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;lastUpdated&quot;&gt;01/08/2017 05:30 AM&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div xml:base=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/Maui-Linux-2.1-is-a-suprisingly-good-plasma-distribution-Review/&quot; class=&quot;feedEntryContent&quot;&gt;The Maui Linux is a reborn version of Ubuntu based Netrunner Desktop edition featuring KDE Plasma desktop. Netrunner Desktop edition is still alive (at least by that name), but is based on Debian instead of Ubuntu. Maui Linux is based on KDE Neon project which is basically Ubuntu LTS with latest KDE Plasma presentation layer.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><summary type="html">Welcome to the 79th Weekly News Feed of OpenSourceFeed portal. This week, we have migrated to a different
platform to provide news in a more organized way. In this platform we have individual pages for each
popular distributions and desktop environments and you can find news related to each of them in their
respective pages.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/news%20feed.png" /></entry></feed>
