<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-12-01T11:18:41+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">OpenSourceFeed</title><subtitle>Database of free &amp; open-source distributions and desktop environments
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Linux Mint 18.3 Sylvia MATE &amp;amp; Cinnamon editions released</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/linux-mint-183-sylvia-mate-and-cinnamon-editions-released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linux Mint 18.3 Sylvia MATE &amp; Cinnamon editions released" /><published>2017-11-27T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-11-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/linux-mint-183-sylvia-mate-and-cinnamon-editions-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/linux-mint-183-sylvia-mate-and-cinnamon-editions-released/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Linux Mint team has announced release of Linux Mint 18.3 MATE &amp;amp; Cinnamon editions with code name &lt;em&gt;Sylvia&lt;/em&gt;. This release is based on Ubuntu 16.04.x LTS branch and will be supported till 2021. It comes with various updated packages and desktop refinements to provide a more reliable and efficient experience to it’s users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/linuxmint18.3mate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Preview of Linux Mint 18.3 MATE edition&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the important highlights in Linux Mint 18.3 release includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Redesigned app center - Linux Mint was one of the early adopters of App Center concept in GNU/Linux &amp;amp; BSD world. It’s app center was looking the same since it’s inception. By this release, Linux Mint team has spent significant effort on app centre redesign. Inspired by GNOME Software, it provides more consistent and reliable user experience. It features various commonly used applications like Spotify, WhatsApp, Skype, Google Earth, Steam or Minecraft ..etc&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Linux Mint 18.3 introduces support for flatpak, a modern binary distribution system. It helps to install bleeding edge packages in your system even if dependencies are not met.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The backup tool was completely rewritten to make it simple, efficient and effective.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Linux Mint 18.3 features Timeshift, a tool dedicated to system snapshots.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A new tool called “System Reports” was developed for Linux Mint 18.3. Its goal is to generate reports when software crashes occur, and to show information relevant to your computer and your environment.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Also, there are multiple improvements in XApps, a OS independent collection of applications maintained by Linux Mint team.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;and more..&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information see separate &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.linuxmint.com/?p=3457&quot;&gt;official release announcements for Linux Mint Cinnamon&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.linuxmint.com/?p=3458&quot;&gt;MATE editions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Linux Mint team has announced release of Linux Mint 18.3 MATE &amp;amp; Cinnamon editions with code name Sylvia. This release is based on Ubuntu 16.04.x LTS branch and will be supported till 2021. It comes with various updated packages and desktop refinements to provide a more reliable and efficient experience to it’s users.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/linuxmint18.3mate.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lumina Desktop 1.4.0 released with various runtime optimizations, feature improvemets &amp;amp; more</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lumina-desktop-140-released-with-various-runtime-optimizations-feature-improvemets-and-more/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lumina Desktop 1.4.0 released with various runtime optimizations, feature improvemets &amp; more" /><published>2017-11-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-11-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lumina-desktop-140-released-with-various-runtime-optimizations-feature-improvemets-and-more</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lumina-desktop-140-released-with-various-runtime-optimizations-feature-improvemets-and-more/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Ken Moore&lt;/em&gt; on behalf of TrueOS project has announced release of Lumina Desktop 1.4.0, latest stable release of highly configurable desktop environment written from scractch. This release brings various improvements ranging from runtime optimizations to feature additions. It also implements support for ZFS, an advanced file system format which facilitate large scale data storage in a secure way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/lumina1.4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lumina Desktop 1.4.0 Preview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Various changes in Lumina Desktop 1.4.0 includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The Lumina theme engine : It is a new component of the “core” desktop, and provides enhanced theming capabilities for the desktop as well as all Qt5 applications. While it started out life as a fork of the “qt5ct” utility, it quickly grew all sorts of new features and functionality such as system-defined color profiles, modular theme components, and built-in editors/creators for all components.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The Lumina PDF Viewer : This is a new, stand-alone desktop utility for viewing/printing/presenting PDF documents. It uses the poppler-qt5 library in the backend for rendering the document, but uses multi-threading in many ways (such as to speed up the loading of pages) to give the user a nice, streamlined utility for viewing PDF documents.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Various updated packages &amp;amp; bug fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a complete list of changes, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://lumina-desktop.org/version-1-4-0-released/&quot;&gt;original release announcement for Lumina Desktop 1.4.0&lt;/a&gt; published in Lumina blog.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="[&quot;linux&quot;, &quot;desktop&quot;, &quot;lumina&quot;, &quot;release&quot;]" /><summary type="html">Mr Ken Moore on behalf of TrueOS project has announced release of Lumina Desktop 1.4.0, latest stable release of highly configurable desktop environment written from scractch. This release brings various improvements ranging from runtime optimizations to feature additions. It also implements support for ZFS, an advanced file system format which facilitate large scale data storage in a secure way.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/lumina1.4.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Korora 27 development started with code name Marlin</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/korora-27-development-started-with-code-name-marlin/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Korora 27 development started with code name Marlin" /><published>2017-11-22T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-11-22T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/korora-27-development-started-with-code-name-marlin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/korora-27-development-started-with-code-name-marlin/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Korora team has started working on Korora 27, upcoming stable release of Fedora based GNU/Linux distribution providing additional plugins and addons to provide better user experience. Korora 27 will be known by the code name &lt;em&gt;Marlin&lt;/em&gt;. This name follows tradition of Korora project by naming their releases with characters from &lt;em&gt;Finding Nemo&lt;/em&gt; series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/korora-laptop.png&quot; alt=&quot;Korora Preview Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Korora team has already prepared a few experimental ISOs and has started working on layouts for various spins, and ISO testing is also in progress. Once everything is set, Korora 27 will be officially announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From official statement made by Korora team:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For our next release, Korora 27, we have decided that the codename will be “Marlin” which continues the tradition of having codenames based on characters from “Finding Nemo”. The development on Korora 27 is in full progress, this involves fixing the layouts on a couple of our spins and of course building and testing iso’s which is done by the team. Once we are satisfied and everything works as should the final iso’s will be build, tested and released. For the upcoming release we are using Canvas to build, maintain our ISO’s and much more.
You can find &lt;a href=&quot;https://kororaproject.org/about/news/korora-27-codename-has-been-given-and-development-started&quot;&gt;blog post on Korora 27&lt;/a&gt; published in Korora website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Korora team has started working on Korora 27, upcoming stable release of Fedora based GNU/Linux distribution providing additional plugins and addons to provide better user experience. Korora 27 will be known by the code name Marlin. This name follows tradition of Korora project by naming their releases with characters from Finding Nemo series.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/korora-laptop.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kali Linux 2017.03 released</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/kali-linux-201703-released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kali Linux 2017.03 released" /><published>2017-11-21T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-11-21T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/kali-linux-201703-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/kali-linux-201703-released/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Dookie&lt;/em&gt; on behalf of Kali Linux team has announced release of Kali Linux 2017.3, latest bug fix cum maitenance release of Kali Linux. This release includes various patches, bug fixes, updates and added packages comparing to previous release, ie, Kali Linux 2017.2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kali Linux comes with Linux Kernel 4.13.10 which includes major improvements like SMB 3.0 as default backend for CIFS, increased directory entry limit for EXT4 and built in support for TLS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/kali-release.png&quot; alt=&quot;Kali Linux release banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kali Linux 2017.3 also includes some new tools which will come handy during security assesments and penetration testing. Tools added in this relese includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;InSpy : A small but useful utility that performs enumeration on LinkedIn and can find people based on job title, company, or email address.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;CherryTree - The oft-requested CherryTree has now been added to Kali for all of your note-taking needs. CherryTree is very easy to use and will be familiar to you if you’ve used any of the “big-name” note organization applications.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sublist3r - Sublist3r is a great application that enables you to enumerate subdomains across multiple sources at once. It has integrated the venerable SubBrute, allowing you to also brute force subdomains using a wordlist.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;OSRFramework - Another excellent OSINT tool that has been added to the repos is OSRFramework, a collection of scripts that can enumerate users, domains, and more across over 200 separate services.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Also, Massive Maltego Metamorphosis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on Kali Linux 2017.3 release see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kali.org/releases/kali-linux-2017-3-release/&quot;&gt;original release announcement&lt;/a&gt; published in Kali website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Mr Dookie on behalf of Kali Linux team has announced release of Kali Linux 2017.3, latest bug fix cum maitenance release of Kali Linux. This release includes various patches, bug fixes, updates and added packages comparing to previous release, ie, Kali Linux 2017.2.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/kali-release.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">deepin 15.5 beta released with small yet useful features</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/deepin-155-beta-released-with-small-yet-useful-features/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="deepin 15.5 beta released with small yet useful features" /><published>2017-11-15T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-11-15T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/deepin-155-beta-released-with-small-yet-useful-features</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/deepin-155-beta-released-with-small-yet-useful-features/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; deepin community has announced availability of deepin 15.5 beta for testing. This release brings various small feature additions and improvements to provide a better user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the feature additions in deepin 15.5 beta release includes, new web application framework, support for flatpack pages, color temperature feature, better compatibility for WUXGA displays… etc. Also, there are multiple optimizations applied on network module and desktop environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/deepin 15.5 beta.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;deepin 15.5 beta preview image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other highlights in deepin 15.5 beta release includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Optimized proxy function, fast export configured VPN and import existing VPN file.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Application proxy function - When set proxy, different applications required different environment (such as Netease Cloud Music and Spotify), then you can enable Application Proxy for specified applications.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Launcher icon scaling - On device with WUXGA screen, the system will auto adjust the icon size for your sreen. On common device, you can freely resize the icon by shortcuts and mouse wheel (Ctrl =/- or Ctrl+mouse wheel).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Desktop icon collision avoidance - Besides Auto Arrange, if you want to move an icon to a location on desktop, just drag and drop it before another icon which will leave a location.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ability to hide plugins on dock - n Fashion and Efficient mode, if you want to reduce space on Dock, right click on Dock to select Plugins and uncheck the plugin to hide it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ability to force quit applications&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ability to clear package cache directory.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deepin.org/en/2017/11/15/deepin-15-5-beta-small-and-beautiful-features/&quot;&gt;release announcement published in deepin blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The deepin community has announced availability of deepin 15.5 beta for testing. This release brings various small feature additions and improvements to provide a better user experience.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/deepin%2015.5%20beta.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Fedora 27 released</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fedora-27-released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fedora 27  released" /><published>2017-11-14T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-11-14T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fedora-27-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fedora-27-released/">&lt;p&gt;The Fedora Project has announced release of Fedora 27 , latest stable release of independently developed GNU/Linux operating system project backed by Red Hat Inc. This release announcement is applicable for Fedora Workstation and Fedora atomic editions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping the tradition of Fedora releases, Fedora 27 comes with thousands of improvements from Fedora community and various upstream projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key highlight of Fedora 27 workstation is availability of GNOME 3.26 as default desktop environment. It included various improvements ranging from better display manager support, improved search results and redesigned settings application. It also includes built-in support for various emojis.  Other updates in Fedora 27 includes LibreOffice 5.4, updated image writer software,  ..etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Fedora Atomic 27 now defaults to a simpler container storage setup. Furthermore, it offers containerized Kubernetes, flannel and etcd. These changes bring flexibility for users to choose different versions of Kubernetes, or to not use Kubernetes at all. This release ships with the latest rpm-ostree, now with support for base package overrides. Cockpit is also updated to the latest version. It includes support for Cockpit Dashboard installation on Atomic Host via RPM package layering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on Fedora 27, see o&lt;a href=&quot;https://fedoramagazine.org/announcing-fedora-27/&quot;&gt;riginal release announcement published in Fedora magazine.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Fedora Project has announced release of Fedora 27 , latest stable release of independently developed GNU/Linux operating system project backed by Red Hat Inc. This release announcement is applicable for Fedora Workstation and Fedora atomic editions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ubuntu 16.04.2 LTS will be postponed till February 9, due to boot issues</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/01-ubuntu-16042-will-delayed-till-february-9-due-to-boot-issues/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ubuntu 16.04.2 LTS will be postponed till February 9, due to boot issues" /><published>2017-02-02T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-02-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/01-ubuntu-16042-will-delayed-till-february-9-due-to-boot-issues</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/01-ubuntu-16042-will-delayed-till-february-9-due-to-boot-issues/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Leann Ogasawara&lt;/em&gt; of Ubuntu engineering team has requested the release team to postpone Ubuntu 16.04.2 LTS release till February 9. This was owing to some serious booting issues found in arm64 systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is expected that, the resolution for currently detected issue will require pulling kernel leve changes and flash kernel. Eventhough this can be completed within the scheduled time, there won’t be enough time available for testing which will raise a concern over stability of the release. Considering the seriousness of issue, &lt;em&gt;Mr Adam Cornard&lt;/em&gt; from Ubuntu release engineering team has agreed to postpone the release till February 9th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/ubuntu16042-banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ubuntu 16.04.2 banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You find these mail threads in Ubuntu &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.ubuntu.com/archives/ubuntu-release/2017-January/004015.html&quot;&gt;release mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
Hi Adam (and the Release Team),
&lt;br /&gt;
We would like to formally request an extension for 16.04.2's release.  We
have just identified a serious boot regression on arm64.  The resolution
looks to require landing changes to the kernel, flash-kernel, and possibly
d-i.  While we can likely physically get those changes into the archive in
time for the release, there would be next to no time to test this nor
provide appropriate regression testing on other platforms. We would be much
more comfortable giving that some proper testing before releasing and
therefore would like to request an additional extension for the point
release date.  Thoughts?  We will honor whatever guidance we receive from
you.
&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks,
Leann
&lt;br /&gt;
----
&lt;br /&gt;
I'm a big fan of caution when it comes to the bits that make people's
computers either boot or completely fail to, as it's pretty hard to fix
boot errors after shipping them.  So, yes, a delay for a week while all
this is landed and tested seems entirely reasonable to me.  Will push
the release to Feb 9 instead.
&lt;br /&gt;
... Adam
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Mr Leann Ogasawara of Ubuntu engineering team has requested the release team to postpone Ubuntu 16.04.2 LTS release till February 9. This was owing to some serious booting issues found in arm64 systems.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/ubuntu16042-banner.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">LibreOffice 5.3 released with a tons of new features</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-libreoffice-53-released-see-what-is-new/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LibreOffice 5.3 released with a tons of new features" /><published>2017-02-02T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-02-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-libreoffice-53-released-see-what-is-new</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-libreoffice-53-released-see-what-is-new/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Document Foundation&lt;/strong&gt; has announced release of LibreOffice 5.3, latest stable release of popular
free and open source office suite. This release introduces a lot of new proffessional quality features which makes it more competing with other proprietary office suites. It will be immediately available for windows, GNU/Linux and macOS platforms and also for cloud platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LibreOffice 5.3 is a major milestone in the history projects. It introduces new features like online collaborative editing, which will increase the competency of project, also this release provides a lot of incremental improvements to make it more reliable, smooth and user friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/LibreOffice Impress - Notebookbar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;LibreOffice 5.3 with Notebookbar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major highlights in LibreOffice 5.3 can be summarized as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduces LibreOffice Online, a cloud based office suite that offers basic collaborative editing features on a web browsers. It is basically a server service and should be expected and configured by adding a cloud storage and SSL certificate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An experimental ribbon UI (MUFFIN - My User Friendly &amp;amp; Flexible INterface)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyboard shortcuts can now be displayed in context menus, and are enabled by default on Windows and Linux.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To help you work better with filled shapes, the Area dialog has been simplified and includes a new Patterns section, for better compatibility with other office software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additionally, if you want to fill a shape with a custom bitmap image, you can now import a new image directly from the sidebar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's now possible to insert PDFs into your documents as images, with the first page being shown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Furthermore, you can sign existing PDF files, and verify those signatures as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colour palette management has been simplified, and new palettes have been added for professional graphic and layout workflows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New items have been added to the Help menu, including quick links to user guides and community support forums.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Safe Mode is now available, to help you find and fix problems with your user profile or extensions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text layout has been unified for consistency across operating systems, while file format compatibility has been improved as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, LibreOffice 5.3 is the first full source code release of LibreOffice online, a browser-based version of the suite that you can run on your private cloud infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Writer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In LibreOffice 5.3, Writer has some great new features to make your documents shine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table styles are now supported, letting you apply formatting to a table which is preserved when you make edits to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new Page deck in the sidebar lets you quickly customise page settings without having to go through a separate dialog box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For faster navigation, a new Go to Page box lets you jump to another page in the document with just a few keypresses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the drawing tools, arrows that were previously only available in Draw and Impress can now be used in Writer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lastly, the toolbar includes a new Small Capitals button, and this formatting can also be applied via macros.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Calc&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LibreOffice 5.3 has many improvements in Calc, to help you work smarter with spreadsheets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new set of default cell styles are now available, with greater variety and better names than in previous releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In fresh installations, &quot;Enable wildcards in formulas&quot; is now the default option, rather than regular expressions, to improve compatibility with other spreadsheet software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you're creating pivot tables, a new median function is now available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The merge cells feature now lets you empty the contents of cells that are hidden after the merge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, when you're inserting a function, a new text entry box lets you narrow down the functions you're looking for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Impress &amp;amp; Draw&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In LibreOffice 5.3, Impress has been updated to make your presentations really stand out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you launch the software, a template selector now appears to get you off to a quick start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two new attractive templates have been included by default, whileothers have been improved as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you're inserting images from a photo album, it's now possible to link these images so that they're not saved in the document itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lastly, in slide master mode, slide properties are now available in the sidebar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details, see release announcement published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.documentfoundation.org/blog/2017/02/01/the-document-foundation-announces-feature-rich-libreoffice-5-3/&quot;&gt;document foundation blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Document Foundation has announced release of LibreOffice 5.3, latest stable release of popular free and open source office suite. This release introduces a lot of new proffessional quality features which makes it more competing with other proprietary office suites. It will be immediately available for windows, GNU/Linux and macOS platforms and also for cloud platforms.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/LibreOffice%20Impress%20-%20Notebookbar.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">KDE neon offers a near perfect desktop on a stable base</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-kde-neon-offers-perfect-desktop-on-stable-base/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KDE neon offers a near perfect desktop on a stable base" /><published>2017-02-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-02-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-kde-neon-offers-perfect-desktop-on-stable-base</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-kde-neon-offers-perfect-desktop-on-stable-base/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KDE neon&lt;/strong&gt; is an amazing GNU/Linux distribution developed by the KDE community. It integrates most up-to-date
KDE Plasma desktop and other KDE community developed applications on stable base of Ubuntu LTS (Long Term
Supported) releases. While the core remains the same (LTS release of Ubuntu), the KDE components get
contineous updates to provide most modern KDE technologies to the end users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/neon_a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Preview of KDE neon Desktop&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Courtesy : Linux.com portal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Linux.com&lt;/em&gt; portal has published a review on KDE neon project which observes that, the project a 
success for providing an almost perfect desktop environment to the end users. The review begins by 
stating that, the user interest has dramatically moved away from KDE project over the years. Plasma 3
was able to attract a lot of users owing to it’s simplcity and traditional user experience. However, Plasma 4
made the system more heavy and was not that responsive. Plasma 5 was able to overcome limitations of 
Plasma 4 by making system more responsive and resource efficient. Still it was lagging behind due to
sticking with a traditional desktop metaphor and the desktop was buggy on most of the platforms. The
KDE neon project was started to show-off how well, KDE Plasma desktop can be integrated with a GNU/Linux
distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the review, KDE neon provides a smooth Plasma experience to the end users. The project is
integrating a nice flat theme, and it is very stable and fast comparing to KDE Plasma 4. The widget management
has also becomes much easier. However, there are some rough edges like, lack of commonly used applications
like office suites and somewhat outdated packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
To recover a bit of that lost ground, the KDE developers opted to fork Ubuntu into KDE Neon. The launch of Neon didn’t quite go as planned (and the initial release wasn’t exactly stable). Since then, however, the project has managed to pull off something quite intriguing. KDE Neon takes the stability of Ubuntu 16.04 and applies a cutting-edge release of the KDE desktop to create an absolutely beautiful experience, that could easily appease those looking for the best of both worlds.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read complete review in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linux.com/learn/kde-neon-offers-near-perfect-desktop-solid-platform&quot;&gt;linux.com&lt;/a&gt; portal.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">KDE neon is an amazing GNU/Linux distribution developed by the KDE community. It integrates most up-to-date KDE Plasma desktop and other KDE community developed applications on stable base of Ubuntu LTS (Long Term Supported) releases. While the core remains the same (LTS release of Ubuntu), the KDE components get contineous updates to provide most modern KDE technologies to the end users.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/neon_a.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bodhi Linux 4.1.0 released with Linux 4.8 and Arc inspired moksha theme</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/01-bodhi-linux-410-released-with-linux-kernel-48/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bodhi Linux 4.1.0 released with Linux 4.8 and Arc inspired moksha theme" /><published>2017-01-29T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-01-29T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/01-bodhi-linux-410-released-with-linux-kernel-48</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/01-bodhi-linux-410-released-with-linux-kernel-48/">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;/distribution/bodhi&quot;&gt;Bodhi Linux&lt;/a&gt; team has announced release of Bodhi Linux 4.1.0, latest maintenance cum bug fix release in Bodhi Linux 4 branch. This release comes with several updated packages and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who are not familiar with Bodhi Linux, it is an Ubuntu LTS based GNU/Linux distribution featuring Enlightenment inspired &lt;a href=&quot;/desktop/moksha&quot;&gt;Moksha desktop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/bodhi410.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bodhi Linux 4.1.0 Preview&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Bodhi Linux 4.1.0 Preview&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newly announced Bodhi Linux 4.1.0 features updated packages like EFL 1.18.4, and updated version of Enlightenment Foundation Libraries, Linux Kernel 4.8 which comes with improved support for different graphics cards, and a new Moksha desktop theme inspired by Arc Dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The existing users of Bodhi Linux 4.x, can avail all the bug fixes by a simple system update. But they need to take manual actions for changing linux kernel and to use updated dark theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
This release serves to package up the fixes for a few bugs that slipped through the cracks in the 4.0.0 release, as well as provided updated package sets for the install ISO images. Most notably these ISO images come with EFL 1.18.4, Linux Kernel 4.8, and a new Moksha Theme based on the “Arc Dark” theme. Existing Bodhi 4.0.0 users already have the bug fixes incorporated into these ISO images, but they will need to manually install the newer kernel and theme if they wish to utilize them.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also find original &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bodhilinux.com/2017/01/27/bodhi-linux-4-1-0-released/&quot;&gt;release announcement&lt;/a&gt; and a few screenshtos in Bodhi Linux blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download Bodhi Linux 4.1.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;64bit &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.1.0/bodhi-4.1.0-64.iso/download&quot;&gt;ISO Download&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;– &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.1.0/bodhi-4.1.0-64.iso.torrent/download&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;32bit &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.1.0/bodhi-4.1.0-32.iso/download&quot;&gt;ISO Download&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.1.0/bodhi-4.1.0-32.iso.torrent/download&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Legacy &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;– &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.1.0/bodhi-4.1.0-legacy.iso/download&quot;&gt;ISO Download&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.0.0/bodhi-4.0.0-legacy.iso.torrent/download&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;64bit AppPack – &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.1.0/bodhi-4.1.0-apppack-64.iso/download&quot;&gt;ISO Download&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.1.0/bodhi-4.1.0-apppack-64.iso.torrent/download&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;32bit AppPack – &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.1.0/bodhi-4.1.0-apppack-32.iso/download&quot;&gt;ISO Download&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/4.1.0/bodhi-4.1.0-apppack-32.iso.torrent/download&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Bodhi Linux team has announced release of Bodhi Linux 4.1.0, latest maintenance cum bug fix release in Bodhi Linux 4 branch. This release comes with several updated packages and bug fixes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/bodhi410.jpg" /></entry></feed>