<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-30T21:59:56+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">OpenSourceFeed</title><subtitle>Database of various GNU/Linux, BSD and other open source distributions and different open source desktop environments with updates &amp; stories on each.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">ArchLabs Linux 2018.07 released with a brand new dark theme</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-archlabs-linux-2018.07-released-with-brand-new-dark-theme/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ArchLabs Linux 2018.07 released with a brand new dark theme" /><published>2018-07-30T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-07-30T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-archlabs-linux-2018.07-released-with-brand-new-dark-theme</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-archlabs-linux-2018.07-released-with-brand-new-dark-theme/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; ArchLabs team has announced the release of ArchLabs 2018.07. It is the latest stable release of Arch-based GNU/Linux distribution inspired by the design principles of &lt;em&gt;Bunsenlabs&lt;/em&gt;. The main focus of this release on stability improvement, performance and usability improvements and other optimizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/ArchLabs_2018-02-07-18_1920x1080.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of ArchLabs 2018.07&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A preview of ArchLabs Linux 2018.07&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the visible change with ArchLabs is the introduction of a brand new dark theme which works well the default light icon theme shipped with ArchLabs. Last week, ArchLabs team had shared some updates on with a discussion thread on ArchLabs forums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other main highlights in ArchLabs Linux 2018.07 includes,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The ArchLabs installer finally has it’s own name, presenting, AL-Installer.  Originally forked from ABIF, it has been completely re-written for use with ArchLabs and only vaguely resembles the original product.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A lot of changes have been made to keep your install simple.  Sorting of mirrors has been added as well as a page to create your user.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A brand new default theme, ArchLabs-dARK.  This works nicely with the current icon theme, ArchLabs-Light.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;New default wallpaper.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Aurman has replaced Yaourt as our AUR helper.  This helper works nicely with Pacman.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Neofetch has been replaced quite some time ago with our lightweight homemade info script, AL-Info.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;With the help from Oddproton and Karl Schneider, we have our very own dynamic wallpaper script (à la MacOS Mojave/Gnome) called Dynpaper.  With custom walls created by the ever talented Karl.  Dynpaper isn’t installed or enabled by default.  If you’d like to get this up and running on your system, check out our thread at the forum.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Polybar has been updated to the latest version and has undergone a tidy up.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Vim and Ranger’s configs have been added and updated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the original &lt;a href=&quot;https://archlabslinux.com/2018/07/29/archlabs-linux-2018-07/&quot;&gt;ArchLabs 2018.07 release announcement&lt;/a&gt; in projects website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The ArchLabs team has announced the release of ArchLabs 2018.07. It is the latest stable release of Arch-based GNU/Linux distribution inspired by the design principles of Bunsenlabs. The main focus of this release on stability improvement, performance and usability improvements and other optimizations.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/ArchLabs_2018-02-07-18_1920x1080.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Neptune 5.4 released with a fresh look and feel</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/neptune-5.4-released-with-better-dark-theme-and-icon-theme/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Neptune 5.4 released with a fresh look and feel" /><published>2018-07-24T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-07-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/neptune-5.4-released-with-better-dark-theme-and-icon-theme</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/neptune-5.4-released-with-better-dark-theme-and-icon-theme/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Leszek&lt;/em&gt; of the Neptune project has announced the release of Neptune 5.4. It is the latest updated snapshot in Neptune 5.x series. It brings a set of updated packages and applications and avoids the need for the bulk package update after installing the operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to package updates and critical bug fixes, Neptune 5.4 brings a fresh look and feel with an improved dark theme.  This dark theme also includes a modified version of &lt;em&gt;Faenza&lt;/em&gt; icon theme. Neptune 5.4 also brings Linux Kernel 5.16.x. It ensures better hardware support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/preview/neptune5.0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A file picture of Neptune 5.0&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A file picture of Neptune 5.0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other highlights from Neptune 5.4 include,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;the update of KDE Frameworks to version 5.48  and KDE Applications to version 18.04.3. As the new KF5 version is not compatible with Qt 5.7 anymore we had to backport its patches to version 5.45.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;VLC has been updated to 3.0.3 to provide more speed and lots of bugfixes.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thunderbird 52.9 fixes issues with encrypted HTML e-mails. The Excalibur menu is now available in version 2.7 which provides some bugfixes in regards to multiple activities and moving favorites around.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;KWin the default window manager for Plasma got an update to version 5.12.5.  This offers some nice speed improvements as well as some updated effects and better hardware support.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;LibreOffice is now available in version 6.0.6. We fixed an issue with MTP causing issues to share files with Android devices.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Enlightenment 22 is now available in Version 0.22.3 together with Terminology 1.2.1.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find further information in &lt;a href=&quot;https://neptuneos.com/en/news-reader/neptune-5-4-159.html&quot;&gt;Neptune 5.4 release announcement&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://neptuneos.com/en/changelog.html&quot;&gt;Neptune 5.4 changelogs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Mr. Leszek of the Neptune project has announced the release of Neptune 5.4. It is the latest updated snapshot in Neptune 5.x series. It brings a set of updated packages and applications and avoids the need for the bulk package update after installing the operating system.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/preview/neptune5.0.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Peppermint OS 9 is a good for some, not for all distribution</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/01-peppermint-os-9-is-good-for-some-not-for-all/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Peppermint OS 9 is a good for some, not for all distribution" /><published>2018-07-24T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-07-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/01-peppermint-os-9-is-good-for-some-not-for-all</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/01-peppermint-os-9-is-good-for-some-not-for-all/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peppermint OS&lt;/strong&gt; a &lt;em&gt;hybrid&lt;/em&gt; operating system that integrates many web-based applications. It is built on top of Ubuntu and uses a blend of LXDE and Xfce with some components from other environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peppermint OS 9 is a stable release based on Ubuntu 18.04 LTS. Like it’s predecessors, Peppermint 9 also focuses on improving the overall user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest issue of &lt;em&gt;DistroWatch Weekly&lt;/em&gt; features a review on Peppermint OS 9. The review categorizes this distribution as a &lt;em&gt;good for some, not for all&lt;/em&gt; distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The review praises the distribution for its ability to consume only 350 - 400 MB of memory on idle state. Peppermint is able to limit its memory usage while using usable components from multiple desktop environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/peppermint-9-settings.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of Peppermint OS 9 settings panel&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A preview of Peppermint OS 9 settings panel (Courtesy : DistroWatch)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;em&gt;Ice&lt;/em&gt; tool, users can create stand-alone web application launchers and keep it on the application menu. This is the most important specialty of Peppermint OS. While most of the applications in Peppermint OS 9 are stand-alone web application launcher, it also supports installing desktop applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DistroWatch review finds Peppermint OS 9 as an ideal choice for people who uses web-based applications extensively. For others, there can be better alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;While I have to admit that I am not the target audience for a distribution focused on web-based applications, I found Peppermint 9 to be a solid distribution. Despite pulling components from multiple desktop environments, Peppermint 9’s desktop is well integrated and easy to use. It was also easy to add both web-based and traditional applications to the system, so the distribution can be adjusted for users who prefer either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Peppermint 9 is not for everyone, but users who do most of their work in Google Docs or Microsoft Office Online should give Peppermint a try. However, users accustomed to using traditional desktop applications might want to stick to one of the many alternatives out there. Yes, Peppermint 9 can be easily adjusted to use traditional desktop applications, but many of the other distribution options out there come with those kinds of applications pre-installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original &lt;a href=&quot;https://distrowatch.com/weekly.php?issue=20180723#peppermint&quot;&gt;Peppermint OS 9 review&lt;/a&gt; can be read on DistroWatch weekly.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Peppermint OS a hybrid operating system that integrates many web-based applications. It is built on top of Ubuntu and uses a blend of LXDE and Xfce with some components from other environments.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/peppermint-9-settings.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">ReactOS 0.4.9 released with stability &amp;amp; usability improvements</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reactos-4.9-released-with-stability-and-usability-improvements/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ReactOS 0.4.9 released with stability &amp; usability improvements" /><published>2018-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reactos-4.9-released-with-stability-and-usability-improvements</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reactos-4.9-released-with-stability-and-usability-improvements/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr.&lt;/strong&gt; Colin Finck on behalf of ReactOS project has announced the release of ReactOS 0.4.9. It is the latest stable release in ReactOS tri-monthly release series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ReactOS tri-monthly release series has reduced the number of changes in each cycle. Rather, it provides improved workflow and ensures the work is moving in the right way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/reactos-banner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ReactOS banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-reactos&quot;&gt;What is ReactOS?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ReactOS is an independently developed, windows binary compatible operating system. It provides a traditional user experience to make users more productive while moving from other platforms. Despite the default look and feel resembling Windows 9.x releases, ReactOS supports most of the modern windows applications. The project also reuses some components from open source project’s like Wine to avoid reinventing the wheel from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-new-in-reactos-049&quot;&gt;What is new in ReactOS 0.4.9?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main highlights of ReactOS 0.4.9 include improved stability and usability improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ReactOS 0.4.9 is a self-hosting operating system. It means, the ReactOS code can be compiled on ReactOS itself. It is a big deal, due to the complexity involved in handling memory and IO cycles. In past, ReactOS used to be a self-hosting operating system. This capability was lost while migrating the Kernel to be compatible with NT components.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A major source of system instability came from the complex interplay between the memory manager, the common cache, the hardware abstraction layer (HAL), and the FastFAT driver. The biggest culprit in the instability came from the significant resource leakages caused by the FastFAT driver, resulting in it eating up the common cache to the point where attempts to copy large files would result in a crash. Multiple stability related issues have been rectified in ReactOS 0.4.9.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ability to handle zip files natively. Now, you can handle zip files in ReactOS without installing any 3rd party applications.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ability to choose between copy, cut and create link while dragging files from one location to another.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;There are of course plenty of other changes in less trodden parts of ReactOS, with many people providing contributions and improvements. These range from the functional, like zooming no longer crashing in the Paint application thanks to Stanislav Motylkov, to more behind the scenes like Timo Kreuzer’s continued efforts to prepare the codebase to actually function when building an x64 target (the project owes Timo many bottles of beer for taking on that one).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;And other improvements…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a complete list of changes and screenshots, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactos.org/project-news/reactos-049-released&quot;&gt;ReactOS 0.4.9 release announcement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Mr. Colin Finck on behalf of ReactOS project has announced the release of ReactOS 0.4.9. It is the latest stable release in ReactOS tri-monthly release series.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/reactos-banner.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">ArchLabs opts for a new default dark theme</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/arch-labs-introduces-a-new-icon-theme/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ArchLabs opts for a new default dark theme" /><published>2018-07-22T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-07-22T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/arch-labs-introduces-a-new-icon-theme</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/arch-labs-introduces-a-new-icon-theme/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; ArchLabs team has announced the availability of a new default theme for testing. This will be the default theme in upcoming ArchLabs releases. Currently, the team is focusing on the window manager theme. The team is yet to finalize the icon theme. Two possible candidates for icon theme are existing ArchLabs-light theme and Suru++ Aspromauros icon theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/archlabs-light-theme.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of ArchLabs-dark-theme&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A preview of ArchLabs Dark theme&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new theme is available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/Dobbie03/ArchLabs-dARK&quot;&gt;ArchLabs-dark theme repository hosted on Gitlab&lt;/a&gt;. It will be made available on ArchLabs testing repositories in a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main highlights of the ArchLabs-light theme include,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Added Geany color scheme. This is in the .config file. Named ArchLabs-dARK.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jgmenu added and updated.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;st color theme added.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Alternative window buttons added. The final choice will be decided by the poll included.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Polybar updated to a new scheme. You will need to change in the config file the path to master and modules with your username.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Custom Firefox CSS included. Read changelog on how to use.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Options on a new theme for the mouse cursor.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Unfocused window decoration change as per @m00n.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dunst updated and included.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Alternative window decoration colors to replace the OSX traffic lights New Default Theme Available for Testing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.archlabslinux.com/t/new-default-theme-available-for-testing/1321&quot;&gt;updates on ArchLabs-dark theme on ArchLabs forums&lt;/a&gt;. In case you are testing this theme, you can also leave feedback on ArchLabs forums.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The ArchLabs team has announced the availability of a new default theme for testing. This will be the default theme in upcoming ArchLabs releases. Currently, the team is focusing on the window manager theme. The team is yet to finalize the icon theme. Two possible candidates for icon theme are existing ArchLabs-light theme and Suru++ Aspromauros icon theme.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/archlabs-light-theme.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Arya Linux 1.0 Xfce spin beta released</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/arya-linux-1.0-xfce-beta-released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Arya Linux 1.0 Xfce spin beta released" /><published>2018-07-19T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-07-19T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/arya-linux-1.0-xfce-beta-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/arya-linux-1.0-xfce-beta-released/">&lt;p&gt;The Arya Linux team has announced the release of Arya Linux 1.0 Xfce spin beta. It is the latest development release of from scratch GNU/Linux distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Arya Linux 1.0 Xfce code-named Aryana brings a fresh look and feel with Adapta Nokto GTK theme and Flat Remix Icon theme. This release features &lt;em&gt;Parole&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Exaile&lt;/em&gt; as default video and audio players. With this release, Midori browser is replaced with chromium owing to the self-certification issue in the former.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/arya-linux-xfce.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of Arya Linux 1.0 Xfce spin&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Arya Linux 1.0 Xfce spin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
Just released the beta version of AryaLinux 1.0 XFCE Spin. The UI is refreshed (Adapta Nokto GTK theme and Flat Remix Icon theme). The default audio and video applications are exaile and parole respectively. LibreOffice works out of the box and is the default Office suite and Chromium is the default browser. We chose Chromium over Midori(even thought Midori was our first choice) because of the self-signed certificate issue of Midori. We are currently working on it. Apart from that rest of the application stack is similar to the Gnome release. We also rebuilt the kernel to fix some startup issues associated with some models of HP laptops.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read the &lt;a href=&quot;http://aryalinux.org/&quot;&gt;Arya Linux 1.0 Xfce beta release announcement&lt;/a&gt; in projects official website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;download-arya-linux-10-xfce-spin&quot;&gt;Download Arya Linux 1.0 Xfce spin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/aryalinux/files/releases/1.0/aryalinux-xfce-1.0-x86_64.iso&quot;&gt;Arya Linux 1.0 Xfce 64 bit ISO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aryalinux.org/files/1.0/aryalinux-xfce-1.0-x86_64.iso.torrent&quot;&gt;Arya Linux 1.0 Xfce 64 bit torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Arya Linux team has announced the release of Arya Linux 1.0 Xfce spin beta. It is the latest development release of from scratch GNU/Linux distribution.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/arya-linux-xfce.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Managing multi-cloud services using Juju</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/managing-a-multi-cloud-platform-using-juju/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Managing multi-cloud services using Juju" /><published>2018-07-18T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-07-18T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/managing-a-multi-cloud-platform-using-juju</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/managing-a-multi-cloud-platform-using-juju/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deploying&lt;/strong&gt; an application to a single cloud platform is not a very difficult task. But, it can be very challenging when we are dealing with multiple public clouds. It becomes quite difficult to handle the scalability and to troubleshoot deployment issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There should be some kind of robust automation for managing applications on multi-cloud platforms. This automation mechanism should be highly flexible. It should permit to do a one-time configuration and allow to deploy applications on any platform. Let it be a bare metal or a cloud container.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/mojo-brand-gray.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ubuntu Mirror service management using Juju&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ubuntu Mirror service management using Juju&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Ubuntu blog&lt;/em&gt; has shared an article on managing multi-cloud platform using &lt;em&gt;Juju&lt;/em&gt;.  Juju is a cloud deployment automation tool. It is responsible for talking to the cloud APIs, installation and configuration of each application, provisioning cloud services, such as security, networking, storage, and user access control. It enables scalable and efficient deployment of applications on different cloud platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article published on Ubuntu blog explains the scenario on which &lt;em&gt;Juju&lt;/em&gt; was used for multi-cloud deployment. It is used to deploy Ubuntu Archive Mirror services to serve a large number of requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
All our Archive Mirror deployments are centrally managed. We have a deployment host from which all SREs connect to environments we manage. An internally developed tool allows SREs to search for the environment they need to connect to (such as “Azure Archive Mirror for Japan East region”), and then configures for them everything they need to connect to that environment in a consistent way.

The Ubuntu Archive Mirror service itself is modeled as a Mojo specification. Mojo is a system of configuration and tools for verifying the success of Juju environment deployments. It allows us to define what an Archive Mirror is in a revision-controlled configuration repository, and a means of validating whether what we deployed is as we intended.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the complete article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ubuntu.com/2018/07/17/how-to-manage-multi-cloud-services-with-juju&quot;&gt;multi-cloud management using Juju&lt;/a&gt; on Ubuntu blog.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Deploying an application to a single cloud platform is not a very difficult task. But, it can be very challenging when we are dealing with multiple public clouds. It becomes quite difficult to handle the scalability and to troubleshoot deployment issues.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/mojo-brand-gray.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">MX Linux 17.1 stands out because of simplicity</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mx-linux-17.1-is-a-success-in-delivering-a-simple-os/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MX Linux 17.1 stands out because of simplicity" /><published>2018-04-08T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-04-08T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mx-linux-17.1-is-a-success-in-delivering-a-simple-os</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mx-linux-17.1-is-a-success-in-delivering-a-simple-os/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MX Linux 17.1&lt;/strong&gt; is a stable release of Debian based GNU/Linux distribution featuring Xfce desktop environment. The main purpose of this distribution is to provide a simple user experience to all kind of users, say from absolute beginners to experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/mx-171-preview.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of MX Linux 17.0 - Courtesy distroscreens&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr &lt;em&gt;Jack Wallen&lt;/em&gt; has written a review on MX Linux 17.1 and it is published on &lt;em&gt;linux.com&lt;/em&gt; portal. At the very beginning of this review, &lt;em&gt;Jack&lt;/em&gt; was wondering what is the need for another distribution when there are hundreds of distributions which are getting actively developed. He was also curious to see what can we expect from a blend of antiX and MEPIS when they stand out in their own ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of the review, the impression changes gradually, and he reaches in a conclusion that, though MX Linux 17.1 is not among the most elegant distributions, it delivers what it promises, ie, simplicity. Quoting from his own concluding words,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;MX Linux makes transitioning from just about any desktop operating system simple. Although some might find the desktop interface to be a bit less-than-modern, the distribution’s primary focus isn’t on beauty, but simplicity. To that end, MX Linux succeeds in stellar fashion. This flavor of Linux can make anyone feel right at home on Linux. Spin up this mid-weight distribution and see if it can’t serve as your daily driver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linux.com/learn/intro-to-linux/2018/4/mx-linux-mid-weight-distro-focused-simplicity&quot;&gt;complete review on MX Linux 17.1&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;linux.com&lt;/em&gt; portal.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">MX Linux 17.1 is a stable release of Debian based GNU/Linux distribution featuring Xfce desktop environment. The main purpose of this distribution is to provide a simple user experience to all kind of users, say from absolute beginners to experts.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/mx-171-preview.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ubuntu 18.04 final beta images are availabe now</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-ubuntu-18.04-final-beta-images-are-available-now/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ubuntu 18.04 final beta images are availabe now" /><published>2018-04-08T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-04-08T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-ubuntu-18.04-final-beta-images-are-available-now</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-ubuntu-18.04-final-beta-images-are-available-now/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Steve Langasek&lt;/em&gt; on behalf of Ubuntu team has announced the availability of Ubuntu 18.04 final beta images. This the second beta image release in this series and gives a near complete idea of features that can be expected from the final releases scheduled for 26th April 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the project’s release strategy, Ubuntu 18.04 will be a long term supported release and will provide support for 5 years. Taking the tradition of Ubuntu releases, Ubuntu 18.04 will also bring the latest and greatest open source technologies ready to deploy in enterprise environments. The team is working towards introducing new features and fixing critical bugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/ubuntu1804b2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ubuntu 18.04 beta2 banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;release-announcement-from-ubuntu&quot;&gt;Release announcement from Ubuntu&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The release announcement shared by &lt;em&gt;Steve Langasek&lt;/em&gt;, an Ubuntu developer, in official mailing list can be read as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Ubuntu team is pleased to announce the final beta release of the Ubuntu 18.04 LTS Desktop, Server, and Cloud products. Codenamed “Bionic Beaver”, 18.04 LTS continues Ubuntu’s proud tradition of integrating the latest and greatest open source technologies into a high-quality, easy-to-use Linux distribution.  The team has been hard at work through this cycle, introducing new features and fixing bugs.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This beta release includes images from not only the Ubuntu Desktop, Server, and Cloud products, but also the Kubuntu, Lubuntu, Ubuntu Budgie, UbuntuKylin, Ubuntu MATE, Ubuntu Studio, and Xubuntu flavours.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The beta images are known to be reasonably free of showstopper CD build or installer bugs, while representing a very recent snapshot of 18.04 that should be representative of the features intended to ship with the final release expected on April 26th, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;applicability--availability&quot;&gt;Applicability &amp;amp; Availability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final beta release announcement of Ubuntu 18.04 covers various flavors like Ubuntu Desktop, Server, Cloud products and also other official community flavors including Ubuntu Budgie, Kubuntu, Ubuntu MATE, Xubuntu, Lubuntu, Ubuntu Kylin and Ubuntu Studio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These release images can be downloaded from following sources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdimage.ubuntu.com/releases/18.04/beta-2/&quot;&gt;Download Ubuntu 18.04 beta 2 images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdimage.ubuntu.com/kubuntu/releases/18.04/beta-2/&quot;&gt;Download Kubuntu 18.04 beta 2 images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdimage.ubuntu.com/lubuntu/releases/18.04/beta-2/&quot;&gt;Download Lubuntu 18.04 beta 2 images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdimage.ubuntu.com/ubuntu-budgie/releases/18.04/beta-2/&quot;&gt;Download Ubuntu Budgie 18.04 beta 2 images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For more links, see original &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.ubuntu.com/archives/ubuntu-announce/2018-April/000230.html&quot;&gt;release announcement&lt;/a&gt; published in Ubuntu mailing list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Mr Steve Langasek on behalf of Ubuntu team has announced the availability of Ubuntu 18.04 final beta images. This the second beta image release in this series and gives a near complete idea of features that can be expected from the final releases scheduled for 26th April 2018.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/ubuntu1804b2.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Fedora 28 beta released with initial support for modular repositories</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fedora-28-beta-released-with-initial-support-for-module-repositories/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fedora 28 beta released with initial support for modular repositories" /><published>2018-04-03T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-04-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fedora-28-beta-released-with-initial-support-for-module-repositories</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fedora-28-beta-released-with-initial-support-for-module-repositories/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Eduard Lucena&lt;/em&gt;, on behalf of Fedora Project, has announced the release of Fedora 28 beta, a development release of upcoming Fedora 28 which is scheduled to release in May 2018. This release will give a brief idea of features expected in the upcoming release and will enable beta testing around the world. Fedora 28 includes several package updates and design changes including the introduction of modular repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/fedora-28-beta.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fedora 28 beta banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-new-in-fedora-28&quot;&gt;What is new in Fedora 28?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been around 6 months since the release of Fedora 27. Fedora 28 includes all updated packages since the release of Fedora 27. Other notable highlights in Fedora 28 beta release includes -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modular Repository&lt;/strong&gt; - The idea of the modular repository was around for a while. Fedora 28 brings initial support for modular repositories. Fedora 28 beta server edition will be getting a few modular repositories immediately. The support for other variations will be implemented in near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On end-user perspective, there will be two set of repositories. One will be traditional fedora repositories. The other set of repositories will provide alternative and supplementary modules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;64-bit ARM is now a primary architecture&lt;/strong&gt; - In addition to the existing &lt;em&gt;AAarch64&lt;/em&gt;, the 64-bit ARM also becomes a primary architecture of Fedora server edition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GNOME 3.28&lt;/strong&gt; - Fedora 28 Workstation beta improves the desktop experience with GNOME 3.28, which comes with plenty of features and improvements. It will also include the power saving features enabled by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VirtualBox Guest Additions&lt;/strong&gt; - Fedora 28 installation images will include VirtualBox guest additions to provide better performance in virtualization environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kubernetes 1.9&lt;/strong&gt; - Fedora Atomic Host includes Kubernetes 1.9, which includes several features to deploy and manage your containerized applications in a modular way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;download-fedora-28-beta&quot;&gt;Download Fedora 28 beta&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fedora 28 beta release is available in different variations and can be downloaded by following links given below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://download.fedoraproject.org/pub/fedora/linux/releases/test/28_Beta/Workstation/x86_64/iso/Fedora-Workstation-Live-x86_64-28_Beta-1.3.iso&quot;&gt;Download Fedora 28 beta workstation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://download.fedoraproject.org/pub/fedora/linux/releases/test/28_Beta/Server/x86_64/iso/Fedora-Server-dvd-x86_64-28_Beta-1.3.iso&quot;&gt;Download Fedora 28 beta server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://getfedora.org/atomic/prerelease/&quot;&gt;Download Fedora 28 beta atomic host&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to these variations, there is official community spins with different desktop environments and targeting a different audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://spins.fedoraproject.org/prerelease&quot;&gt;Download Fedora 28 beta spins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://labs.fedoraproject.org/prerelease&quot;&gt;Download Fedora 28 beta labs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arm.fedoraproject.org/prerelease&quot;&gt;Download Fedora 28 beta ARM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fedoramagazine.org/announcing-fedora-28-beta/&quot;&gt;Fedora 28 beta release announcement on Fedora Magazine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://communityblog.fedoraproject.org/modularity-dead-long-live-modularity/&quot;&gt;Modularity is dead, long live modularity - Article on modularity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Mr Eduard Lucena, on behalf of Fedora Project, has announced the release of Fedora 28 beta, a development release of upcoming Fedora 28 which is scheduled to release in May 2018. This release will give a brief idea of features expected in the upcoming release and will enable beta testing around the world. Fedora 28 includes several package updates and design changes including the introduction of modular repositories.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/fedora-28-beta.jpg" /></entry></feed>