<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-02-28T23:52:19+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">OpenSourceFeed</title><subtitle>Database of various GNU/Linux, BSD and other open source distributions and different open source desktop environments with updates &amp; stories on each.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">SolydXK 201801 released with Meltodown vulnerability fix, SolydXK System Settings ..etc</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/solydxk-201811-released-with-meltodown-vulnerability-fix-solydxk-system-settings-etc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SolydXK 201801 released with Meltodown vulnerability fix, SolydXK System Settings ..etc" /><published>2018-01-17T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-17T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/solydxk-201811-released-with-meltodown-vulnerability-fix-solydxk-system-settings-etc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/solydxk-201811-released-with-meltodown-vulnerability-fix-solydxk-system-settings-etc/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; SolydXK team has announced availability of SolydXK 201801, an updated snapshot for Debian based GNU/Linux distribution. This snapshot includes various updates from base distribution, latest Linux Kernel with &lt;em&gt;Meltdown&lt;/em&gt; vulnerability patch, and a centralized Control Center called &lt;em&gt;SolydXK System Settings&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/solydxk-home-banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;SolydXK banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After installation, SolydXK provides a Welcome App from which users can choose additional packages to install. This LetoDMS (Document Management System) has been removed from Welcome Application as it is not working well with SolydXK. It is also removed from project repositories. The SolydXK team suggests to use SeedDMS instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though, SolydXK is basically a Dutch operating system, it provides international community as well. The project maintainer has decided to maintain an official German image to accomodate German users. Community editions like 32 bit image and Enthusiast’s editions (based on Debian Buster) will be made available in near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other highlights from SolydXK 201801 release includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Device Driver Manager (DDM) has been integrated.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Debian Plymouth Manager has been integrated.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Add new partitions to Fstab.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Safely remove old kernel packages.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, see original release announcement published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://solydxk.com/new-solydxk-isos-released/&quot;&gt;SolydXK website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The SolydXK team has announced availability of SolydXK 201801, an updated snapshot for Debian based GNU/Linux distribution. This snapshot includes various updates from base distribution, latest Linux Kernel with Meltdown vulnerability patch, and a centralized Control Center called SolydXK System Settings.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/solydxk-home-banner.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lubuntu 17.10.1 released with fix for BIOS issue on lenovo laptops</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lubuntu-17101-released-with-fix-for-bios-issue-on-lenovo-laptops/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lubuntu 17.10.1 released with fix for BIOS issue on lenovo laptops" /><published>2018-01-12T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-12T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lubuntu-17101-released-with-fix-for-bios-issue-on-lenovo-laptops</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lubuntu-17101-released-with-fix-for-bios-issue-on-lenovo-laptops/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bringing&lt;/strong&gt; an end to the long standing uncertainty, Lubuntu team has published an updated Lubuntu 17.10 ISO which fixes BIOS issue reported in various Lenovo laptops. This issue was a hot discussion topic in Linux communities for past few days and it has raised a serious question on the credibility of Ubuntu and it’s derivatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/lubuntu17101.png&quot; alt=&quot;Lubuntu 17.10.1 banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An update for Kernel in (L)Ubuntu 17.10 with Intel SPI drivers enabled was causing the issue with Lenovo BIOS. It affects the persistence of BIOS changes, USB boot and modifiability of EFI entries. You can learn more about this issue in &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/linux/+bug/1734147&quot;&gt;launchpad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Lubuntu 17.10.1 has been released to fix a major problem affecting many Lenovo laptops that causes the computer to have BIOS problems after installing. .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Please note that the Meltdown and Spectre vulnerabilities have not been fixed in this ISO, so we advise that if you install this ISO, update directly after.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This release is no different in terms of features from the 17.10 release and is comparable to an LTS point release in that all updates since the 17.10 release have been rolled into this ISO.
The original &lt;a href=&quot;http://lubuntu.me/lubuntu-artful-atque-vale-released/&quot;&gt;release announcement of Lubuntu 17.10.1&lt;/a&gt; is available on project’s website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Bringing an end to the long standing uncertainty, Lubuntu team has published an updated Lubuntu 17.10 ISO which fixes BIOS issue reported in various Lenovo laptops. This issue was a hot discussion topic in Linux communities for past few days and it has raised a serious question on the credibility of Ubuntu and it’s derivatives.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/lubuntu17101.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ubuntu Budgie team member Jacob creates Budgie Applet to manage USB devices</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ubuntu-budgie-team-member-jacob-creates-budgie-applet-to-manage-usb-devices/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ubuntu Budgie team member Jacob creates Budgie Applet to manage USB devices" /><published>2018-01-10T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-10T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ubuntu-budgie-team-member-jacob-creates-budgie-applet-to-manage-usb-devices</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ubuntu-budgie-team-member-jacob-creates-budgie-applet-to-manage-usb-devices/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today&lt;/strong&gt; Ubuntu Budgie team has announced the immediate availability of a new budgie applet for managing USB storage devices. This applet is named as &lt;em&gt;DropBy&lt;/em&gt; and is a part of &lt;em&gt;budgie-extras&lt;/em&gt; applet collection developed by Ubuntu Budgie team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/dropby.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;First preview of DropBy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;DropBy&lt;/em&gt; applet will pop-up when a USB storage devices are connected to the system. It provides various options to manage connected devices, which includes the ability to mount/unmount devices, copy contents, open devices using default file manager ..etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DropBy&lt;/em&gt; is expected to find it’s first release with a few more polishing activities. Once it’s ready, it will be made available through Ubuntu Budgie 17.10 backport repositories. It can also be installed using &lt;em&gt;Budgie Welcome&lt;/em&gt;, a multipurpose app created by Ubuntu Budgie team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Jacob joined Ubuntu Budgie team, a few months back. Since then, he was working on &lt;em&gt;budgie-extras&lt;/em&gt;, a handy collection of budgie applets to serve various purposes. So far, it includes applets like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Window Previews&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hotcorners&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quicknote&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Workspace Switcher Overview&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wallpaper Switcher&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Workspace Mover&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ShowTime&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CountDown&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automatic Keyboard Layout Switcher&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Screen Rotation Lock&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ClockWorks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and now DropBy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Citing from original text shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/UbuntuBudgie/posts/529310910785686&quot;&gt;Ubuntu Budgie in their facebook page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Team member Jacob has been busy again - another optional applet you may wish to use called “DropBy”. This one automatically pops up whenever a USB device is added. You can mount/unmount, copy the USB device contents and open in Files all from the popup.
Nice! Well done Jacob 😁&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Will be polishing in the next few days and will release to the 17.10 backports PPA and you can use budgie-welcome to install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Today Ubuntu Budgie team has announced the immediate availability of a new budgie applet for managing USB storage devices. This applet is named as DropBy and is a part of budgie-extras applet collection developed by Ubuntu Budgie team.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/dropby.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">feren OS launches a new snapshot to welcome 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/feren-os-launches-a-new-snapshot-to-welcome-2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="feren OS launches a new snapshot to welcome 2018" /><published>2018-01-02T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feren-os-launches-a-new-snapshot-to-welcome-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/feren-os-launches-a-new-snapshot-to-welcome-2018/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; feren OS team has kick started their activities in 2018 by launching an updated snapshot. This snapshot brings various updated packages, bug fixes and enhancements over the previous release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feren OS 2018.1 (Let me call it in that way) provides a smooth update path from previous release via update manager. A clear update path between releases is one among the objectives of ferenOS!.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/ferenOS18.1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Update Software Manager in feren OS 2018.1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Citing from release announcement, following are some of the notable highlights of feren OS 2018.1 comparing to its predecessor released in October 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A new set of wallpapers called &lt;em&gt;Unsplash Wallpaper Set&lt;/em&gt;. This includes several refreshing wallpapers. In addition to wallpapers provided in the default installation, you may also install &lt;em&gt;feren-extra-background&lt;/em&gt; package to get more.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;feren OS 2018.1 release is based on Linux Mint 18.3. So, it brings various package updates from base distribution. Software Manager (Mint) is one of the key highlights. It provides a modern UI to manage applications easily. It also provides support for Flatpak. In feren OS 2018.1, GNOME Software is replaced with Mint Software Manager.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Custom themer theme - feren OS 2018.1 will let you create and install your own custom theme. You can explore &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/feren/Themer-Store&quot;&gt;project’s repository&lt;/a&gt; to get started with creating your custom theme.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The themer tool is now integrated with Theme App, which is available in control center. This will help you to choose between various themes and layouts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on feren OS 2018.1 and future plans, you may refer &lt;a href=&quot;https://ferenos.weebly.com/blog/2018-kicking-off-with-yet-another-new-snapshot-changes&quot;&gt;official release announcement&lt;/a&gt; published in projects’ website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The feren OS team has kick started their activities in 2018 by launching an updated snapshot. This snapshot brings various updated packages, bug fixes and enhancements over the previous release.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/ferenOS18.1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Uruk 2.0 Xfce edition is available now</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/uruk-20-xfce-edition-is-available-now/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Uruk 2.0 Xfce edition is available now" /><published>2018-01-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/uruk-20-xfce-edition-is-available-now</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/uruk-20-xfce-edition-is-available-now/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Uruk GNU/Linux has gained a lot of popularity with its 1.0 release. Now, after Uruk 2.0 release, it is time to work on diversity. As a beginning of diversification effort, Mr &lt;em&gt;Hayder Ctee&lt;/em&gt; on behalf of Uruk team has announced the availability of Uruk 2.0 Xfce edition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/uruk-software-center.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of Uruk Software Center in Uruk 2.0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release brings a 100% libre operating system with Xfce desktop tweaked with Uruk look &amp;amp; feel. It also includes various Uruk tools like Uruk Cleaner, Uruk Package Manager Simulator (UPMS), ..etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following are some of the key highlights of Uruk 2.0 Xfce release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Xfce 4.12 as window manager with Uruk 2.0 Customization&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Some default xfce4 apps like (mousepad, thunar file manager, xfburn ….)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Some Uruk project apps like Uruk cleaner, RoseCrypt and AIA&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Upms (Uruk package manager simulator)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;UCC (Uruk control center)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Software center with Synaptic Package Manager&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Some Extra apps like (ffmulticonverter, deluge, vlc, engrampa archive manager, Abrowser, Libreoffice5, Rhythmbox, …. )&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Lightdm as a display manager&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.urukproject.org/en/index.php/welcome/20-xfce&quot;&gt;Uruk 2.0 Xfce edition official release announcement&lt;/a&gt; in projects blog, and download installation image &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/urukos/files/2.0/xfce/uruk_2.0-xfce-amd64.iso/download&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Uruk GNU/Linux has gained a lot of popularity with its 1.0 release. Now, after Uruk 2.0 release, it is time to work on diversity. As a beginning of diversification effort, Mr Hayder Ctee on behalf of Uruk team has announced the availability of Uruk 2.0 Xfce edition.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/uruk-software-center.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Siduction 2018.1.0 released, based on Debian unstable</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/siduction-201810-released-based-on-debian-unstable/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Siduction 2018.1.0 released, based on Debian unstable" /><published>2018-01-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/siduction-201810-released-based-on-debian-unstable</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/siduction-201810-released-based-on-debian-unstable/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Siduction community has released Siduction 2018.1.0, the first release of Debian unstable based GNU/Linux distribution in 2018. This release is built on top of Debian unstable snapshot from 29th December 2017 with some enhancements like a brand new installer, various useful scripts &amp;amp; packages, and a patched Linux Kernel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/siduction201810.png&quot; alt=&quot;Siduction 2018.1.0 banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidcution 2018.1.0 comes in various flavors. The desktop flavors include KDE, LXQt, GNOME, Cinnamon, MATE, XFCE, LXDE, Xorg, and noX. Currently, GNOME, MATE &amp;amp; LXDE flavors and largely unmaintained. Depending on the availability of volunteers, these flavors may be discontinued in future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting from &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.siduction.org/2017/12/release-notes-for-siduction-2018-1-0/&quot;&gt;original release announcement for Siduction 2018.1.0&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;KDE Plasma stands at version 5.10.5, while GNOME comes in at 3.26 with
some packages still at 3.24. LXQt ships at 0.12.0 and Xfce at 4.12.4, while
Cinnamon comes in at 3.4.6 and MATE at 1.18.3. Sadly, right now, GNOME,
MATE and LXDE are largely unmaintained. If no one steps up to keep them in a releasable state, we might have to drop these flavors with our next release. The corresponding packages will stay in the archives.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This release comes with the name “patience 2018.1.0”. How we deal with
this in the future is unclear. The next release, which might be there in March, in advance of CLT 2018, will ship whatever we come up with. Maybe it’ll be just numbered…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Siduction community has released Siduction 2018.1.0, the first release of Debian unstable based GNU/Linux distribution in 2018. This release is built on top of Debian unstable snapshot from 29th December 2017 with some enhancements like a brand new installer, various useful scripts &amp;amp; packages, and a patched Linux Kernel.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/siduction201810.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Calculate Linux 17.12 released with support for RAID</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/calculate-linux-1712-released-with-support-for-raid/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Calculate Linux 17.12 released with support for RAID" /><published>2018-01-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/calculate-linux-1712-released-with-support-for-raid</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/calculate-linux-1712-released-with-support-for-raid/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr&lt;/strong&gt; Alexander Tratsevskiy on behalf of Calculate Linux team has announced the release of Calculate Linux 17.12. This release brings support for installation on the RAID (Redundant Array of Inexpensive Disks) without losing fine tuning between performance and resource consumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/cld-mini.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;File picture of Calculate Linux 17.0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calculate Linux 17.12 is available in 8 different flavors. The Calculate Linux Desktop (CLD) comes with KDE Plasma. There are other alternative desktop flavors featuring Cinnamon, MATE &amp;amp; XFCE. In addition to desktop flavors, it includes Calculate Directory Server (CDS), Calculate Linux Scratch (CLS), Calculate Scratch Server (CSS) and Calculate Container Scratch (CCS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the notable highlights in Calculate Linux 17.12 can be summarized as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Installation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;SoftRaid support added.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fixed autopartitioning problems.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Third-party overlays supported.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The Calculate Utilities server does not run in the background. Instead, it is launched by D-Bus.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The MuQSS patch was included in the kernel configuration for better application task scheduling.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The UKSM patch was included in the kernel configuration for less memory load.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;PAE binary kernel supported for 32-bit systems.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;All server kernel settings optimized.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;GCC completely updated to v6.4 and the kernel updated to v 4.14.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;In CLDC, CLDM and CLDX Pidgin were replaced by Gajim. The “httpupload, “image” and “URL image preview” come included.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The LXC/LXD container version was renamed to Calculate Container Scratch (CCS).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;11 493 binary packages are available.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.calculate-linux.org/blogs/en/681/show&quot;&gt;original Calculate Linux 17.12 release announcement&lt;/a&gt; in projects website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Mr Alexander Tratsevskiy on behalf of Calculate Linux team has announced the release of Calculate Linux 17.12. This release brings support for installation on the RAID (Redundant Array of Inexpensive Disks) without losing fine tuning between performance and resource consumption.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/cld-mini.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Slax 9.3 released with improved WiFi support</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/slax-93-released-with-improved-wifi-support/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Slax 9.3 released with improved WiFi support" /><published>2017-12-25T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-12-25T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/slax-93-released-with-improved-wifi-support</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/slax-93-released-with-improved-wifi-support/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Tomas M&lt;/em&gt;, developer of Slax has announced the release of Slax 9.3, the latest stable release of Debian based, live GNU/Linux distribution that follows a modular design approach. One of the major highlights of this release is the inclusion of various firmware drivers to provide better support for WiFi devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/slax93.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Application Launcher in Slax 9.3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inclusion of additional firmware drivers makes the Slax image a little bigger (around 40 MB). Though, this can be justified by support for various WiFi devices. A bigger distribution with network capabilities is definitely better than a small distribution without networking capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other notable changes in Slax 9.3 includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;There were some regression tests to identify issues while booting from alternative file systems. Some of the issues have been identified and corrected during this phase. This mainly includes the ability to boot from NTFS and ext4 file systems.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;If booted from a writable storage medium, Slax enables persistence by default.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;added pcmanfm as file manager for GUI&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;added wicd as wifi network manager&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;xLunch now auto updates, to see newly installed apps&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;hard drives are mounted on boot and bookmarks added to pcmanfm&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;keyboard layout stays persistent&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;screen resolution change is reimplemented to make it work better&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;syslinux updated to newest version&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may also proceed to read original &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slax.org/blog/24578-Slax-9-3-is-here.html&quot;&gt;Slax 9.3 release announcement&lt;/a&gt; in project’s website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Mr Tomas M, developer of Slax has announced the release of Slax 9.3, the latest stable release of Debian based, live GNU/Linux distribution that follows a modular design approach. One of the major highlights of this release is the inclusion of various firmware drivers to provide better support for WiFi devices.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/slax93.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">ArchLabs 2017.12 released with various look &amp;amp; feel improvements</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/archlabs-201712-released-with-various-look-feel-improvements/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ArchLabs 2017.12 released with various look &amp; feel improvements" /><published>2017-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/archlabs-201712-released-with-various-look-feel-improvements</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/archlabs-201712-released-with-various-look-feel-improvements/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;ArchLabs&lt;/em&gt; Linux team has announced the release of ArchLabs 2017.12, the latest stable release of Arch based GNU/Linux distribution featuring customized open box desktop environment. This release brings various package updates from upstream project, ie, Arch and other cool improvements in visual experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ArchLabs as an Arch based distribution, usually ships rolling release. However, considering some significant changes in the distribution, ArchLabs team decided to ship another snapshot release. This will be the final release of project in this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/archlabs_2017-12-22-24_1366x768.png&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of ArchLabs 2017.12&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major change in ArchLabs 2017.12 is the removal of Calamares installer in favor of ABIF. This was done by the discretion of core developers. It will also help the distribution to cut the image size by a few megabytes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other highlights in ArchLabs 2017.12 includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;jgmenu a very cool menu has been added to Polybar.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Polybar itself has had another makeover, and I think it is looking super sharp.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Pacli has been forked for use with ArchLabs.  All the options now work as they should.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;new default monospaced font has been added, the very stylish Fantasque Sans font.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The obligatory change to the default wallpaper, which is pretty much expected upon every release.  I personally have prescribed to the “Ubuntu Theorem of New Release Wallpaper“, which is “slightly changed but still the same”.  I think this brings a consistent and recognizable look to ArchLabs.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Numerous minor changes across the board.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Polybar-zen, that’s all I’m saying…..lol.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Oblogout has been removed, rofi-logout has replaced this.  Looks good too.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Al-Hello has had another upgrade and is looking incredible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://archlabslinux.com/2017/12/23/rounding-out-2017-with-a-final-release/&quot;&gt;ArchLabs 2017.12 release announcement&lt;/a&gt; published in projects website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The ArchLabs Linux team has announced the release of ArchLabs 2017.12, the latest stable release of Arch based GNU/Linux distribution featuring customized open box desktop environment. This release brings various package updates from upstream project, ie, Arch and other cool improvements in visual experience.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/archlabs_2017-12-22-24_1366x768.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">TrueOS 17.12 released with improved stability</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/trueos-1712-released-with-improved-stability/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TrueOS 17.12 released with improved stability" /><published>2017-12-14T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-12-14T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/trueos-1712-released-with-improved-stability</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/trueos-1712-released-with-improved-stability/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;TrueOS&lt;/em&gt; team has announced the release of TrueOS 17.12, latest 6 monthly stable release of FreeBSD based desktop BSD operating system. This release comes with improved stability to provide a more reliable experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are dramatic improvements in various components &amp;amp; tasks such as OpenRC, boot speed, removable device management, SysAdm API integrations ..etc. The Lumina Desktop has also got several improvements since the previous release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/trueos17.12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TrueOS 17.12 release banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the changes in the desktop release, the team was also working on TrueOS server edition. As a proof of this, the team has introduced a new text-based server image with support for Virtualization systems such as &lt;em&gt;bhyve&lt;/em&gt;. This server image also takes advantage of various improvements in FreeBSD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the important highlights in TrueOS 17.12 release can be summarized as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Over 1100 OpenRC services have been created for 3rd-party packages. This should ensure the functionality of nearly all available 3rd-party packages that install/use their own services.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The OpenRC services for FreeBSD itself have been overhauled, resulting in significantly shorter boot times.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Separate install images for desktops and servers (server image uses a text/console installer). The server image provides support for Bhyve.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;FreeBSD base is synced with 12.0-CURRENT as of December 4th, 2017 (Github commit: 209d01f)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;FreeBSD ports tree is synced as of November 30th (pre-FLAVOR changes)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Lumina Desktop has been updated/developed from 1.3.0 to 1.4.1&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;PCDM now supports multiple simultaneous graphical sessions&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Removable devices are now managed through the “automounter” service.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Devices are “announced” as available to the system via .desktop shortcuts in /media. These shortcuts also contain a variety of optional “Actions” that may be performed on the device.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Devices are only mounted while they are being used (such as when browsing via the command line or a file manager).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Devices are automatically unmounted as soon as they stop being accessed.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Integrated support for all major filesystems (UFS, EXT, FAT, NTFS, ExFAT, etc..)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The TrueOS update system has moved to an “active” update backend. This means that the user will need to actually start the update process by clicking the “Update Now” button in SysAdm, Lumina, or PCDM (as well as the command-line option). The staging of the update files is still performed automatically by default but this (and many other options) can be easily changed in the “Update Manager” settings as desired.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, proceed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.trueos.org/blog/trueos-17-12-release/&quot;&gt;TrueOS 17.12 release announcement&lt;/a&gt; published in projects website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The TrueOS team has announced the release of TrueOS 17.12, latest 6 monthly stable release of FreeBSD based desktop BSD operating system. This release comes with improved stability to provide a more reliable experience.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/trueos17.12.jpg" /></entry></feed>