<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-01T12:33:28+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">OpenSourceFeed</title><subtitle>Gallery of various GNU/Linux, BSD and other open source distributions and different open source desktop environments with updates &amp; stories on each.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Nitrux 1.0.16 released with package updates from Ubuntu Cosmic</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-Nitrux-1.0.16-released-with-package-updates-from-Ubuntu-Cosmic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nitrux 1.0.16 released with package updates from Ubuntu Cosmic" /><published>2018-09-29T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-09-29T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-Nitrux-1.0.16-released-with-package-updates-from-Ubuntu-Cosmic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-Nitrux-1.0.16-released-with-package-updates-from-Ubuntu-Cosmic/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Nitrux community has announced the release of Nitrux 1.0.16. It is an incremental release that provides package updates from Ubuntu &lt;em&gt;Cosmic Cutlet&lt;/em&gt; branch. It also includes various bug fixes, performance improvements, and better hardware support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/Nitrux-nomad-menu.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nitrux - Nomad Menu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-software-center-is-integrated-with-a-new-web-scraper&quot;&gt;The Software Center is integrated with a new web scraper&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NX Software Center is a free tool shipped with Nitrux, that facilitate easy management of applications and packages, especially AppImages. AppImages are distribution independent stand-alone packages that reduce the complexity involved in application packaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Software Center in Nitrux 1.0.16 is integrated with a new web scraper. This web scraper enables automated sorting and listing of AppImages. This work is still in progress, but it is fully functional now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-else-is-there-in-nitrux-1016&quot;&gt;What else is there in Nitrux 1.0.16?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the web scraper integration to Software Center, Nitrux 1.0.16 has following noteworthy changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Updated packages from Ubuntu/cosmic.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Updated kernel to version 4.18.10.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Updated Plasma 5 (5.13.90), KDE Apps (18.08.1), KF5 (5.51.0) and Qt 5 (5.11.1).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Updated Nomad Look and Feel. Fixed bug with the top panel.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Updated Luv icon theme.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Updated Software Center.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Remove Babe (deprecated) music player.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fixed bug where PPAs couldn’t be added.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;last-in-the-series&quot;&gt;Last in the series&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nitrux 1.0.16 is the final release in Nitrux 1.0.x series. The next series will be having the version number 1.1.x.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-can-i-get-nitrux-1016-images&quot;&gt;Where can I get Nitrux 1.0.16 images?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nitrux 1.0.16 installation images can be downloaded using the links given below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opendesktop.org/p/1188112/startdownload?file_id=1538255140&amp;amp;file_name=nitrux_release_1.0.16-1.iso&amp;amp;file_type=application/octet-stream&amp;amp;file_size=1411383296&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdl.opendesktop.org%2Fapi%2Ffiles%2Fdownload%2Fid%2F1538255140%2Fs%2Fce8e46720db6df163dcc93ad87f4d19c%2Ft%2F1538325806%2Fu%2F%2Fnitrux_release_1.0.16-1.iso&quot;&gt;Nitrux 1.0.16 ISO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Nitrux community has announced the release of Nitrux 1.0.16. It is an incremental release that provides package updates from Ubuntu Cosmic Cutlet branch. It also includes various bug fixes, performance improvements, and better hardware support.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/Nitrux-nomad-menu.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ubuntu 18.10 Cosmic Cutlet beta released</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-ubuntu-18.10-cosmic-cutlet-beta-release/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ubuntu 18.10 &lt;em&gt;Cosmic Cutlet&lt;/em&gt; beta released" /><published>2018-09-28T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-09-28T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-ubuntu-18.10-cosmic-cutlet-beta-release</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-ubuntu-18.10-cosmic-cutlet-beta-release/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Ubuntu team has announced the availability of Ubuntu 18.10 &lt;em&gt;Cosmic Cutlet&lt;/em&gt; beta for testing. This is the only development release prior to upcoming 18.10 stable release scheduled to release on October 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu 18.10 beta release announcement includes Ubuntu Desktop, Server, Cloud and also the Kubuntu, Lubuntu, Ubuntu
Budgie, UbuntuKylin, Ubuntu MATE, Ubuntu Studio, and Xubuntu flavors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/Ubuntu-18.10-beta-gnome-shell.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Preview of Ubuntu 18.10 Overview&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image Courtesy : OMG Ubuntu&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu beta images are almost free from major issues and provide a chance to see the changes that can be expected in the final release. Meanwhile, the community testers can make use of this chance to hunt for the bugs and to report them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-the-changes-ubuntu-1810-cosmic-cutlet&quot;&gt;What are the changes Ubuntu 18.10 Cosmic Cutlet?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the most interesting question on any distribution release. Everyone is curious to see how the release is different from the old one? While the Ubuntu 18.10 beta release announcement is a generic one shared through the mailing list, &lt;em&gt;OMG Ubuntu&lt;/em&gt; blog lists some changes in this release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;gnome-330&quot;&gt;GNOME 3.30&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GNOME 3.30 is included as default desktop environment in Ubuntu 18.10. It brings a lot of performance improvements with code cleanup and other hotfixes. It also consumes less power comparing to previous releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;linux-kernel-418&quot;&gt;Linux Kernel 4.18&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu 18.04 &lt;em&gt;Cosmic Cutlet&lt;/em&gt; is shipped with Linux Kernel 4.18. It brings a lot of performance improvements and power consumption improvements. It also provides better support for modern hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;faster-installation&quot;&gt;Faster Installation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ubuntu 18.10 Cosmic Cutlet installation process is faster than the previous releases. This is achieved using the lossless data compression algorithm used by Facebook. The &lt;em&gt;zstd&lt;/em&gt; compression tool enables a real-time compression and extraction approach to facilitate faster installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;brand-new-theme-and-icon-set&quot;&gt;Brand new theme and icon set.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu 18.10 Cosmic Cutlet ships a new icon theme and Gtk theme. It replaces the long-standing &lt;em&gt;Adapta&lt;/em&gt; theme with &lt;em&gt;Yaru&lt;/em&gt;, which makes a complete makeover on Ubuntu look, but without losing the identity. The default human icon theme in Ubuntu has been replaced by the  “squircular”, an Ubuntu Phone-inspired ‘Suru’ icon set, authored by open-source designer Sam Hewitt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog post is prepared by taking information from following sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.ubuntu.com/archives/ubuntu-release/2018-September/004601.html&quot;&gt;Ubuntu 18.10 Cosmic Cutlet beta release announcement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2018/09/ubuntu-18-10-beta-download-out&quot;&gt;OMG Ubuntu post on Cosmic Cutlet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Ubuntu team has announced the availability of Ubuntu 18.10 Cosmic Cutlet beta for testing. This is the only development release prior to upcoming 18.10 stable release scheduled to release on October 2018.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/Ubuntu-18.10-beta-gnome-shell.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lubuntu 18.10 Cosmic Cutlet beta released with LXQt Desktop for the first time</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/01-Lubuntu-18.10-beta-released-with-lxqt-for-the-first-time/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lubuntu 18.10 &lt;em&gt;Cosmic Cutlet&lt;/em&gt; beta released with LXQt Desktop for the first time" /><published>2018-09-28T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-09-28T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/01-Lubuntu-18.10-beta-released-with-lxqt-for-the-first-time</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/01-Lubuntu-18.10-beta-released-with-lxqt-for-the-first-time/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Simon Quigley&lt;/em&gt; of Lubuntu project has announced the availability of Lubuntu 18.10 Cosmic Cutlet Beta for testing. Lubuntu 18.10 is going to be the first release to replace LXDE with LXQt, a lightweight desktop environment using the Qt framework. With this release, Lubuntu is taking a big direction change and the expectation is to attract more users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/lubuntu-cosmic-beta.png&quot; alt=&quot;Lubuntu Cosmic Cutlet beta banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lubuntu 18.10 and the succeeding releases will be using LXQt. The LXDE and related tools and applications will be no longer be supported. Instead of the LXDE tools, Lubuntu 18.10 will be using the following technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;LXQt 0.13.0, with many bugfixes and improvements backported from upstream.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Qt 5.11.1, which is the first point release in the Qt 5.11 series.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;KDE Falkon 3.0.1, which is based on the Qt WebEngine toolkit.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The LibreOffice 6.1.1 suite, with the Qt 5 frontend.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;VLC 3.0.4, for viewing media and listening to music.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Featherpad 0.9.0, for notes and code editing.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Discover Software Center 5.13.5, for an easy, graphical way to install and update software.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;download-lubuntu-1810-cosmic-cutlet-beta&quot;&gt;Download Lubuntu 18.10 &lt;em&gt;Cosmic Cutlet&lt;/em&gt; beta&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lubuntu &lt;em&gt;Cosmic Cutlet&lt;/em&gt; is available for 32-bit and 64-bit architectures. These images can be downloaded using the links given below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdimage.ubuntu.com/lubuntu/releases/cosmic/beta/lubuntu-18.10-beta-desktop-amd64.iso&quot;&gt;Lubuntu 18.10 Cosmic Cutlet beta 64 BIT ISO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;magnet:?xt=urn:btih:a1fcfc63837eed64f0f2ab2df051b3e6c41d5c07&amp;amp;dn=lubuntu-18.10-beta-desktop-amd64.iso&amp;amp;tr=http%3A%2F%2Ftorrent.ubuntu.com%3A6969%2Fannounce&quot;&gt;Lubuntu 18.10 Cosmic Cutlet beta 64 BIT TORRENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdimage.ubuntu.com/lubuntu/releases/cosmic/beta/lubuntu-18.10-beta-desktop-i386.iso&quot;&gt;Lubuntu 18.10 Cosmic Cutlet beta 32 BIT ISO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;magnet:?xt=urn:btih:f1db22f122b7011091baae4a0e28eaa05c1b1c8f&amp;amp;dn=lubuntu-18.10-beta-desktop-i386.iso&amp;amp;tr=http%3A%2F%2Ftorrent.ubuntu.com%3A6969%2Fannounce&quot;&gt;Lubuntu 18.10 Cosmic Cutlet beta 32 BIT TORRENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lubuntu.me/cosmic-beta-released/&quot;&gt;Lubuntu 18.10 Cosmic Cutlet beta release announcement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Mr Simon Quigley of Lubuntu project has announced the availability of Lubuntu 18.10 Cosmic Cutlet Beta for testing. Lubuntu 18.10 is going to be the first release to replace LXDE with LXQt, a lightweight desktop environment using the Qt framework. With this release, Lubuntu is taking a big direction change and the expectation is to attract more users.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/lubuntu-cosmic-beta.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">KDE neon rebased to Ubuntu 18.04 Bionic Beaver</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-kde-neon-rebased-with-ubuntu-18.04/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KDE neon rebased to Ubuntu 18.04 &lt;em&gt;Bionic Beaver&lt;/em&gt;" /><published>2018-09-26T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-09-26T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-kde-neon-rebased-with-ubuntu-18.04</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-kde-neon-rebased-with-ubuntu-18.04/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Jonathan Riddel&lt;/em&gt; of KDE neon project has announced the availability of Ubuntu 18.04 based KDE neon images. The rebasing is done for both installable ISOs and docker images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/kdeneon-18.04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ubuntu 18.04 based KDE neon - banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-rebasing-mean-for-kde-neon&quot;&gt;What does rebasing mean for KDE neon?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KDE neon is a distribution built to deliver the latest technologies from KDE family as soon as it is available. The images are built on top of Ubuntu LTS base and provide a strong platform to rely on. KDE neon is a part of KDE community itself instead of standing as a separate project. It provides the project an opportunity to work closely with KDE technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The migration to Ubuntu 18.04 &lt;em&gt;Bionic Beaver&lt;/em&gt; implies a set of updated packages, drivers and better hardware compatibility to KDE neon users. This will help the users to focus on their work instead of worrying about the outdated operating system. With rebasement, the KDE neon can focus more their &lt;em&gt;snap&lt;/em&gt; integration to provide a smooth installation for application from KDE family and other communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KDE neon provides a migration plan from Ubuntu 16.04 based installations. This migration path was thoroughly tested in the last few months, and most of the issues have been fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-kde-neon-images&quot;&gt;Getting KDE neon images&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The updated KDE neon images can be downloaded from &lt;a href=&quot;https://neon.kde.org/download&quot;&gt;projects official download page&lt;/a&gt;. You may also use the direct links given below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://files.kde.org/neon/images/neon-useredition/current/neon-useredition-20180925-0833-amd64.iso&quot;&gt;Download KDE neon user edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://files.kde.org/neon/images/neon-devedition-gitunstable/current/neon-devedition-gitunstable-20180924-1254-amd64.iso&quot;&gt;Download KDE neon developer edition - unstable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://files.kde.org/neon/images/neon-devedition-gitstable/current/neon-devedition-gitstable-20180925-1248-amd64.iso&quot;&gt;Download KDE neon developer Edition - stable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dot.kde.org/2018/09/26/kde-neon-rebased-ubuntu-1804-lts-bionic-beaver&quot;&gt;Ubuntu 18.04 based KDE neon announcement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Mr Jonathan Riddel of KDE neon project has announced the availability of Ubuntu 18.04 based KDE neon images. The rebasing is done for both installable ISOs and docker images.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/kdeneon-18.04.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Fedora 29 Beta released with GNOME 3.30</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-fedora-29-beta-released-with-GNOME-3.30/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fedora 29 Beta released with GNOME 3.30" /><published>2018-09-25T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-09-25T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-fedora-29-beta-released-with-GNOME-3.30</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-fedora-29-beta-released-with-GNOME-3.30/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Fedora Project has announced the release of Fedora 29 Beta. This is a footstep to the upcoming Fedora 29 release. The beta release will show a strong resemblance with the final release. It provides an opportunity for individuals and corporates to ensure their required functionality is working properly. If not, they may file an issue with Fedora QA team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/fedora 29 beta - modified.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fedora 29 Beta banner&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy: Fedora Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;availability-of-fedora-29-beta&quot;&gt;Availability of Fedora 29 Beta&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fedora 29 beta release announcement is applicable for all Fedora editions including Fedora Workstation, Server Edition, Atomic Edition, and the Silver Blue edition. It also offers popular variants as Fedora spins with an alternative desktop environment, Fedora Labs and ARM editions. These pre-release images can be downloaded from &lt;a href=&quot;https://getfedora.org/workstation/prerelease/&quot;&gt;Fedora Portal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-different-in-fedora-29-beta&quot;&gt;What is different in Fedora 29 Beta?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fedora 29 Beta showcases a plethora of changes that we can expect in the final release. This includes the availability of modular repositories in all editions, GNOME 3.30 in Fedora 29 Workstation ..etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modular repositories&lt;/strong&gt;: Modular repositories are a way to keep multiple versions of same software parallelly. In Fedora 28, this was included in Server Edition only. Fedora 29 beta release introduces modular packages across all the editions.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GNOME 3.30&lt;/strong&gt;: Fedora 29 beta features GNOME 3.30, a recently released version of GNOME Desktop. It provides significant performance and usability improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Other updates like The Fedora Atomic Workstation was rebranded as Fedora Silverblue, the GRUB menu will be hidden on single OS installation. Fedora 29 also includes updated versions of many popular packages like MySQL, the GNU C Library, Python and Perl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read &lt;a href=&quot;https://fedoramagazine.org/announcing-fedora-29-beta/&quot;&gt;more about Fedora 29 Beta&lt;/a&gt; in the original release announcement. For a &lt;a href=&quot;https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Releases/29/ChangeSet&quot;&gt;complete list of changes in Fedora 29&lt;/a&gt;, see the ChangeLogs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Fedora Project has announced the release of Fedora 29 Beta. This is a footstep to the upcoming Fedora 29 release. The beta release will show a strong resemblance with the final release. It provides an opportunity for individuals and corporates to ensure their required functionality is working properly. If not, they may file an issue with Fedora QA team.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/fedora%2029%20beta%20-%20modified.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Linux Lite 4.2 beta released</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-linux-lite-4.2-beta-released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linux Lite 4.2 beta released" /><published>2018-09-24T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-09-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-linux-lite-4.2-beta-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-linux-lite-4.2-beta-released/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Jerry&lt;/em&gt;, lead at Linux Lite project has announced the immediate availability of Linux Lite 4.2 beta for testing. This is a minor update in Linux Lite 4.x &lt;em&gt;Diamond&lt;/em&gt; series. It includes some improved artworks, extra tweaks, and updated packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/linux lite 4.2 beta.png&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of Linux Lite 4.2 installer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-is-a-development-release-not-ready-for-production&quot;&gt;It is a development release, not ready for production&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux Lite 4.2 beta is a development release meant to showcase the features in the upcoming stable release. It also gives community contributors to involve in the regression testing and to provide their feedback. As a development release, there could be critical issues with this release. A known issue is slow booting in some issues. This issue should be tested on multiple hardware configurations and need to be analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Linux Lite provides no direct update path from development release to stable release. So, it recommended to not install Linux Lite 4.2 beta on production systems in hope, it will become eventually stable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-new-in-linux-lite-42-beta&quot;&gt;What is new in Linux Lite 4.2 beta?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Already told, Linux Lite 4.2 is a minor release. So, there won’t be any long list of features. Some noticeable changes include,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Minor tweaks and improvements in Lite Welcome&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A set of new wallpapers&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Linux Kernel: 4.15.0-34.37 (Custom Kernels with versions 3.13 - 4.18 can be installed from Lite repositories)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Firefox: 62.0.2 Quantum&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thunderbird: 52.9.1&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;LibreOffice: 6.0.6.2&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;VLC: 3.0.3&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Gimp: 2.10.6&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Base: 18.04.1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxliteos.com/forums/release-announcements/linux-lite-4-2-beta-released&quot;&gt;Linux Lite 4.2 beta release announcement and related discussions&lt;/a&gt;, see Linux Lite forums.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Mr Jerry, lead at Linux Lite project has announced the immediate availability of Linux Lite 4.2 beta for testing. This is a minor update in Linux Lite 4.x Diamond series. It includes some improved artworks, extra tweaks, and updated packages.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/linux%20lite%204.2%20beta.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">elementary Juno Beta 2 released for developers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-elementary-juno-beta2-released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="elementary Juno Beta 2 released for developers" /><published>2018-09-21T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-09-21T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-elementary-juno-beta2-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-elementary-juno-beta2-released/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; elementary team has published a second beta release of elementary Juno, an upcoming stable release of elementary, based on Ubuntu 18.04 LTS. This beta release is for curious technical users and 3rd party app developers to make their app working on Juno when it will be available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/elementary-Juno-beta-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;elementary Juno beta banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-new-in-juno&quot;&gt;What is new in Juno?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The elementary Juno beta 2 release comes with a set of features and improvements that we can expect in the final release. The main changes in Juno beta2 release include,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The login screen and lock screen greeter is improved with better scaling on HiDPI screens. This is made possible with a simple compositor that provides things like shadows beneath the shutdown window and indicators. The indicator works more consistently on the desktop and on the login screen.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;There have been multiple issue fixes in AppCenter. Banners on the home screen will have a glow on hover, based on the band color. Some old CSS styles were removed from the theme. These styles were required for pre-Gtk.3.20 release. elementary Juno uses Gtk 3.22.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thumbnail in &lt;em&gt;Files&lt;/em&gt;, the elementary file manager, has been improved to show consistent thumbnails.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The stylesheet now provides an “inline” style for tab bars. This means if an app opts into this style, its tabs can better match the content they’re switching between instead of always being chrome-colored.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Music&lt;/em&gt; app has got multiple issues fixes to make it more stable. There is no visual improvement between beta 1 and beta 2, but there has been a rigor code cleanup.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;There has been a lot of code cleanup and refinement into the far reaches of Photos. Most of it is not user-visible, but you might notice that almost all of the dialogs have been cleaned up and made more consistent with the rest of the elementary apps thanks to being moved to Granite.MessageDialog.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Code&lt;/em&gt; has UI improvements across the board, which make it look cleaner and be able to tile down to smaller sizes. A new inline tab bar style is introduced in the stylesheet across all three color schemes.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Manipulating the display settings is now more accurate with the Settings App. Now, this configurations is a lot more natural, especially in multiscreen setup.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just a glimpse of features in elementary beta 2 release. You can find the complete list of changes along with screenshots in &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/elementaryos/developer-preview-juno-beta-2-is-out-418f5037e9bb&quot;&gt;elementary Juno beta 2 release announcement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The elementary team has published a second beta release of elementary Juno, an upcoming stable release of elementary, based on Ubuntu 18.04 LTS. This beta release is for curious technical users and 3rd party app developers to make their app working on Juno when it will be available.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/elementary-Juno-beta-2.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Solus 3 ISO refresh released with better hardware support and improved artwork</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/01-Solus-3-ISO-refresh-released-with-better-hardware-supported-improved-theming/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Solus 3 ISO refresh released with better hardware support and improved artwork" /><published>2018-09-21T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-09-21T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/01-Solus-3-ISO-refresh-released-with-better-hardware-supported-improved-theming</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/01-Solus-3-ISO-refresh-released-with-better-hardware-supported-improved-theming/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Joshua Strobl&lt;/em&gt; has announced the availability Solus 3 ISO refresh, a stable snapshot of independently evolved, rolling GNU/Linux distribution. This release comes with updated Linux Kernel and other applications. It also includes more consistent user experience with improved theming and other artworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/solus-3-iso-refresh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Solus 3 ISO refresh, a snap of different editions&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently announced Solus 3 ISO refresh is identified by the version number 3.9999. It is available in all 3 official flavors of the Solus project, ie, Budgie, MATE and GNOME editions. Despite the edition chosen, Solus provides a consistent user experience across the entire system with the improved theming. It makes use of &lt;em&gt;Adapta&lt;/em&gt; for GTK theming and &lt;em&gt;Papirus&lt;/em&gt; for icon theming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solus 3.9999 brings Linux Kernel 4.18.5. It enables support for the recent CPUs from AMD and Intel. This includes the support for advanced technologies like high core count CPUs like AMD Threadripper 2. Additional hardware compatibility is enabled out-of-the-box by tuning kernel flags wisely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main changes in various Solus edition include,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GNOME&lt;/strong&gt;: Removable Devices is extension is now enabled by default. It helps to mount/unmount partitions without opening Nautilus. The Nautilus is configured to open files and folders with a single click. Also, the thumbnail preview is enabled for network devices also. The search results in Nautilus have been limited to local in order to avoid performance delay.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MATE&lt;/strong&gt;: A separator is added on the panel after the clock widget, to improve readability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solus 3.9999 brings a set of updated applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Firefox 62&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;LibreOffice 6.1.0.3&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Rhythmbox 3.4.2&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thunderbird 60&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;GNOME MPV 0.14 in Budgie and GNOME editions&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;VLC 3.0.3 in MATE edition&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&quot;https://getsol.us/2018/09/20/solus-3-iso-refresh-released/&quot;&gt;further information on Solus 3.9999&lt;/a&gt;, read the release announcement published in Solus website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Mr Joshua Strobl has announced the availability Solus 3 ISO refresh, a stable snapshot of independently evolved, rolling GNU/Linux distribution. This release comes with updated Linux Kernel and other applications. It also includes more consistent user experience with improved theming and other artworks.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/solus-3-iso-refresh.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Sparky Linux 5.5 Nibiru released with GCC8 and Linux 4.18.6</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-sparky-linux-5.5-released-with-gcc8-linux4.18.6-and-more/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sparky Linux 5.5 &lt;em&gt;Nibiru&lt;/em&gt; released with GCC8 and Linux 4.18.6" /><published>2018-09-18T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-09-18T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-sparky-linux-5.5-released-with-gcc8-linux4.18.6-and-more</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-sparky-linux-5.5-released-with-gcc8-linux4.18.6-and-more/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Sparky Linux team has released Sparky Linux 5.5. It brings a set of updated packages including GCC 8 and Linux Kernel 4.18.6. It also contains some minor bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sparky Linux 5.5 with codename &lt;em&gt;Nibiru&lt;/em&gt; is a stable snapshot in distribution’s 5.x series. This series is based on Debian &lt;em&gt;Buster&lt;/em&gt; branch and follows a rolling release model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/preview/sparky-lxqt-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An older version of Sparky Linux Plasma Edition&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;An older version of Sparky Linux Plasma Edition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main highlights of Sparky Linux 5.5 release can be summarized as,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;system updated from Debian testing repos as of September 17, 2018&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Linux kernel 4.18.6 (4.18.8- &amp;amp; 4.19-rc4-sparky are available at Sparky “unstable” repos)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;the Calamares installer updated up to version 3.2.1&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thunar daemon is deactivated in the MinimalGUI Live (Openbox), due to a problem of automounting new partitions created by Calamares&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;GCC 7 compiler has been removed, the system uses GCC 8 as default&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;removed packages: libpam-gnome-keyring, vim, imagemagick, systemd-ui, sparky-gexec, xterm (Openbox)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;also removed from LXQt media: lxtask, leafpad, notepqdqq&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;added new packages: seahorse, rxvt-unicode (Openbox), qps (LXQt), featherpad (LXQt)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;the Calamares and Advanced Installer remove Cryptsetup packages now (Calamares removes the packages if the system is not installed on an encrypted disk/partition)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;a terminal emulator used by Sparky tools has been changed from xterm to rxvt-unicode with pseudo-transparency (Openbox)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;small fixes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also read &lt;a href=&quot;https://sparkylinux.org/sparky-5-5/&quot;&gt;Sparky Linux 5.5 release announcement&lt;/a&gt; in projects official website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Sparky Linux team has released Sparky Linux 5.5. It brings a set of updated packages including GCC 8 and Linux Kernel 4.18.6. It also contains some minor bug fixes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/preview/sparky-lxqt-5.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">LibreOffice 6.1.1 released with over 120 bug fixes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-libreoffice-6.1.1-released-with-120-bug-fixes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LibreOffice 6.1.1 released with over 120 bug fixes" /><published>2018-09-13T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-09-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-libreoffice-6.1.1-released-with-120-bug-fixes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-libreoffice-6.1.1-released-with-120-bug-fixes/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Document Foundation has released LibreOffice 6.1.1, a maintenance cum bug fix release in LibreOffice 6.1.x. It brings fixes for over 120 bugs and regression issues reported on &lt;a href=&quot;http://theopensourcefeed.com/01-libreoffice-6.1-proclaims-the-power-of-large-and-diverse-community-contributors/&quot;&gt;LibreOffice 6.1&lt;/a&gt;. The main audience of this release is power users, early technology adopters and enthusiasts who are curious to try the latest and greatest technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/libreoffice.png&quot; alt=&quot;LibreOffice banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main features of LibreOffice 6.1.1 release includes improvement in image handling module, reorganized draw menu, brand new icon theme, ..etc. These highlights can be summarized as,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Colibre, the new icon theme for Windows based on Microsoft’s icon design guidelines;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The reworked image handling feature, which is significantly faster and smoother thanks to a new graphic manager and an improved image lifecycle;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The reorganization of Draw menus with the addition of a new Page menu;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The new Online Help pages enriched with text and example files to guide the users through features;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Several improvements to all modules of LibreOffice Online, with changes to the user interface to make it more appealing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.documentfoundation.org/blog/2018/09/13/libreoffice-6-1-1/&quot;&gt;read more about LibreOffice 6.1.1&lt;/a&gt; and find the download links in original release announcement published by &lt;em&gt;The Document Foundation&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Document Foundation has released LibreOffice 6.1.1, a maintenance cum bug fix release in LibreOffice 6.1.x. It brings fixes for over 120 bugs and regression issues reported on LibreOffice 6.1. The main audience of this release is power users, early technology adopters and enthusiasts who are curious to try the latest and greatest technologies.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/libreoffice.png" /></entry></feed>