<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-09-08T10:26:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">OpenSourceFeed</title><subtitle>Gallery of various GNU/Linux, BSD and other open source distributions and different open source desktop environments with updates &amp; stories on each.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">GNOME 3.30 Almeria released with improved performance and other features</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-gnome-3.30-almeria-released-with-improved-performance-and-more/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GNOME 3.30 Almeria released with improved performance and other features" /><published>2018-09-07T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-09-07T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-gnome-3.30-almeria-released-with-improved-performance-and-more</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-gnome-3.30-almeria-released-with-improved-performance-and-more/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; GNOME Foundation has released GNOME 3.30. It is a result of 6 months of development effort by the GNOME community and includes major new features and smaller stability and performance improvements. A number of community developers around the world has helped to make this release possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/gnome3.30.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of GNOME Desktop 3.30&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;With the improved performance, GNOME 3.30 can run multiple applications simultaneously, without affecting performance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GNOME 3.30 is named as Almeria, as a recognition to the GUADEC organizing team at Almeria, Spain. GUADEC is an annual conference of GNOME developers and community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-new-in-gnome-330&quot;&gt;What is new in GNOME 3.30?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GNOME 3.30 is a major release from popular open source desktop environment. So, it is quite obvious to expect a lot from this release. The main highlights in GNOME 3.30 include,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;GNOME 3.30 has fixed some critical memory leak issues. This has helped the project to make it’s footprint smaller. With the improved resource usage, we can now run multiple application without affecting the performance.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;GNOME 3.30 makes screen sharing and remote desktop session easier. An indicator is added to the system menu to quickly monitor the status of the connection and to disconnect when required.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The GNOME Software now includes the option to enable/disable automatic update of flatpak applications.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The Web application now enables the minimal view. With this, when reading some content, you can toggle the minimal view to give more focus on content rather than controls. The minimal view stripes out images and unnecessary parts from the web page and makes the content more readable.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Boxes, the GNOME virtual machine application, can now connect to remote windows servers using the remote desktop protocol(RDP). This enables seamless integration with Windows servers.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Games, the gaming application is faster now. It enables navigation with the gamepad and includes some new games.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;GNOME 3.30 includes a new application called Podcasts. It helps to easily monitor, subscribe and watch podcasts right from the desktop.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;And more
For a &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.gnome.org/misc/release-notes/3.30/&quot;&gt;complete list of features in GNOME 3.30&lt;/a&gt;, read the release notes available in projects website. You may also check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.distroscreens.com/2018/09/gnome-330-almeria-screenshots.html&quot;&gt;GNOME 3.30 screenshots&lt;/a&gt; published on DistroScreens&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The GNOME Foundation has released GNOME 3.30. It is a result of 6 months of development effort by the GNOME community and includes major new features and smaller stability and performance improvements. A number of community developers around the world has helped to make this release possible.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/gnome3.30.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tails 3.9 released with automated additional software installation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-Tails-3.9-released-with-additional-automated-software-installation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tails 3.9 released with automated additional software installation" /><published>2018-09-05T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-09-05T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-Tails-3.9-released-with-additional-automated-software-installation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-Tails-3.9-released-with-additional-automated-software-installation/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Tails project has announced the release of Tails 3.9. It marks the biggest update of the amnesic live incognito system in this year. Tails 3.9 includes two main features on which the team has been working for a year. The features include the ability to install additional software automatically on launching the live session and the integration of VeraCrypt a tool to encrypt and decrypt partitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/tails 720x340.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tails banner with logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main highlights of Tails 3.9 release can be briefed as,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ability to install additional software automatically when booting to the Tails system. Whenever you install a Debian package, a confirmation will be asked to include the package in additional software list.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tails 3.9 includes the VeraCrypt integration to encrypt and decrypt partition. This feature is inherited from the GNOME ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thunderbird is now the official feed and RSS reader in Tails. Existing librerea will be removed by the Tails 3.12 release.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Improve the configuration of the persistent storage to make it easier to scroll and consistent with the GNOME guidelines.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The Tor Browser has been updated to 8.0 which is based on Firefox 60.0 ESR&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thunderbird has been updated to version60.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tor to 0.3.4.7-rc is included&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Updated Electrum to from 3.0.6 to 3.1.3.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Updated Linux to 4.17 which provides better hardware support and also fixes the Foreshadow attack.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Update the DRM and Mesa libraries to improve support for some graphics cards.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Updated the Intel and AMD microcodes and most firmware packages.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/news/version_3.9/index.en.html&quot;&gt;further information on Tails 3.9&lt;/a&gt;, read release announcement published on Tails website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Tails project has announced the release of Tails 3.9. It marks the biggest update of the amnesic live incognito system in this year. Tails 3.9 includes two main features on which the team has been working for a year. The features include the ability to install additional software automatically on launching the live session and the integration of VeraCrypt a tool to encrypt and decrypt partitions.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/tails%20720x340.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">4MLinux 26.0 released with LibreOffice 6.1 and Firefox 61.x</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/01-4MLinux-26.0-released-with-updated-packages-and-features/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4MLinux 26.0 released with LibreOffice 6.1 and Firefox 61.x" /><published>2018-09-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-09-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/01-4MLinux-26.0-released-with-updated-packages-and-features</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/01-4MLinux-26.0-released-with-updated-packages-and-features/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; 4MLinux team has announced the release of 4MLinux 26.0, the latest stable release of independent GNU/Linux distribution with JWM. This release brings a set of updated packages including LibreOffice 6.1 and Firefox 61.0.2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/4MLinux26.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of 4MLinux 26.0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the usual package updates, 4MLinux 26.0 provides better development, image editing and, multimedia experience with a set of tools and packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main highlights in 4MLinux 26.0 can be summarized as,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Set of updated packages including LibreOffice 6.1.0.1, GNOME Office (AbiWord 3.0.2, GIMP 2.10.6, Gnumeric 1.12.43).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Helps to share your files using DropBox 55.4.171, surf the Internet with Firefox 61.0.2 and Chromium 68.0.3440.75, stay in touch with your friends via Thunderbird 52.9.1 and Skype for Web, enjoy your music collection with Audacious 3.10, watch your favorite videos with VLC 3.0.3 and mpv 0.28.2, play games powered by Mesa 17.3.7 and Wine 3.14. You can also set up the 4MLinux LAMP Server (Linux 4.14.64, Apache 2.4.34, MariaDB 10.3.9, PHP 5.6.37 and PHP 7.2.9). Perl 5.26.1, Python 2.7.14, and Python 3.6.4 are also available.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tcl/Tk (with a collection of small games) integration&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Engrampa (archive manager) with the ability open Debian packages&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Git includes both GUI and cgit web interface&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Beaver (with syntax highlighting) has been as a simple Script/C/C++ code editor&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;TiMidity++ now uses the Tcl/Tk interface&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;AbiWord has migrated from GTK2 to GTK3&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Expect has been added to the 4MLinux Server to facilitate task automation&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Xorriso (with its GUI) is now available as a downloadable extension&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;full support for modern image and video encoding&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ImageMagick and GIMP are now able to handle WebP, HEIF and BPG images.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Hyper Video Converter for VP8/VP9/AVC/HEVC encoding, creating the video for web, extracting audio tracks, and many other tasks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may also read the &lt;a href=&quot;http://4mlinux-releases.blogspot.com/2018/09/4mlinux-260-stable-released_1.html&quot;&gt;4MLinux 26.0 release announcement&lt;/a&gt; in projects blog.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The 4MLinux team has announced the release of 4MLinux 26.0, the latest stable release of independent GNU/Linux distribution with JWM. This release brings a set of updated packages including LibreOffice 6.1 and Firefox 61.0.2.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/4MLinux26.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Nitrux 1.0.15 released with Linux Kernel 4.18.5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-Nitrux-1.0.15-released-with-updated-hardware-and-graphics-stack/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nitrux 1.0.15 released with Linux Kernel 4.18.5" /><published>2018-09-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-09-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-Nitrux-1.0.15-released-with-updated-hardware-and-graphics-stack</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-Nitrux-1.0.15-released-with-updated-hardware-and-graphics-stack/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Nitrux team has announced the immediate availability of Nitrux 1.0.15. This is a stable update of Ubuntu-based GNU/Linux distribution that offers a simplified Plasma experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/nitrux1.0.15.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of Nitrux 1.0.15&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Nitrux 1.0.15 brings improved hardware support and updated graphics stack with Linux Kernel 4.18.5.  It also includes package updates from the base distribution, bug fixes, and performance improvement tweaks. Nitrux 1.0.15 ships fixe for several vulnerabilities found in previous releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main highlights of Niturx 1.0.15 release can be summarized as,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Updated packages from Ubuntu/cosmic.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Updated kernel to version 4.18.5.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Updated Plasma 5 (5.13.4), KDE Apps (18.08), KF5 (5.50.0) and Qt 5 (5.11.1).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Updated Kvantum to version 0.10.9.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Added Mesa (18.1.5) drivers for Vulkan, VDPAU, and support for VP-API.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Added microcode updates for Intel (3.20180807a.1) and AMD (3.20180524.1) processors.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Added support for exFAT drives.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Added support for btrfs partitions in Calamares (default is ext4).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Added Kcalc.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Disabled KDE Wallet subsystem.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/+NitruxInside/posts/Jx2Dgeai8gF&quot;&gt;more about Nitrux 1.0.15&lt;/a&gt; in a release announcement published in projects Google Plus community.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Nitrux team has announced the immediate availability of Nitrux 1.0.15. This is a stable update of Ubuntu-based GNU/Linux distribution that offers a simplified Plasma experience.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/nitrux1.0.15.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Linux Mint Debian Edition (LMDE) 3 ‘Cindy’ released</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-linux-mint-debia-edition-3-cindy-released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linux Mint Debian Edition (LMDE) 3 'Cindy' released" /><published>2018-08-31T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-08-31T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-linux-mint-debia-edition-3-cindy-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-linux-mint-debia-edition-3-cindy-released/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Linux Mint team has released Linux Mint Debian Edition 3 with the code-name ‘Cindy’. This release is based on Debian 9.x &lt;em&gt;Stretch&lt;/em&gt; series and provides the latest Cinnamon Desktop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/lmde3-cindy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A glimpse of Linux Mint Debian Edition 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-lmde&quot;&gt;What is LMDE?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux Mint Debian Edition (LMDE) is a GNU/Linux distribution based on Debian. It is an attempt to keep the Linux Mint operating system alive if the Ubuntu disappears. Instead of the Ubuntu base used on normal Linux Mint releases, LMDE makes use of Debian packages. It keeps the original Debian packages as it is and provides the latest Cinnamon Desktop and associated components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-new-in-lmde-3-cinnamon&quot;&gt;What is new in LMDE 3 Cinnamon?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an experimental release, we can’t expect a long list of unique features on LMDE. It provides everything that an ordinary Linux Mint release provides. The only difference in the base operating system. LMDE 3 is shipped with Cinnamon Desktop 3.18, which is the latest available release at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on LMDE 3, read &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.linuxmint.com/?p=3633&quot;&gt;LMDE 3 ‘Cindy’ release announcement&lt;/a&gt; published on Linux Mint blog.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Linux Mint team has released Linux Mint Debian Edition 3 with the code-name ‘Cindy’. This release is based on Debian 9.x Stretch series and provides the latest Cinnamon Desktop.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/lmde3-cindy.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">NetBSD 7.2 released with critical security updates &amp;amp; bug fixes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-netbsd-7.2-released-with-critical-security-updates-and-bug-fixes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NetBSD 7.2 released with critical security updates &amp; bug fixes" /><published>2018-08-29T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-08-29T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-netbsd-7.2-released-with-critical-security-updates-and-bug-fixes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-netbsd-7.2-released-with-critical-security-updates-and-bug-fixes/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; NetBSD project has announced the release of NetBSD 7.2, the second feature update in NetBSD 7.x series. NetBSD 7.2 brings a set of critical security updates and bug fixes along with some minor feature improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/netbsd.png&quot; alt=&quot;NetBSD generic banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the version number signifies, NetBSD 7.2 is second maintenance release in 7.x series. The first release in this series was announced in September 2015. Since then, there have been several security updates. So it is highly recommended to install NetBSD 8.x if you are doing a fresh installation. NetBSD 7.2 is provided an updated image to existing 7.x users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the main highlights in NetBSD 7.2 release includes,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Support for USB 3.0.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Enhancements to the Linux emulation subsystem.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fixes in binary compatibility for ancient NetBSD executables.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;iwm(4) driver for Intel Wireless 726x, 316x, 826x and 416x series added.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Support for Raspberry Pi 3 added.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fix interrupt setup on Hyper-V VMs with Legacy Network Adapter.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;SVR4 and IBCS2 compatibility subsystems have been disabled by default (besides IBCS2 on VAX). These subsystems also do not auto-load their modules anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Various USB stability enhancements.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Numerous bug fixes and stability improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further information and detailed change logs, you can proceed to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netbsd.org/releases/formal-7/NetBSD-7.2.html&quot;&gt;NetBSD 7.2 release announcement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The NetBSD project has announced the release of NetBSD 7.2, the second feature update in NetBSD 7.x series. NetBSD 7.2 brings a set of critical security updates and bug fixes along with some minor feature improvements.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/netbsd.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kali Linux 2018.3 released with Linux Kernel 4.17</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-kali-linux-2018.03-released-with-linux-4.17/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kali Linux 2018.3 released with Linux Kernel 4.17" /><published>2018-08-28T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-08-28T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-kali-linux-2018.03-released-with-linux-4.17</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-kali-linux-2018.03-released-with-linux-4.17/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Kali Linux team has announced the release of Kali Linux 2018.03. It is the 3rd minor release in Kali Linux 2018.3 release. The main highlight of Kali Linux 2018.3 is the inclusion of Linux Kernel 4.17, which includes Intel/AMD graphics driver improvements, improved power consumption on idle state, improved file system handling and better compatibility with modern hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/kali-release.png&quot; alt=&quot;Kali Linux Release banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the Linux Kernel update, Kali Linux 2018.3 also includes several fixes and package updates. It includes updated tools like aircrack-ng, burpsuite, openvas, wifite, and wpscan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kali Linux 2018.3 has also introduced a number of tools in the default installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;idb&lt;/strong&gt; – An iOS research / penetration testing tool&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gdb-peda&lt;/strong&gt; – Python Exploit Development Assistance for GDB&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;datasploit&lt;/strong&gt; – OSINT Framework to perform various recon techniques&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kerberoast&lt;/strong&gt; – Kerberos assessment tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kali.org/releases/kali-linux-2018-3-release/&quot;&gt;more information on Kali Linux 2018.3&lt;/a&gt;, see release announcement published on Kali blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-kali-linux-201803&quot;&gt;Getting Kali Linux 2018.03&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kali Linux 2018.03 ISO for different platforms can be downloaded using the following links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;footable&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Image Name&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Download&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Size&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Version&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kali Linux Light 32 Bit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux Light 32 Bit&quot; href=&quot;http://cdimage.kali.org/kali-2018.3/kali-linux-light-2018.3-i386.iso&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux Light 32 Bit&quot; href=&quot;https://images.offensive-security.com/kali-linux-light-2018.3-i386.iso.torrent&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;851M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018.3&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kali Linux Lxde 64 Bit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux Lxde 64 Bit&quot; href=&quot;http://cdimage.kali.org/kali-2018.3/kali-linux-lxde-2018.3-amd64.iso&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux Lxde 64 Bit&quot; href=&quot;https://images.offensive-security.com/kali-linux-lxde-2018.3-amd64.iso.torrent&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.9G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018.3&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kali Linux 32 Bit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux 32 Bit&quot; href=&quot;http://cdimage.kali.org/kali-2018.3/kali-linux-2018.3-i386.iso&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux 32 Bit&quot; href=&quot;https://images.offensive-security.com/kali-linux-2018.3-i386.iso.torrent&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.1G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018.3&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kali Linux Kde 64 Bit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux Kde 64 Bit&quot; href=&quot;http://cdimage.kali.org/kali-2018.3/kali-linux-kde-2018.3-amd64.iso&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux Kde 64 Bit&quot; href=&quot;https://images.offensive-security.com/kali-linux-kde-2018.3-amd64.iso.torrent&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.1G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018.3&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kali Linux Xfce 64 Bit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux Xfce 64 Bit&quot; href=&quot;http://cdimage.kali.org/kali-2018.3/kali-linux-xfce-2018.3-amd64.iso&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux Xfce 64 Bit&quot; href=&quot;https://images.offensive-security.com/kali-linux-xfce-2018.3-amd64.iso.torrent&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.8G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018.3&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kali Linux Light 64 Bit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux Light 64 Bit&quot; href=&quot;http://cdimage.kali.org/kali-2018.3/kali-linux-light-2018.3-amd64.iso&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux Light 64 Bit&quot; href=&quot;https://images.offensive-security.com/kali-linux-light-2018.3-amd64.iso.torrent&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;854M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018.3&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kali Linux Light Armhf&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux Light Armhf&quot; href=&quot;http://cdimage.kali.org/kali-2018.3/kali-linux-light-2018.3-armhf.img.xz&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux Light Armhf&quot; href=&quot;https://images.offensive-security.com/kali-linux-light-2018.3-armhf.img.xz.torrent&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;557M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018.3&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kali Linux E17 64 Bit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux E17 64 Bit&quot; href=&quot;http://cdimage.kali.org/kali-2018.3/kali-linux-e17-2018.3-amd64.iso&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux E17 64 Bit&quot; href=&quot;https://images.offensive-security.com/kali-linux-e17-2018.3-amd64.iso.torrent&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.8G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018.3&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kali Linux Mate 64 Bit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux Mate 64 Bit&quot; href=&quot;http://cdimage.kali.org/kali-2018.3/kali-linux-mate-2018.3-amd64.iso&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux Mate 64 Bit&quot; href=&quot;https://images.offensive-security.com/kali-linux-mate-2018.3-amd64.iso.torrent&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.0G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018.3&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kali Linux 64 Bit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux 64 Bit&quot; href=&quot;http://cdimage.kali.org/kali-2018.3/kali-linux-2018.3-amd64.iso&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a title=&quot;Download Kali Linux 64 Bit&quot; href=&quot;https://images.offensive-security.com/kali-linux-2018.3-amd64.iso.torrent&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Torrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.0G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018.3&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Kali Linux team has announced the release of Kali Linux 2018.03. It is the 3rd minor release in Kali Linux 2018.3 release. The main highlight of Kali Linux 2018.3 is the inclusion of Linux Kernel 4.17, which includes Intel/AMD graphics driver improvements, improved power consumption on idle state, improved file system handling and better compatibility with modern hardware.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/kali-release.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bodhi Linux 5.0.0 released based on Ubuntu 18.04</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-bodhi-linux-5.0.0-released-with-ubuntu-18.04-base/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bodhi Linux 5.0.0 released based on Ubuntu 18.04" /><published>2018-08-22T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-08-22T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-bodhi-linux-5.0.0-released-with-ubuntu-18.04-base</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-bodhi-linux-5.0.0-released-with-ubuntu-18.04-base/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Jeff Hoogland&lt;/em&gt; of Bodhi Linux project has announced the immediate availability of Bodhi Linux 5.0.0, the fifth major release of Ubuntu-based GNU/Linux distribution serving simple and fast desktop experience. It has been more than 7 years since the inception of Bodhi Linux 1.x, the first stable release from the project. Over the years, the project has evolved a lot in terms of user experience and stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/bodhilinux5.0.0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of Bodhi Linux 5.0.0 clean desktop&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A preview of Bodhi Linux 5.0.0 boot screen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bodhi Linux 5.0.0 is based on Ubuntu 18.04 LTS. It will be supported until 2023. While the recent releases of Bodhi Linux were based on Ubuntu 16.04 LTS and will continue to provide support till 2021. Other than the core change, there is nothing remarkable in Bodhi Linux 5.0.0. However, the core change implies, updated packages, more stability, and better hardware compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the main-stream distributions, Bodhi Linux does not provide direct upgrade path between the major releases. It encourages to do a fresh installation in order to avoid system breakage and other stability issues. However, the regression testers and the distribution enthusiasts who are already running a 5.0.0 prerelease, can perform a normal system update operation to get changes from the latest ISO. This will require manual configuration to get the latest look &amp;amp; feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Today I am very pleased to share the hard work of the Bodhi Team which has resulted in our fifth major release. It has been quite the journey since our first stable release a little over seven years ago and I am happy with the progress this projected has made in that time.
For those looking for a lengthy changelog between the 4.5.0 release and 5.0.0, you will not find one. We have been happy with what the Moksha desktop has provided for some time now. This new major release simply serves to bring a modern look and updated Ubuntu core (18.04) to the lightning-fast desktop you have come to expect from Bodhi Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodhilinux.com/2018/08/22/bodhi-linux-5-0-0-released/&quot;&gt;Bodhi Linux 5.0.0 release announcement&lt;/a&gt; in projects website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;download-bodhi-linux-500&quot;&gt;Download Bodhi Linux 5.0.0&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bodhi Linux 5.0.0 installation images can be grabbed by following below links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standard Release &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; –&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/5.0.0/bodhi-5.0.0-64.iso/download&quot;&gt;ISO Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Legacy Release&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; –&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/5.0.0/bodhi-5.0.0-legacy.iso/download&quot;&gt;ISO Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AppPack Release&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;–&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bodhilinux/files/5.0.0/bodhi-5.0.0-appack-64.iso/download&quot;&gt;ISO Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Mr Jeff Hoogland of Bodhi Linux project has announced the immediate availability of Bodhi Linux 5.0.0, the fifth major release of Ubuntu-based GNU/Linux distribution serving simple and fast desktop experience. It has been more than 7 years since the inception of Bodhi Linux 1.x, the first stable release from the project. Over the years, the project has evolved a lot in terms of user experience and stability.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/bodhilinux5.0.0.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">deepin 15.7 brings improved performance, reduced power usage and more</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-deepin-15.7-brings-power-consumption-and-performance-improvements/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="deepin 15.7 brings improved performance, reduced power usage and more" /><published>2018-08-20T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-08-20T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-deepin-15.7-brings-power-consumption-and-performance-improvements</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-deepin-15.7-brings-power-consumption-and-performance-improvements/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; deepin project has announced the release of deepin 15.7. This release brings various performance improvements, power optimization, and other critical bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/deepin157.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Category listing in deepin menu mini-mode&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-deepin-version-number-convention&quot;&gt;The deepin version number convention&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning from deepin 15.7, the project is changing the version number convention. The version number will be of the form X.Y.Z, in which X indicates the major version number. Currently, the major version number is 15, it indicates current version is developed and maintained from 2015. Y - indicates the subversion number, and it will come in a rough period of 3 months. Deepin releases with even subversion number will bring feature additions. While the odd releases will focus on bug fixes and stability improvements. The Z component in version number indicates the minor version number. It will be used if there is any minor update in the current release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-new-in-debian-157&quot;&gt;What is new in Debian 15.7?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;deepin 15.7 is a release that focuses mainly on bug fixes and performance improvements. It synchronizes the latest packages from the upstream project, Debian. If you are updating from an existing installation, there will be more than 1G of package updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main highlights of deepin 15.7 include,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Reduced ISO size. The deepin ISO size used to increase drastically, in proportion to the number of features and artworks added. With the 15.7 release, the team has reduced the ISO size to 2.5GB from the previous 3.1 GB. This is done by removing unnecessary components and packages from the system.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The overall power consumption is reduced by adding the power saving mode in deepin 15.7. It allows the system to automatically enter on power saving mode while running on battery. Preliminary tests show standby time extended by 20%.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The memory consumption on startup is reduced to 830MB. In the previous release, it was around 1.1 GB.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Other usability &amp;amp; configuration changes like power saving configuration in control panel, a time-costing prompt from bigger updates, category listing in application menu min-mode ..etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deepin.org/en/2018/08/20/deepin-15-7-enjoy-the-better-performance/&quot;&gt;more details on deepin 15.7&lt;/a&gt;, read official release announcement in projects blog.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The deepin project has announced the release of deepin 15.7. This release brings various performance improvements, power optimization, and other critical bug fixes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/deepin157.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Zorin OS 12.4 released with better hardware support</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/00-zorin-os-12.4-released-with-better-hardware-support/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zorin OS 12.4 released with better hardware support" /><published>2018-08-13T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-08-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/00-zorin-os-12.4-released-with-better-hardware-support</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/00-zorin-os-12.4-released-with-better-hardware-support/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; Zorin Group has announced the availability of Zorin OS 12.4, the final snapshot in Zorin 12.x series. This release brings various updated packages from the upstream project, ie, Ubuntu 16.04.5. It provides better hardware support with Linux Kernel 4.15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a minor release, Zorin OS brings critical package updates, crucial bug fixes, and other performance enhancements. The existing users of Zorin OS 12.x can perform a regular system update operation to get all benefits from Zorin OS 12.4. With the updated ISO new users can ensure that they have to download only the minimum number of packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-images/zorinos122.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A preview of Zorin OS 12.2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Zorin OS 12.4 introduces an updated hardware enablement stack. The newly-included Linux kernel 4.15, as well as an updated X server graphics stack, add compatibility for newer computers and hardware in Zorin OS. In addition, new patches for system vulnerabilities are included in this release, so you can have the peace of mind knowing that you’re using the most secure version of Zorin OS ever.&lt;br /&gt;
After installing Zorin OS 12.4, you will have the latest versions of the pre-installed packages. That means fewer software updates will need to be downloaded after installing Zorin OS onto your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&quot;https://zoringroup.com/blog/2018/08/13/zorin-os-12-4-released-more-secure-and-compatible-than-ever-before/&quot;&gt;more information on Zorin OS 12.4&lt;/a&gt;, read the official release announcement published on Zorin Group blog.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Zorin Group has announced the availability of Zorin OS 12.4, the final snapshot in Zorin 12.x series. This release brings various updated packages from the upstream project, ie, Ubuntu 16.04.5. It provides better hardware support with Linux Kernel 4.15.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/post-images/zorinos122.jpg" /></entry></feed>